My face is the front of shop My face is the real shop front
My shop is the fixer front I'm real when I shop my face
Hey guys it's Natalie welcome back to my channel
Today I'm gonna do a makeup tutorial as always but first story time, story time, story time
I just wanna be upfront with you guys and let you know that I've had some facial surgery
I'm always gonna be honest with you guys about this kind of thing because you mean so much
to me like you've been here with me since the beginning and you've seen my story
my whole entire journey this journey I've been on as a transgender woman you've been
with me on this whole journey this is my truth and you've accepted the truth of my journey
this is a really vulnerable moment for me and you guys are just so special because you've
been here for me throughout my whole transgender journey the whole message of my journey as
a vulnerable moment it's just been so impactful on my life and the truth of my journey it's
just so meaningful that you guys have been here for so much to me that you guys are supporting
the truth of the life experience of my transgender journey as a transgendered journey it's been
so painful and it's been a really vulnerable time for me and I'm just so grateful to you guys
because you guys are so meaningful and you've been here for so much
I think the main thing we've learned together on this channel is that makeup is a lot of fun
but it's inner beauty that really counts anyway let's talk about plastic surgery I had facial
feminization surgery on April 2nd so about a month and a half ago what we call facial feminization
surgery or FFS is actually a series of different procedures that some transgender women choose to
have to look more feminine so what I had done is forehead contouring a brow lift rhinoplasty
mandible contouring a trachea shave you know what let's just have the skull lady talk you through it
a coronal incision was made across the cranial vault whence the skin of the forehead was stripped
away from the bone a fragment of the super orbital ridge was then chiseled away removed reshaped and
re-affixed thereby eliminating that undesirable prominence of a robust brow that oft times
distinguishes the skull of the chard a second incision was made athwart the columnella of the
nasal septum facilitating the reconstruction of the anterior cartilage and bone further incisions
were made betwixt the gum and cheek through which the mandible was rasped and shaved
down to a gracile curvature of jaw and pointed chin thereby delineating a facial silhouette
exhibiting that aspect which medical men call canti it all sounds pretty gruesome when you
describe it like that but there's actually a very fine level of technique and aesthetics involved
my plastic surgeon is an artist the results are natural I don't look like I've had a bunch of
work done which is good you know you at least want to leave people wondering maybe she's born with
it maybe a surgeon peeled her face off and fixed her shitty skull here's a before and after picture
where you can clearly see the difference to use the exact medical terminology my brows on fleek
my nose is no longer busted the house my jaw snatched and my Adam's apple is canceled wasn't
it always really Eve's apple maybe Satan's apple I think I still look like myself it's not a new
face we're talking about millimeters of bone here but to have all that done was well it cost a lot
of money the anticipation was oh terror like I've never known the pain was memorable and the
recovery took more than a month in fact I still have some swelling in my jowls jowls there's a
nice feminine sounding word love that the standard youtube t girl thing to do of course would have
been to vlog the whole journey story time my facial surgery experience my FFS journey and
post constant social media updates about it and I am grateful to the trans women who have done that
because it was really helpful to me to be able to watch those vlogs in advance and know what
I was getting myself into but I decided not to post about the surgery because I wanted privacy
for the recovery and to just take some time to get to feel at home with the results before
subjecting myself to the vicious things they say about me in the tabloids you know I think I've
been kind of psychologically damaged by reading for years the things people say about my appearance
online I'm not even talking about the haters like at this point I can mostly brush them off
but for instance about a year ago I was reading through a transgender subreddit and some trans
woman was agonizing about her appearance and someone offered the encouragement you know you
can still look hot even if you don't pass just look at contour points oh like a dagger to the
heart the unintentional shade of it all so the past six weeks have been at times difficult and
lonely but I did manage to keep my mug off social media for long enough that I'm as ready as I'm
ever gonna be for the commentary of the internet so bring it on you jackals you vultures you
goblin swine while I was lying around bandaged and bored I did have a lot of time to think and what
I've been thinking about is probably the same thing you're wondering right now which is why
would someone do what I just did why would I spend so much time and money and go through so much
anxiety and pain just to change a few millimeters of bone isn't this all just extravagant vanity
some narcissistic symptom of phones but too much well I feel like there's a lot of pressure
on me to say that in fact this wasn't cosmetic surgery at all usually trans people say that
surgeries like facial feminization top surgery general reassignment and so on serve the sole
purpose of alleviating gender dysphoria this discomfort we feel with the mismatch between
our bodies and our gender identity so what I'm supposed to say is that my surgery was a medically
necessary reconstructive procedure needed to make my testosterone weathered facial bones
match the five foot two happy baby bouncy bio girl I truly am inside thereby alleviating my
dysphoria helping me safely blend into society and preventing a five-alarm psychiatric meltdown
and there is definitely truth to that it's certainly the argument I intend to make when I
write this off as a medical expense on my taxes if you're an IRS auditor please stop this video
now and insert the next floppy disk into your CD drive but hypothetically speaking I think the
reality might not be quite so simple how sharp is the line separating gender dysphoria from the
other kinds of body image dysphoria that drives cisgender people to get cosmetic surgery all the
time last year when I used to foolishly tweet things of substance I tweeted that I wanted to
get FFS and some trans people responded telling me that I was suffering from internalized transphobia
and self-loathing they compared it to East Asian people getting double eyelid surgery or so-called
ethnic rhinoplasty which they say are motivated by internalized racism and western beauty standards
I think that's a pretty weak analogy and telling a trans person to just learn to accept the way they
look can actually be kind of transphobic because a big part of what it even means to be trans
at least for me is the desire to look more female but I also think trans people often talk like
gender dysphoria is this intrinsic personal experience that's always 100% valid and never
has anything at all to do with the external pressure of beauty standards but in fact gender
dysphoria is not sealed away in a vacuum away from the influence of societal ideals and norms
early in my transition some of my worst dysphoria was about body hair so I had full body laser hair
removal and now I'm smoother than a cisgender boiled egg but where does the idea that women
don't have body hair come from isn't that just an arbitrary grooming custom a lot of the cis women
I know don't so much as shave their legs so maybe I'm not even trying to look like a cis woman
maybe I'm simply doing everything I can to avoid looking like the caricature of a knuckly hairy
manish trans woman with which society has terrorized me to my core is this gender dysphoria
or is it internalized transphobia or is it simply a cosmetic preference when I try to psychoanalyze
myself I find that my desires to look female to look feminine and to look beautiful are not
exactly the same but they're woven together so tightly that it's kind of difficult to untangle
them and the opposite is also true that for me feeling manish or dysphoric usually goes along
with feeling ugly I don't have a lot of days where I walk out the house thinking well I'm giving fem
queen realness but apart from that I look like absolute shit of course there are qualities that
make you look female that aren't necessarily attractive like cellulite or flabby arms which
are super fish but aren't deemed beautiful by society the truth is I don't just want to look
female I want to be beautiful desperately god I'll do anything anything in this video I want to
explore why I'm so obsessed with being beautiful and why it seems like a lot of people who live in
a society are so obsessed is it phones it's probably phones I know you're supposed to pretend that you
don't care about being beautiful or that you're not trying but guys it's the only thing I care
about and I've never tried so hard in anything of course I do feel guilty about being so obsessed
with it because there's this idea that caring about beauty makes you shallow or vain you know
smart people aren't supposed to care about beauty and I've always been categorized as a smart person
by people around me some of that is when you're raised like I was as a middle class white boy with
no athletic talent parents and teachers treat you like a fucking genius like Einstein nutted a load
in Mozart's bussy and Mozart shot you out while he was getting a rusty trombone from Vincent van Gogh
it inspired his famous painting starfish night but even among women caring about beauty is often
frowned upon I feel like an alien species when I hang out with women in academia and I know a few
because I once got half a PhD before dropping out to become a uh what do you call someone who makes
videos a cam girl most female grad students and professors I know don't wear makeup to them the
idea of earnestly putting on press on nails or false eyelashes is inconceivable like maybe on
Halloween now part of that is that women in male dominated fields sometimes feel like they have to
present more masculine to be taken seriously because of this prejudice that beautified femininity
equals frivolous but another part is clearly some kind of not like other girls weird flex which okay
fine whatever I'm not going to judge another woman for the way she copes with a society that
pressures women to be beautiful while simultaneously belittling them for caring about it I guess my way
of coping is this tacky heteronormative and tragically sincere aspiration to some kind of
post-ironic feminine beauty why am I like this well part of it is vindictive transsexualism pure
and simple to all the people who've ever called me a man I want to say fuck you by looking like the
undeniable visual archetype of a woman which is a beautiful feminine woman who's wearing
600 000 sequins they're biological sequence
oh that is some asmr right right there isn't that
another factor is this shitty website I'm a professional youtube influencer forgive me
father and I'm on camera all the time I edit my own videos so I spend upwards of 60 hours a month
staring at my own face on a screen now you try doing that and see what kind of fucked up complex
you develop plus I compare myself to other women who make videos a lot of the trans women on
youtube are so young and so beautiful it makes me want to throw up and in comparison for a long
time I've felt like this this shabby aging transvestite just this feral cat wandering the
aisles of the liquor store so I'm insecure I'm compensating for that whole mess but I honestly
don't resent the beautiful people I really just stand the hell out of them I follow this woman on
youtube but I want to be just like her mom her name is Dame Jefferson Star her name is Lady Jane
McLean Señora Nicole Beatrice tutorials Tatiana Petrovna West Prokova and of course my queen and
perfect goddess whomst I stand in whose portrait I've painted hundreds of times so there's maybe
some extra intensity for me but I think it's actually pretty normal to want to be beautiful
I think even grad students want to be beautiful they just want to do it in that Becky kind of
way where you scoff at anything glam or artificial and it's not just women who care about beauty
either I mean gay men in LA have always been getting cosmetic surgery but now even the
straights are doing it in cells are completely obsessed with the defects of their personal
appearance and the ones who aren't completely black pilled are obsessed with plastic surgery
the incel newspeak word for beauty is looks maxing because of course they have to go about
this in the most heterosexual possible way it is imperative to implement a skin max regimen in
order to maximize looks money status and secure access to females oh my god comte own not every
sentence out of your mouth has to be worded like a dispatch to the police commissioner yes they
actually call skincare skin maxing James Charles I know you're having a hard month but I've got a
business idea that's gonna turn this thing around for you here's the plan you're gonna create a new
line of skincare products called Chad glow bribed PewDiePie to send his fans to the promo video
hi sister cells and send me a check in the mail you're welcome if you read looks max forums
they're filled with discussions of brow ridge implants chin implants mandible implants
it must needs be remarked that the skull of the chad exhibited a jawbone most robust
it's literally facial masculinization surgery so everyone's obsessed with the bones everyone's
obsessed with beauty whether man or woman cis or trans gay or gamer maybe lesbians are just
straight chillin well everyone else has completely lost their minds but why why do we care so much
well with incels by their own account the only reason they care is they think that looks maxing
will make femoids have sex with them and they think of that will make their lives feel meaningful
which um it will not so incels are canceled now what about women what's our deal what's our
sitch what's our vibe what's our vish well men seem to think that women are like inverted incels
that we care about beauty and wear makeup fake up because we're trying to attract men my daddy
don won on vice news last year and said that women wear makeup because they're trying to stimulate
male sexual arousal and because evolution now with the risk of being bratty i gotta say this is maybe
10 true and 90 false for one thing straight men don't like makeup at least they don't think they
do here's a chart i made illustrating what every straight man in the world thinks about makeup
yes i asked all of them if you wear no makeup they think you look diseased and i actually do
look diseased when i don't wear makeup so fair enough if you wear natural makeup you know a
little concealer mascara maybe a nude lip they think you're not wearing any makeup and they like
it if you wear campy makeup colorful eyeshadow heavy contouring overdrawn lips they think it's
dumb and they hate it of course i'm generalizing hashtag not all daddy doms but if women really
wore makeup to attract men then you'd expect that they'd stop wearing it when there are no men
around but that doesn't happen about a month ago there was that video going around of a woman
showing how to make jailhouse makeup mixing deodorant and magazine ink to make eyeshadow using
kool-aid and vaseline to make lipstick there's not a lot of men in women's prisons but women are still
performing incredible feats of ingenuity and resourcefulness just to wear makeup so maybe
women are using makeup to express their individuality and femininity you know things that prison tries
to take away from you kind of makes sense there's a refinery 29 documentary about prison cosmetology
and also sexual exploitation yikes in which a former inmate describes how women would engage
in sexual bartering with male guards just to get makeup if a girl's performing sexual favors for
an officer he would bring her in colored pencils lip gloss things like that that's right women are
sucking dicks and they can put on makeup not the other way around honestly if all the men died
tomorrow af i'd definitely keep wearing makeup in fact i might wear more and i'm not just saying
that because i'm trying to win feminist points or anything like do i want to attract men yes of
course i do do i want to attract women i guess i don't really think about it isn't it safer to just
secretly fall in love with them while quietly dying inside whatever it's fine i want to attract
non-binary people too of course but right now you guys are kind of getting in the way of my crudely
stereotyping people based on gender so how dare you the point is when i think about my appearance
wanting to attract people to have sex with is not the main thing going through my head what is going
through my head i guess i just want to feel beautiful i want to see myself in the mirror
and think i look snatched is that a crime i don't feel pretty very often i'd say it happens about
once a month when i'm having a good skin day i do my makeup just right i glisten with setting spray
and then it happens a tingle goes up my spine i am bodicelli i am van gogh i have created
beauty i'm a girl and then it's over that's it for a month usually when i look in the mirror i
can't actually tell whether i'm pretty or not like with other people i can just look at them and
instantly make a judgment about it but with myself i have to just guess it's the same as
being a trans person trying to figure out whether you pass would you clock me i'd clock me
i'd fuck me too i don't give a shit get out of my room mom it doesn't work like that for me
i have to rely on other people's feedback of course the problem with other people's feedback
is that people are liars you look gray on especially when those people are your fans
put the house queen stuff in my throat mother i'll die for you oh my god or when they're your
haters you're disgusting a giant collarbone outs you as a man at a thousand paces i guess
i'll never know whether i'm pretty or not but i can't estimate like i have figured out that i'm
too pretty for twitter but i'm not sure yet if i'm pretty enough for instagram it's hard being
i have been dipping my toes in the instagram water before my surgery i got into a pretty good
rhythm of posting my shitty little makeup looks and what i find addictive about it is this constant
flow of positive comments from other people even though i know it's mostly flattery you invented
beauty perfect angel choke me mommy every time i get a comment like that i'm perfectly aware
that it's wild exaggeration fueled by parasocial delusions but i still get a hit of dopamine in my
biologically female brain and the intoxicating thing about instagram is that the embellishment
of the truth is a two-way street thanks to the miracle of facetune yes we finally get to talk
about the phones see it's a black mirror because it's a window into the darkness of the human soul
get it should i explain it again phones live in a society facetune is an app that lets you fix all
the problems with your face so here's an unedited pre-ffs picture of me what i would do in facetune
is smooth out the complexion shrink the nose a little bring the jaw in and use the vibrance tool
to make the eyeshadow pop it's really no more drastic than the kinds of photo doctoring people
have been doing since the invention of photography what's changed is that now everyone is doing it
to their own photos every day and i've noticed that when i'm in the habit of editing my flaws
out of pictures when i look at an unedited picture of myself or when i look in the mirror
my eyes go straight to the flaws why aren't my pores so big why aren't medical scientists doing
something to stop this is this really a good use of my mental energy here comes that guilt again
instead of worrying about my pores shouldn't i be helping stop the impending climate catastrophe
that's going to destroy the planet if we don't change the economy in like 12 years
shit i guess it's 11 years now it's just hard to focus on climate change when there's so much
else on my mind he's just so cute i guess i'd just rather think about the aesthetic than the
apocalypse and that's the darkness why is my neck like two decades older than the rest of my skin
do i need botox yet should i get a facelift these are the questions that will no doubt define the
next couple decades of my life as if it wasn't bad enough to have to go through a second adolescence
on camera i also have to deal with aging and thus the ritual of skincare products here's my daytime
routine so first i'm gonna mix the dermalogica exfoliator with the cleansing gel and just
massage my face none of this is sponsored by the way this is just me supporting corporations out
of the kindness of my heart now if i'm not running late for something i will do a face mask but
if i'm out of bed it's because i'm running late for something so
i've never done a face mask now i'm gonna use a toner which is very important now a lot of people
don't know what a toner does but um look it tones okay do you want your face to be untoned next i'm
going to spray expensive korean yeast directly into my eyes i use this because it's actually
a lot cheaper than the japanese yeast so you're really losing money if you don't buy it think of
the savings now i'm going to mix a pump of hyaluronic acid with a couple spritzes of organic
bulgarian rose water you can almost smell the bulgarian rose fields it's enchanting it's like
i'm there there's not enough serum in the world for this neck leather i use this moisturizer
because gg gorgeous told me to and i do everything gg says every fucking thing i know it seems like
a lot of products but once you get locked into a serious skincare collection the tendency is to push
it as far as you can i feel like i'm forgetting something of sunscreen i'm not really sure what
this does we can probably skip it and i'm just gonna finish it all off with some more expensive
mist yes god i love a good facial i'm so fucking wet right now so after all these products does
my skin look clearer younger more toned well it's hard to say for sure but it certainly is moist
this is the part where i usually just stare at my own face for 10 minutes
and contemplate the futility of my struggle against the ravages of time
i'm fine it's it's fine this is fine it's fine
i'm not having fun right now why am i not having
fun i guess i just don't feel beautiful and i know a lot of people think i'm pretty and i know
a lot of other people have it worse than me and i know i should be grateful and i know i'm privileged
to be able to get plastic surgery and i know i shouldn't care so much about this in the first
place but the truth is that this just eats away at me and i'm losing a lot of time and life to
this pain i've been kind of depressed this past month and i think part of it is that on a
subconscious level i think i was hoping that surgery would completely change my self-image
and make me like myself but it really hasn't i mean i'm happy with the results i'd do it all again
but i still feel the way i felt before you have to keep in mind that surgery fixes very specific
problems like the adam's apple problem or the way my forehead looks and profile problem but it's
really not a solution to deep psychological issues i still don't feel beautiful and i need
to face the fact that i'm never going to feel beautiful unless i change the way i think because
i'm trapped in a doom spiral over here and if i'm ever going to get out i think i need to start by
forgiving myself for wanting to be beautiful there's lots of reasons to want to be beautiful
besides being shallow and vain for one beauty is associated with youth it's a symbol of life of
defiance of death that's a profound thing to be concerned about see i'm not a bimbo i'm a poet
beauty is also associated with moral worth the beautiful princess versus the evil hag there's
studies showing that conventionally attractive people are more likely to be assumed to be happy
healthy and trustworthy they're more likely to be hired so it's not just about instagram likes this
is serious stuff and we the woke we are all aware of this we know that beauty is power that beauty
is political we know that beauty standards come from the people with privilege in an unequal
society we know it's unjust that being light-skinned cis able-bodied or thin is considered more
attractive than being dark-skinned trans disabled or fat we know that female beauty matters so much
because patriarchy we know that our obsession with beauty is being provoked by advertising the
cosmetic industry and beauty influencers who are trying to sell us products we know we know we know
all this because we've all been sitting around critiquing it for decades because that's what
leftists do we critique things we are finely tuned detectors of racism sexism ableism fat phobia
transphobia and capitalism run amac we notice an injustice we problematize it we critique it and
then we cancel it but what's next when we're done critiquing things what are we supposed to do
because i'm aware that conventional beauty standards are a racist sexist ableist fat phobic
transphobic social construct designed to preserve power relations and sell products
but does that awareness mean i desire any less to be conventionally beautiful well no i want it
more than ever the problem is that the intellectual exercise of critiquing things doesn't usually
affect my desires very much so what am i supposed to do sit here in silent contemplation until my
desires finally align themselves with the interests of the international proletarian
revolution oh fuck the revolution i want to be a pretty rich girl i don't want to be contra points
anymore i want to be gg gorgeous fighting fascists on youtube was an idea i came up with when i was a
male alcoholic unfortunately america needs a contra points right now more than it needs a 30
year old gg gorgeous impersonator so i guess i'm stuck with it maybe it's for the best critiquing
society may not change our desires but it can motivate us to change society and changing
society can change our desires so how do we change society revolution well sure revolution
depending on what happens in 2020 i'll think of grabbing a brick myself but failing that i think
there are ways we can work to loosen the grip of restrictive beauty standards without the futility
of trying to stop caring how we look i do think representation matters and i think having visible
beauty icons who are dark-skinned or trans or gender non-conforming or disabled or fat or over
35 or influencers makes a big difference beauty standards are social constructs and social
constructs can change that's why it's so important to recognize that influencers are just as valid as
other celebrities but the problem with changing society is that it takes a long time and this
video is almost over where i can see an escape from my particular doom spiral is in style as
an alternative ideal to beauty you can be stylish at any age you can be stylish whether you pass or
not style is a way of cultivating a personal aesthetic that you have complete control over
it's like art and that originality is a virtue style is an individual aesthetic unlike the
collective aesthetic of beauty standards as the poet wordsworth said about artistic appreciation
every author as far as he is great and at the same time original has had the task of creating
the taste by which he is to be enjoyed so even if you don't conform to conventional beauty
standards through the power of original style you can create the taste by which your unique beauty
is to be appreciated society may frown upon us six-foot trannies but if i know i'm dressed well
or my makeup is snatched i can easily abide any comment any stare i can be misgendered a dairy
queen for all i care it does not matter i can strut with confidence because i am basking in
the regal knowledge of my own aesthetic superiority bow before me peasants i proclaim to the drive
through window for i am serving a lurk sir this is a dairy queen so i guess that's the solution
i can't believe i single-handedly ended capitalism now does that mean i'm not going to get a lot of
expensive plastic surgery fuck no what do you people think i am some kind of transgender mother
tereza god damn the audacity of you people the hubris look i need plastic surgery because i have
no style in fact after the month i've had you should be grateful i'm wearing clothes at all
so that's it for me i guess i have nothing but the decay of time and age to look forward to
i guess i'll just have to find my self-worth and cultivating kindness intelligence and inner beauty
ew gross
so
I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry, but I'm sorry
I'm drooling all over myself because my jaw is still numb from the surgery. Love that.