Hey everyone, welcome to my 35,000 subscriber special video. The game plan for this video
is to watch the special bonus video that was unlocked by my patrons over on Patreon. Then
I'll be announcing some fun new rewards for people who decide to join my Patreon,
and then we'll have a very lengthy Q&A with way too many questions.
And now let's watch that classic Jose episode from back in 2017 where I decided to discuss
the scourge of ironic Nazis. A few notes before we start the video. Number one, the audio is
very bad. Very, very bad. I almost recorded the whole thing again, but I feel like that kind of
loses the whole point of it being an old video. You'll also be able to tell that my style is a
bit different. Overall, I think the video actually holds up. Also, I say the word ironic very
strangely inside it. I wasn't actually trying for an accent back then. It was just trying to
imitate a funnier podcast that I had seen in the past. Enjoy and brace yourself for the audio.
Lately, there's been an outbreak of a certain type of jokesters on YouTube.
People who love getting a rise out of others by adopting vocabulary, attitudes, imagery,
and music of history's most playful, silly authoritarian regime, the Third Reich.
It's almost like we've gone back to the 1930s. Nazis invade your cult. Wait, excuse me,
ironic Nazis. Because nowadays it seems like it can't be a real Nazi unless you're literally
throwing someone into an oven. And even then someone might ask if they deserved it or not.
But let's pretend what we've mostly gotten is an outbreak of the ironic Nazis. People who love
living well past the edge of good taste and revel in schlocky shock humor. A few commentators have
pointed out this trend already, but as someone who likes telling stories, I wanted to try relating
one of my own as a cautionary tale, and we have to start an unlikely place. This is Bon Jovi.
That's right. Drink it in. When Bon Jovi isn't culturally appropriate in cigarette
advertising for their albums, they're producing the rock albums that have kept them relevant
for a decade. Throughout their 30-year career, they've had to weather some tough criticisms,
namely the one my friends and I came up with 10 years ago when we concluded that Bon Jovi
is the most generic rock band in history. So we began to mock them. Started off with
some sneering and jokes at their expense. But being the sophisticated cats we were,
we eventually moved on to the much sharper tool of belittling them. We became ironic Bon Jovi fans.
With that move, we entered a golden age of comedy. There's no line that could not be crossed,
no bar that could not be topped. When someone said Bon Jovi's music retroactively became the best
music of the 1950s, someone had to correct them and say Bon Jovi's sweet sounds are the reason
we evolved to have ears. There were no limits. And we kept going deeper. We were buying Bon Jovi
albums, learning the lyrics to their music, and even went to one of their concerts. I remember
by the end of that night, we were hoarse from singing along to living on a prayer. The concert
came to an end. Or in other words, we actually had a lot of fun. And maybe it was because of
that fun that we sort of realized something that night. We realized that our ironic performance
had taken us so far that we had, in fact, become Bon Jovi fans. I went from the guy who sneered at
their music to the one who sings at least one Bon Jovi song every time on that karaoke. I went
from changing the station when they were on to memorizing their lyrics to more songs than I
really feel comfortable admitting in public. I had become and have become the thing I was pretending
to be. Now, my little ironic Nazis, you may be saying to yourself, you would never go so far as
to become an actual Nazi. My analogy is silly, and I should guess myself. I might have said
something similar in my early days of being an ironic Bon Jovi fan. But here's an interesting
point to consider. I am not, and will never likely be so silly as to think our ears evolve
to listen to the music of Bon Jovi. While I am always down to sing, wanted, dead, or alive,
I don't feel the need to see Bon Jovi whenever they're in town either. In other words,
my Jovi fandom is the mild sort of casual fan, which is a far cry from the super fandom I
pretended. Think to yourself, there's all this good-natured memeing around led you to start
believing some new ideas you had never considered. Perhaps you find yourself talking about how
multiculturalism can only fail, and ethnic homogeneity is essential to keep society
functioning. Perhaps you're starting to think that there are some cultures that are barbaric
or so morally reprehensible that anyone from said culture must be regarded with suspicion
or kept away at all costs. No doubt you have rationalizations for your new ideas,
that they're not as bad as Nazism, and that might even be true. But do you wonder why they sound
so similar? Is it possible your ironic Nazism is gradually turning into a soft Nazism? I hope
people who draped themselves in the colors of some of history's worst monsters stop and ask
themselves what all that pretending means and where it might take them. If you're finding your
moral development is being increasingly informed by a group of people you know is repulsive,
maybe you need to start asking yourself what you really believed in the first place.
This video isn't designed to be an accusation. I'm staring away from calling out any ideologies
that have been conflated with Nazism on purpose to focus on how some people like to deploy Nazi
themes for a laugh instead. I'm just hoping people will perhaps stop and think about what they're
doing and saying. I know that's not very popular when we all look to YouTube personalities to do
thinking for us, but maybe they don't always have the answers. And no, I'm actually not trying to be
an ironic YouTuber myself. You can tell me how wrong I am without resorting to name calling
and spamming memes. I'd at least be relieved you're thinking for yourself, even if you are wrong.
At the end of my journey into irony, I ended up the fan of a rock band known for catchy music and
simple lyrics. What will you end up with at the end of yours? And I feel like we need to end on
the words of a great poet. Take a look around you. Nothing's what it seems. We're living in the
broken home of hopes and dreams. Let me be the first to shake a helping hand. Anybody brave enough
to take a stand. I've knocked on every door and every dead end street. Looking for forgiveness
what's left to be. I hope you all enjoyed that rewatching it. It actually held up better than
I thought it would for a little six minute video. It's not too bad. And I am 100% comfortable with
everyone knowing that I'm a Bon Jovi fan. I can live with this. Now let's get on to the new
patron rewards. I have two types of rewards that will now be available on my Patreon. The first is
an exclusive download of my theme song. I'll have some more details on the background of this song
in the Q&A since some people asked about it. But if you've ever wanted a copy of your own to listen
to this will be your chance and if you're worried about the artist who happens to be a friend of
mine she'll be getting a percentage of the first month of your donation and if you really want to
give her a little bit extra just leave a note when you become one of my patrons and say give this
extra money to your lovely singer. The second new reward is one that's being used by a lot of other
people so it's not quite as fun or creative but it will be super useful at least to me. And that's
letting patrons see videos a few days early. I kind of resisted this one because I would prefer
everyone seeing a video at the same time with no one getting preferential treatment but I'm
actually viewing these releases as something of a test case. So what I'm hoping for is that my
patrons will offer me some early feedback letting me edit and modify and just fix up any small
mistakes that appear in videos so when the final version comes out it'll be nice and not filled
with any silly mistakes. And if you're wondering what new expensive tier all of this will be for
the answer is no new tier. Both of these new rewards are being added to the five dollar tier.
Of course if you'd like to give me more than that that's always an option
but there won't be any additional rewards for it at least not for the time being.
Now it's time for the Q&A. The first question comes from overrunpatreon from one of my patrons
Liz Castro. She writes, Congrats! I am curious given the breadth of your research for your videos
were you involved in academia or publishing prior to becoming a youtube creator?
I myself am a teacher and thoroughly appreciate your attention to detail and conscientious
citations. I'm trying to maintain a degree of anonymity here so I won't discuss my professional
life too much but before that I was enrolled in university and have a background in both
english and psychology. I had a double major in my undergrad years. I considered going into a
master's program but for a number of reasons it just wasn't a good option for me. I've always
had a healthy respect for academia and very much appreciate the process and the effort people go
to to make sure their work is properly cited and grounded in appropriate sources. If that's
reflected in my work I'm glad that people are noticing that. A number of questions were asked
on my youtube channel so I am going to go through those in the order that they were asked.
First is, I have a question. What are your thoughts on Balkan politics and will you make
video on it? I assume this is from a viewer in the Balkans and I have to admit I don't know a
lot about Balkan politics. I believe I would have to spend a lot of time researching and learning
about it and to be honest I probably won't ever get around to doing something like that mostly
because this is something that would take years to do if I was going to do it properly and one of my
pet peeves on youtube is seeing people talk about things that they know little or nothing about.
I never want to be one of those people. Next question, are you friends with any right-wing
people? Yes in fact I have a couple of friends who are rather right-wing including family members
and that's always interesting when politics comes up. Thankfully none of the right-wing people I know
have especially noxious or terrible opinions so there's never been too much trouble. I'll share
our brief story. About a month ago I had some family visiting from out of town and they came
and they wanted to do something festive in the city so my idea was to go to a special pop-up bar
that had a christmas theme here in Toronto. It was a fun time. It was all fancy and dressed up
and they had specialty cocktails and we were all having a little fun. Later that evening there was
going to be a show though and one of the people who worked there went around was letting everyone
know there'd be a show that night. Of course I knew about it and I was just waiting to see
my cousin's reaction because when the staff member came by and said it would be a drag show
his eyes just popped out of his head and he was like a drag show? And I just couldn't stop laughing
it was probably my favorite part of the whole night. Okay next question, do you feel any sort
of pressure to hide any opinions you have because of fear of losing fans slash patrons? Even if you
don't do it do you at least consider it? Let me first address patrons. My patrons are actually
surprisingly quiet. If you go over to my patreon you'll see there aren't that many comments and I
get almost no messages from my patrons. I actually kind of like that they have this silent support
for me and I appreciate it. I do hope they're a bit more vocal when it comes time to offering
me some feedback for early videos before they go live but other than that I appreciate having
supporters who are willing to financially back my work without trying to influence it or push it
too much one way or another. With regard to the YouTube audience as a whole and any pressure I
feel from them I think pretty much any YouTube creator will feel a degree of pressure one way
or the other when it comes to certain types of opinions. That said when I look at the reactions
from my audience they're usually pretty positive and I feel as though if I go in a certain direction
that maybe they aren't used to and or don't expect I generally receive support more often
than not and I've never gone about making any particular video thinking I'm not sure people
will appreciate this or this is a topic I shouldn't touch because it might annoy my audience. If
anything I feel like I'm rewarded for taking chances like that. When my channel really blew up
with that Roseanne video that was me taking a chance because I wasn't sure anyone wanted to
listen to me talk about a sitcom from the 1980s and 90s and it turns out they did and the lesson
I learned is it's good to take chances and try and make something even if you think your audience
might not be down for it. That said there are moments when I'm making videos and I cut out
certain lines and certain terms of phrase sometimes in sire sections usually because I
think it'll be bad and people will think that's boring or uninteresting sometimes I'm worried
about things being a little too mean a little too gruff when I look at the reactions from my
audience I like the warm positive ones rather than the sort of angry positive ones if that makes
sense and I'm trying to be aware of the audience I'm cultivating and I don't ever want it to be one
where I feel like I am fearful of them fearful of losing viewers or patrons and if I feel myself
moving in that direction I'll feel as though I'm doing something wrong and right now at least I
don't feel like I'm quite in that space next question are you a socialist a sockdam or just a
liberal well definitely not just a liberal so we can cross that off the list I tend to think of
politics in two different ways the practical reality of electoral politics and the broader
ideology that informs my vision of how I would like the world to be so when it comes to practical
politics and trying to implement policies I tend to act as a social democrat if an election is up
I will vote for the candidate who will represent policies that will move the country further to
the left I know it's not perfect and some people get frustrated that politicians are lagging behind
where they would like the left to be in the mainstream but I think small improvements are
better than no improvements and I think there's a real danger of sitting out in elections because
they have consequences even if they don't affect you other people are affected by these policies
and we owe it to one another to always try and make the world a better place when we have the
opportunity as for the long-term goals you could probably say I'm closer to a socialist
generally speaking I try not to be tied down to any sort of specific ideology and we have to be
aware that there are going to be changes and shifts to our society that will make frameworks
we have today not quite or not necessarily applicable to that much different tomorrow
like climate change that was something that has to be accommodated into any sort of framework we're
going to have for the future and who knows what other sorts of challenges might lie ahead of us
next question do you hobby bird watching you like birds I've actually never gone bird watching
as for liking birds yes I do like birds I don't have any specific affinity towards birds believe
it or not I actually love all animals so birds are also animals and are great next question
what is your take on veganism and animal agriculture I am actually a vegetarian and
have been for about a year and a half now it's been surprisingly easy because I was never a huge
meat eater to begin with so cutting it out was relatively simple although it's sometimes tough
to eat out which is a bit frustrating veganism is great I'm not sure if I'm gonna make it that far
I'd like to there is a version of animal agriculture that can be done humanely and without
cruelty and in a way might need to be done for certain domesticated animals that can't live in
the wild anymore that said that's not what we have at all and animals are really horribly treated
well I'm not about to go around slapping burgers out of people's hands I would recommend you know
if you do eat meat maybe cut down a little bit not just for the sake of the animals but also
the environment it has a pretty hefty toll lots of great channels out there can explain it better
than I can next question would you rather French kiss a poodle or cuddle a wild raccoon I assume
these are both consensual things because I would do neither if the animal wasn't up for it so I
probably go with cuddle wild raccoon because I think it would be weird to open mouth kiss a dog
next question what prompted you to start this channel I saw a increasing amount of reactionary
content on YouTube and it was really starting to annoy me so I wanted to push back against that
honestly for a while I wasn't sure if I was capable of doing something like this but considering the
caliber of the opposition really anyone can debunk some of this garbage that's spewed out there
and from there I've just been experimenting and trying new things and building a channel that's
got some cool different stuff on it now next what do you think is going to stop people from
falling for demagogues um nothing I think demagogues are always going to be an issue and always a
problem as for what people can do there are some general tips and advice and that's to try and be
as educated as possible when it comes to listen to a passionate speaker ask yourself the question
if this is something they're so passionate about and I'm so passionate about why am I simply sitting
here letting this person educate me when I could go out there and use my passion for this subject
to educate myself and you might find that this person who speaks with such passion is actually
full of crap and you just ID'd a demagogue congratulations next your profile picture looks
like a blue jay correct me if I'm wrong why did you choose this it is a blue jay and why I chose
this was actually pretty random I drew this picture back when I started my channel I had actually been
trying to teach myself to draw for about a year or two when I drew that and it was actually my
first time trying to draw a blue jay and my first time ever digitally coloring anything and when I
made my channel I knew I wasn't just going to take a picture of my face I wanted to have some
graphic or image and I was really worried about taking someone else's so I just took this picture
which was mine and I thought it was pretty cute and I figured what the heck I'll use it I originally
had it as part of the name of this channel but I got rid of that pretty quickly and just switched
the name to Jose because that's so much easier next what's your favorite animated film Princess
Mononoke which is actually my favorite movie entirely uh maybe I'll do a video about it someday
who knows which languages do you speak English a little bit of French but it gets worse every year
because I never use it and I understand some Spanish usually just when someone is yelling at me
next what do you think of Jordan Peterson's 12 rules for life I have not read it the only
familiarity I have with it is I watch the videos by Hannah and Jake discussing it it seems kind of
dopey and a cheap way to smuggle in some Christianity into people's lives I don't really like self-help
books and I like religious self-help books even less probably gonna skip this one what's an example
of a movie that you think is really underrated I wish I had really cool unique tastes in movies
but I don't really maybe Children of Men I feel like that's a movie that was a big deal when it
came out but then just got quickly forgotten stars Clive Owen in a post-apocalyptic future
where no new children are being born it's really good do you ever plan on doing live
streams or debate discussions with people on the other side no not in any time in the near future
most people on the other side I'm gonna be totally honest I don't think approach live streams or
these debate discussions in a way that's helpful I don't just mean the people who are adversarial
and see it as an attempt to just dunk on the other side and try and make someone look like
a fool in real time even if someone comes in good faith to have a genuine discussion or debate
I don't think they're gonna become armed with enough research or material to make it worthwhile
you'd basically see me show up with as much as I could find speaking to someone who will just pivot
ignore and shoot out talking points and it would be a waste of time I feel like it would be easier
just to respond to their videos because at least then I don't have someone changing the subject
just as I get going on something because they realize they have no response to anything I'm
bringing up or at least I won't have to deal with responses that are completely incongruent with what
I'm saying will you are you planning on doing more videos about comics yes definitely I was
actually supposed to have a comic book related video in either late December early January
I got about two-thirds the way through the script when I realized I wasn't saying anything new or
interesting I was just looking for an excuse to talk about a certain Avengers comic I still might
do it in the future if I can find a more worthwhile bit of commentary I don't want to just create
videos for the sake of creating videos I want it to be a little more worthwhile as far as big videos
like the Secret Empire one oof I'd need to find another big event I'd want to cover like that
again although it was kind of fun featuring all those different voices in there and having a
really big video discussing comics I might do that again in the future we'll see congrats on
35k Jose have you ever thought about making a video on gamer gate like you did on comics gate
keep up the good work yes I have I kind of want to do this it's going to be an enormous project and
it's going to be painful it'll be more of a an autopsy I guess because gamer gate's pretty dead
right now right it's it's dead huh I hope so what's your hottest take ooh good question
one day I might have to do a video about how Batman is terrible and there are almost no good
Batman stories and as I say that as someone who has read a lot of them it's not even the usual
like ooh Batman's a fascist he's a rich white male he's actually a conservative dream libertarian
etc etc no I just think a lot of Batman stories suck and they just read like fan fiction because
most writers are fans of Batman even if you are atheistic what's your favorite deity
that is a good good question I always thought Poseidon was really cool Greek god of the sea
he always seemed to get downplayed a little in most stories about Greek mythology people are
more interested in Zeus or Aries maybe Athena but why not Poseidon he's got the whole ocean
the ocean's pretty neat next question what method do you believe would be effective in showing
progressives that they are becoming the tea party of the left first of all you're assuming I buy
into that premise the tea party for those who don't know was a very right-wing group that emerged in
conservative politics in 2009 2010 thereabouts it was very much a response to the election of
Barack Obama but it was supposedly more about the out of control spending and the massive debt
deficit as for the comparisons to the tea party I can see what people are saying and that it seems
to be on the extreme left of the spectrum I think pushing for their left is actually a good thing
when it comes to certain tactics though there is something to be said about elements on the left
that give the left a bad name and really the difficulty is finding a way to criticize that
in a way that isn't helpful to the right and becoming a useful idiot like Tim Poole or Dave
Rubin I'm actually working on a video it's still just a germ of an idea and I'm just not sure the
best way of doing this but a video on how to critique the left in a way that will make it
better rather than just try and tear it down like some secret right-wing operative if you want to
see a good example of that Mexy actually had a video about that I the name is blanking on me at
the moment but I'll put it on the screen and there'll be a link somewhere I think we need more
of that more ways of not necessarily making sure everyone on the left believes the same thing
but that we are all pushing in the same direction and see each other as allies next do you agree
rats greater than blue jays of course you do what is your take on political violence first of all
no I don't agree that rats are greater than blue jays I would put them equal because I try not to be
an animal supremacist okay okay why am I take on political violence in defense I I think it's
absolutely vital and necessary there are a lot of rough groups out there and I think if you're
marching against certain groups and you know certain elements will be there it's important to
defend yourself the police might not necessarily have your back or be there in time that said
a poor political violence more broadly and I don't believe it's an especially great tool when
there are avenues to express or to enact actual change people might not like electoral politics
but it has been shown to change and it's far more effective than political violence in the system
we have now I'm also skeptical of more revolutionary types of violence that completely that roll out
the guillotine and start chopping people's heads off because well revolutions are very turbulent
and you never know what you're gonna get and it's important to look at the population around you
I would advise any violent revolutionary or anyone who advocates political violence to look at the
other side look at how many there are of them and to what degree they are armed and ask yourself
what the result of open combat or violence would be here I think it's better to persuade people
non-violently to our side and ironically enough once we have all those people on our side we won't
need violence anymore because electoral politics will become more powerful what is your favorite
book or best book you've read one of my all-time favorites is Vladimir Nabokov's Pale Fire
really great book about the invasive nature of literary criticism or recently I really enjoyed
The Memoir Educated by Tara Westover very stirring story about a woman who grew up in a very
restrictive environment if you want something a little more fun I would recommend the Mistborn
trilogy by Brandon Sanderson I had a lot of fun reading those too I want to read more Brandon
Sanderson but it's hard to find the time when you're oh god I'm just thinking about the horrible
conservative novel I have to start reading that's gonna be fun are there any conservative content
creators you respect I assume that means respect on YouTube I'm gonna go with no there are
conservative commentators who I generally not necessarily enjoy but honestly disagree with
on YouTube ugh no what is the most painful right-wing youtuber you've ever watched don't
kind of convenient these questions are so close I would probably say no bullshit I'm sure there
have been singular videos from other people who are worse but his content is just so completely
devoid of anything it's just the most asinine superficial stuff I've ever seen I haven't
watched it in a while maybe he's gotten better I doubt it his stuff blows I just cannot watch it
okay let's move on to the curious cat questions what's your process making media analysis videos
I rewatch your sitcom analysis and secret empire videos all the time they're so well made and I'd
love to know how they happen huh also would you ever make a video on Frasier love your channel
first of all thank you I always appreciate that as for the process when it comes to either
watching a TV show or reading a comic book event I watch and read all of it while taking copious
notes either little things I notice they'd be funny jokes any recurring patterns or themes or
ideas while taking those notes I always include timestamps page numbers whatever I need to to
make sure that the section I'm referring to can be easily found again when I'm actually
writing the script and then editing together the video it sucks to mention a certain scene
or moment or line that you then have to hunt for because you totally forgot where it was
200 episodes of a sitcom ago when I get to the end I might rewatch certain key sections or moments
and I usually mark that stuff out ahead of time but I'll try to look over the whole thing just
in case there's anything I missed after that I will then go about putting together a script
how I organize it depends on what I'm talking about sometimes I'll just go through things
chronologically usually because that's the easiest way to do it but I also like pulling out
specific touchstones or themes to certain sections I try to create these videos for people who have
either watched or read what I'm talking about or haven't so I try to offer as many handholds as
possible when it comes to the plot and the characters just to make sure everyone is on
board and following along and then I try to probe a little deeper digging further into
what the central themes and ideas being explored are as for a Frasier video it's
possible I've been asked for a Frasier and Cheers one in the past and I'd probably want to make
back-to-back videos about those who knows maybe in the future I don't have any plans at the moment
though next question what is your ideal partner one thing I would appreciate in an ideal partner
is a healthy sense of curiosity I think someone who has questions about the world and is willing
to try and figure them out is quite admirable and something I like to think I do myself I also
appreciate warmth and kindness and a big heart really matters to me also someone with that
healthy sense of adventure I like traveling I like seeing the world don't always have the
opportunity to do it but when I do I'd like to have someone who's willing to go on those adventures
with me next do you like snow I like snow one of my favorite times of year is a cool winter night
not too cold with snow falling is really beautiful and you really get a sense of quiet and peacefulness
in moments like that even in the city so I do have a lot of love for snow hello Jose I was wondering
since you make analyses on sitcoms what are some of your personal favorites oh good question I have
very boring favorites when it comes to sitcoms The Simpsons is one of my all-time favorite TV
shows I also really enjoyed Seinfeld I wish I could offer some more obscure and strange choices but uh
you know it is what it is next are you looking to make youtube more of a career or just something
you do on the side well right now it's on the side because I simply don't make enough to make
it a career if enough people start giving to my patreon uh sure it's something I would consider
next what were your thoughts on the Canadian election considering the range of possibilities
which I think we got somewhere in the middle a compromise that satisfies no one we were looking
at a possible conservative minority so I think avoiding that is a huge win even though I'm not
really a huge fan of the Liberal Party or Justin Trudeau specifically that said the loss of all
those NDP seats is certainly going to hurt the leftist project in Canada hopefully the next
election will be a push back towards the left we'll see conservatives really blow and are bad
at elections so I guess I'm just grateful for that because the way the wind was blowing that
election could have gone much worse next will you ever do a leftist analysis on a movie instead of
a sitcom I don't have any planned right now a movie would be so much easier than a sitcom because
it's just one thing to watch instead of several hundred small things it's just a question of which
movie because movies are so overdone on YouTube that I'd want to find one that people aren't
talking about I have a few in mind I'd like to do but I would have to do some preliminary research
to make sure no one said what I have in mind because I never liked being the second person
to make a point thoughts on Nick Fuentes maybe you could do a video analyzing him like you
analyzed Tim Poole that's unlikely the issue with Nick Fuentes is that I saw this one clip of him
discussing tactics and one of those tactics involved a very loose relationship with the
truth and the idea that you can say or do whatever you want as long as it's advancing your cause
you don't have to hold yourself to any sort of personal standard as long as you're advancing the
cause and that really just summed up why people like that aren't necessarily worth engaging
if he becomes more relevant maybe I'll make a video about him but he seems pretty fringe at
the moment thoughts on Ronald Reagan it's weird that he's become a deity of sorts even though
most of his policies were pretty bad and his victory over the Soviet Union has been wildly
exaggerated and it really shows the power of the modern conservative echo chamber to deify a man
who while popular was not a great president I wonder if we'll see that happen again with
the current man in charge next who are your influences when making YouTube content who do
you perceive as the influences on your beliefs well for YouTube content I think it's pretty obvious
I owe a debt to the youtuber Sean who as we all know invented the whole idea of talking and not
appearing on camera before then it just was not a thing right potholder 54 for instance is a
youtuber I have a lot of respect for also an influence on how I make my content the way he
approaches his work his dogged attempts to engage with research and portray people honestly is
something I really respect and to do it in a fun entertaining way I think everything has a degree
of influence on you one way or the other I could say for instance Dave Rubin had a massive influence
on me on what not to do and that is to never do anything that ever resembles Dave Rubin's work
ever lest I start hating myself uncontrollably as for influences on my beliefs who there are a lot
of them a lot of what I believe now is influenced by the life I've led the people I've met in my
my personal life the books I've read the things I've learned about the world and generally just
trying to keep a positive attitude to the world around me not necessarily a positive in the terms
of being happy but positive in wanting the best for the world next what is your introduction song
I like the voice for that one I actually got my friend Dana to record a little answer so let's
let her handle this one hey it's Dana I recorded the intro and outro music for Jose's videos which
was truly such an honor and like oh my god I'm on a Q&A now am I like famous for this high channel
oh anyway let's get into this so the song is untitled but I think if I had to call it something
I would call it what could have been a beautiful love letter to a long and amazing friendship
but Jose demanded we cut it down to about three seconds by Dana and also kind of by Jose
but actually thank you so much every time you guys say something sweet about me Jose screenshots and
sends it to me and every time you say something not so nice he screenshots and texts that to me
as well so don't think that I don't see you just kidding you guys are so nice and you make me blush
like all the time so just thank you so much I'm really pleased that you liked the song bye
so thank you Fat Dana next have you heard of ContraPoints she's a trans youtuber who
was recently cancelled due to hiring transphobe Buck Angel to do a 10 second voice clip there's
more to the story of course but I was wondering what your opinions on the controversy were if any
and or if you'd be willing to do a video on it slash ContraPoints not to bring her down but offer
a calmer opinion on the events to answer the first part of the question yes I have heard of the
ContraPoints channel I've been a viewer for a very long time and have enjoyed many of our videos
as for the second part of that question as to whether or not I will make a video about
that whole controversy I will absolutely not be doing that it seems like a very intense war that
does more harm than good in the division it sows amongst people I will say this there should
always be a space to offer friendly and constructive criticism of any youtuber and the
choices they make in their videos so long as people are doing that respectfully and with the
effort to get someone to improve that's only ever a good thing next do you own any blue jays if not
what birds do you own I don't think you can legally own a blue jay I don't think it's a
bird that's been domesticated I don't own any birds I don't plan to own any birds I am
uncomfortable with the idea of owning birds myself because I don't like the idea of caging them birds
can fly free through the sky and I can't imagine them liking their cages if you're a bird owner I
hope you treat them kindly and with love and affection very open to the idea of having a like
a bird friend that lives in my backyard or flies around and maybe shows up every now and again for
some seed and to hang out but that's as far as I'd go with a bird relationship next how does
Canada determine who wins an election because in the United States we have the electoral college
who is a body of electors established by the United States Constitution which forms every
four years for the sole purpose of electing the president and vice president of the United States
it has a lot of flaws like the existence of swing states and giving small more votes and more power
despite a small percentage living there in fact I learned from CGP Grey that the president can win
the electoral college with only 22 of the popular vote is the way Canada determines election more
fair than the US personally I think so in Canada we have a parliamentary system so the idea is
whichever political party wins the most seats in election the leader of that party becomes
the prime minister there's also the possibility if you don't win enough seats to form a majority
or even a clear minority there's also the possibility of coalition governments forming
where two parties can combine their forces and name a prime minister and form a government together
although that's pretty rare in Canada we almost never have coalition governments
I also think it's neat that the leaders of the parties actually have to run in specific ridings
so we've had cases like in our previous election where Maxine Bernier who is the leader of the
People's Party of Canada also known as the far-right anti-immigration party he actually
lost in his riding so he doesn't even get to be in parliament which is awesome oh yeah that's
another thing even if your party loses if you're the leader of the party effectively running for
the prime ministership you can still be in the government but you would just be a member of
parliament you probably wouldn't be the leader of your party come the next election either
next do you believe in the deep state sort of in the sense that there are career bureaucrats who
work within governments through most of their lives and will carry with them certain opinions
and political positions sure but I think the term deep state is often weaponized by administrations
to filter out these career bureaucrats and instead replace them with lackeys who will just operate as
ideological tools if we're going to truly combat the deep state or I should say the entrenched
wisdom within political structures it needs to be done in a way that isn't so in terms of partisan
hackery are there any video games that you like let's keep it to more recent games I just finished
playing god of war which I kind of want to do a video on there's so much to say there I think
that one's been done to death one of my favorite games of all time is the legend of zelda breath
of the wild that was just that but like I was playing the future mario galaxy 2 is one of my
absolute favorites persona 4 metal gear solid even the twin snakes version snake eater that
was probably my favorite of that series elite beat agents or any sort of music game is something I
can get down for I actually nearly made a video for my channel about no more heroes which I think
is one of the best examples of video games as art but then I noticed there was a channel out there
oh god I don't even remember the name of the channel or the name of the video but it did a
look at no more heroes that said everything that I want to say so I thought it's been said and then
I didn't make the video I might make one on video games at some point in the future but I'm not in
a rush next do you think these right wingers will ever lose their fame they're just dominating the
internet I think a lot of them actually have especially the ones have been around for years
and years a lot of them seem to have carved out these little fiefdoms and while they do have
viewership and some success they don't have the relevance they once did of course there's an
endless stream of them and they just seem to cycle them out as old ones lose their luster
I don't think we should ever count on them just losing their fame that's why part of the reason
I made this channel is to push back against it and I'm so encouraged by all the new left-wing
channels I've seen appear since I started making mine not that I think mine is necessarily
influencing any specific ones I'm just glad that there are more voices because this truly is
an all hands on deck type of situation and the more we push back against it the better and it's
always easier to push back when you're doing it with a lot of people next have you thought about
exploring Caitlin Bennett and her horrible content for those who don't know this is the gun girl
she showed up to some college with an assault rifle she took photographs of her walking around
she was instantly the poster girl for many conservatives and she now goes around for info
wars interviewing college students asking them questions and then they just humiliate her with
the responses it's kind of like the opposite of Steven Crowder's thing where he goes out and tries
to make them look stupid and usually by using his deceptive tactics can do that Caitlin Bennett
isn't nearly as capable and she just ends up looking like an idiot I don't think I need to
make a video of it I think just watching one of her videos is enough to embarrass her next do you
think capitalism will fall sometime in this century oh since we're only about 20 years in
it's possible think about the end of capitalism which I generally like the sound of it needs to
be done by people who are ready for it by that I mean it's something we all have to buy into rather
than something that will create a top-down improvement in the world I think there has to
be a degree of bottom-up buying into so to speak of a post-capitalism world that's a lot of hearts
and minds to change can we get there by the end of the century I think we have to try will it happen
though I'm not that optimistic next where do you go for unbiased news what about biased entertaining
news I go nowhere for unbiased news here's a new slash all news is biased what I tried to do is
find news that can be sourced when I say biased news I should clarify I don't mean the sort of
stupid left right-wing bias that people talk about a lot of mainstream media isn't as left
biased as people pretend it is it's more biased toward the status quo so generally speaking I
think any news that can inform you is helpful regardless of its bias the more extreme it's
biased it gets tougher because often that includes distorting things through some kind of
funhouse mirror what I would recommend is always look for news that can be adequately sourced
to some primary source of information if it mentions a poll for instance if it instead of
like sending you to blog after blog after blog and eventually finding the poll something that
links directly to the poll is better better still is checking out that poll for yourself and seeing
how accurately the article in question represents it same thing for interviews or descriptions of
events and there's the old reporter's adage of believe nothing you hear in half of what you see
it's always good to be skeptical but that said if someone can demonstrate something is true I
suggest you believe it and not just write it off as fake news because it might be something you
don't agree with another little axiom that might be helpful the truth does not change in accordance
with our ability to stomach it that's from Flannery O'Connor are there any anime and manga
that you like yes definitely loads my favorite tv series of all time not just anime is nana
favorite manga too by the way it is so good I will make a video about this one day I kind of
hope the series ends before I do but it's been on hiatus for eight years so who knows but there's
loads of others I enjoyed cowboy bebop is one of my all-time favorites also a big fan of gundam seed
best gundam don't care what anyone says I just watched carol on tuesday that was fantastic more
people should check that out great music kids on the slope is really good and I even like things
not by shinshirawa nabe anything by studio ghibli obviously I mentioned princess mononoke but grave
of the fireflies is also fantastic spirited way manga wise let's give a shout out to uh monster
by naoki odisawa which is true work of art I might make a video of that someday too I also like
which is great manga I don't know if they made that into an anime yet they should I also have
a soft spot for shonen manga and anime although it's very hard to watch it and make time though
I do try to keep up with world trigger which I really enjoy I love your content thank you
I have two questions one are there any alt right youtubers you have a morbid fascination with
two I really loved your rosan analysis do you have any other shows that you think would be worth
a rewatch if I've made a video on someone I probably have some degree of fascination with
them I don't know if I'd call it morbid though pretty good at disconnecting from the alt right
space when I'm not actively working on something as for the second one if I make a video on something
you can assume I think it's probably worth a rewatch and I've got another sickon video in the
works and I will say that's worth a rewatch too but with some caveats these are all big shows
sometimes it's better to just check out certain episodes and I try to highlight them as I go along
there are lots of great shows to rewatch though I'm just gonna put a bunch on screen pick any of
those sure they're good dumb question alert if you live in Toronto and have a JPFP then was your
channel inspired by the Toronto Blue Jays no I just think Blue Jays are really cool the team's
fine uh the similarity to the Blue Jay logos is a coincidence it just happens that the bird looks
like the logo and I'll put them side by side you can see the similarity but uh you know what I'm
also going to show you all the original photo that my drawing was inspired by this was the image I
was trying to recreate in my own unique style next how do you pronounce your channel name
Jose that was easy there were two questions about Tim Poole's eventual response to my videos about
him I don't know if this is actually happening these two questions are all that I've heard about
if Tim Poole wants to defend his work he's more than entitled to my main concern is that I'm
worried he won't understand my video if he were to respond at all he'll try to defend individual
points and say I was wrong about this I was wrong about that and try to argue in that sense and that
misses the whole point my video wasn't about the content found in that specific week so much as it
was about how Tim delivers his content more broadly I was looking at his methods the way
he frames issues the way he just repeats conservative talking points and the way he
just gives you a superficial understanding of the stories he reads for example I noticed a lot of
people were pushing back on me about the California bill that affects freelance employees I actually
have no opinion on that because I've not really researched it maybe I should have made that clearer
in the video my point was that Tim is trying to present a very specific perspective on that bill
that reinforces a conservative narrative it could very well be that that bill is awful and does
terrible things that's not what I was interested in I was more interested in how Tim was dishonestly
framing that bill by omitting certain key facts in the story he supposedly read if he actually
responds to my videos in a thoughtful way that actually understands the point I was trying to
make I'd love to see that not holding my breath though last question and I'm so glad the last
question is so so good and such a valuable insight into my site thoughts on cat girls
if someone is a cat girl I respect their identity and to identify as a cat girl I value and respect
you and on that lovely note the Q&A comes to a close thank you to all my patrons for helping
make this happen and getting to 35,000 subscribers by my second year of having this channel feels
pretty good pretty good I hope more people will be watching the future and I hope I can continue
creating great content for you guys that you'll all enjoy if you'd like to be one of these lovely
people whose names are scrolling up the screen consider heading over to my patreon where I hear
we got two new rewards for people on the five dollar tier so check that out and of course you
can head over to twitter and follow me on there if you enjoy this channel you can also subscribe
hit the like button leave a comment or ring the bell thank you to everyone who submitted a question
I hope to see you all again soon