Free speech, free speech, free speech.
I think at this point, you guys probably know I'm big on this free speech thing.
Free speech, free speech.
Free speech, free speech and freedom of speech.
Free speech, free speech, free speech.
Free speech, free speech.
Free speech, and free speech, free speech, free speech.
Free speech, free speech, free speech.
I know you're gonna be blown away by this,
but we're gonna have to talk about free speech today.
It would be nice if a week would pass
when there wasn't some sort of threat
to freedom of speech.
Free speech, free speech, free speech.
Free speech, free speech.
free speech, free speech, free speech, free speech,
or free speech or free speech, free speech, free speech,
Free speech, free speech, free speech, free speech,
free speech, free speech, freedom of speech,
free speech, free speech, free speech.
Obviously, we've spent a pretty good amount of time
around here, talking about the assault
on free speech, free speech, free speech,
free speech, free speech, free speech, free speech,
free speech, free speech, free speech,
free speech, free speech, free speech.