Through the haze of time gone by, and a loose spliff or two, came one of the first sitcoms to
take a nostalgic look back at the 1970s. With a knowing laugh at the fashion and trends of the
day, that 70s show served as a reminder of how things had changed over the last two decades,
and how much had stayed the same. When it debuted in 1998, the series was an instant hit,
becoming one of the breakout comedies for Fox in the late 90s, and launching the careers of its
cast. Many shows have imitated it since, but the unique chemistry of the characters and the
inventive style of its production made it a tough act to follow. The idea for the series began with
a business meeting at the Carsey-Warner Company, a production company that had been responsible for
such hits, including The Cosby Show, Roseanne, and Third Rock from the Sun. During the meeting,
it was suggested that they should start focusing their attention on producing a show for men from
ages 18 to 49. Karen Mandebach, who was working for the company, was struck with a sudden inspiration.
Mandebach pitched the idea of doing a show set in the 70s to Bonnie and Terry Turner, who had
recently created Third Rock from the Sun for NBC. The husband and wife duo teamed with writer Mark
Brazil to create a pitch for what would eventually become that 70s show. The series drew heavily from
the lives of its creators, hearkening back to their days growing up in the 1970s, though
crucially what made the series what it was, was not its reliance on making references to the decade,
but rather a memorable cast of characters who just happened to be living in the 1970s.
Memories of the era would appeal to an older demographic, while the drama of the teens would
appeal to a younger one. The show's creators produced a script for a series called Teenage
Wasteland, and while it wouldn't keep that name, it did reflect the idea of a group of teenagers
trapped in a small town with nothing to do but hang out. Set in the fictional town of Point Place,
Wisconsin, shows were less about cheering on the Packers, although they did that on occasion,
and more about creating a dynamic that was driven by its characters rather than its premise.
Topher Grace was chosen for the role of Eric Foreman through an odd twist of fate. He was
starring in his school's production of Our Town with the daughter of the show's creators,
Bonnie and Terry Turner. He impressed them so much, they brought him into audition,
and he got the part. The character is loosely based on writer Mark Brazil.
Eric is an awkward everyman teenage boy in Love with the Girl Next Door.
Laura Prepon played the role of Donna Pinciotti. Prepon was working as a model before trying her
hand at acting, and she turned out a movie role after becoming enamored with a part of Donna.
Donna is the tomboy of the group, with dreams outside the small town of Point Place.
She's also exploring her feelings for her neighbor Eric.
Ashton Kutcher took a direct route to his role of Michael Kelso. He had been working as a model
for about a year and was incredibly lucky with one of his earliest auditions being for Teenage
Wasteland. He was immediately a favorite of the show's creators. Kelso is the handsome,
yet deeply naive member of the teenage group of friends.
Danny Masterson was cast as Stephen Hyde. He had been performing on stage since he was eight,
when he had a role on Broadway, and had since gone on to appear in hundreds of commercials.
His input helped define the character, giving Hyde a harder edge.
Hyde is the street smart troublemaker of the group. He has a healthy distrust of authority
and an even healthier stash of pot. Wilmer Valderrama was cast for the role of the foreign
exchange student Fez. Although born in Miami, he grew up in Venezuela, giving him an authentic
accent that made him appeal to the show's creators. Fez is the perpetual fish out of water,
taken under the guidance of his new American friends. Although we never quite learn where
Fez is from, or what his name even is, he's still embraced as part of the gang.
Mila Kunis was cast as Jackie Burkhardt. Originally born in Ukraine, her family moved
to America when she was seven, and she took acting classes to help with her English.
She quickly found success with a number of parts but went on auditioning for the role of Jackie,
which was looking for a 16-year-old. She lied about her age to get cast. Jackie is a spoiled
rich kid, only barely tolerable in the group because of her romantic connection to Kelso.
Deborah Jo Rupp was cast as Eric's mother, Kitty Foreman. Although a very experienced actress,
she had largely been doing guest roles on shows such as Seinfeld or in movies like Big. Kitty is
the picture-perfect image of a mother figure, holding her family together through freshly baked
cookies and a well-kept home. Although she's not exactly a homebody, as she also works as a nurse
to help the family through some tough financial times. Kurtwood Smith was cast as Eric's father,
Red Foreman, a longtime veteran of the screen. At the time, he was probably best remembered
for his role in Robocop. Red is the perpetual hard-ass, determined to make his son into the
man he expects him to be. When the show begins, he's struggling to put food on the table as his
job as manager at an auto parts factory is in peril. Don Stark was cast as Bob Pinciati,
Donna's father. Another prolific actor, he had appeared in numerous shows and movies in the
years leading up to this role. Bob is the trendy appliance store owner next door who's not afraid
of wearing his heart on his sleeve. Midge Pinciati, played by Tanya Roberts, was the final member of
the Pinciati household. An actress plucked from the 70s, Roberts joined Charlie's Angels in the
show's fifth season. She was also one of the Bond girls in A View to a Kill and starred in the movie
Sheena. Midge is the flighty lady next door who is exploring the exciting world of feminism.
Although the principal cast was quite large, it would grow larger still in later seasons,
and it would also shrink when some of the actors departed. But the action was primarily driven by
its main cast of teenagers, always ready to assemble in the formant basement. The theme
song of the series was a cover of the Big Star song In the Street. The cover was originally
performed by Todd Griffin for the first season of the series, but a new version was recorded by
Cheap Trick that would be used in seasons two through eight. When a music video is released
for the song, the cast even appeared alongside Cheap Trick. After the pilot was filmed, one of
the few things still missing was the title for the show. Teenage Wasteland was out as the show's
creators couldn't get the rights to that from The Who. Several other titles inspired by popular
music of the era faced similar problems, including such names as The Kids Are All Right.
Eventually that became Feelin' All Right, but Fox didn't particularly like the sound of that.
During test screenings of the pilot, audiences kept calling it That 70s Show.
That's what the audience kept calling it. They had no clue what the title was. They just
referred to it as That 70s Show. So we stopped fighting it and went with it.
Point Place, Wisconsin, May 17th, 1976, 847 p.m. Location, Eric Forman's Basement.
This is how we're introduced to the gang of That 70s Show, debuting in the real world on August
23rd, 1998. This first episode was called That 70s Pilot. We meet Eric, Donna, Hyde, and Kelso
in the basement, with the latter three encouraging Eric to do his teenage duty and steal some beer
from his parents who are having a party upstairs. As Eric goes upstairs, we get our first look at
That 70s Show's unique style with a first-person view from Eric's perspective.
One fun bit of trivia here is that we get the first appearance of Kitty's iconic laugh,
a laugh that was done accidentally.
We also get our first sign that Donna and Eric are into each other.
The Jackie and Kelso relationship is also established.
We also get our very first circle, which is how the teens on the show would gather while getting
high. You couldn't show someone smoking pot on a TV show, but That 70s Show got around this by
moving the camera on someone just after they had taken a puff. That way it simulates a joint,
being passed around in a circle without actually showing the joint itself. You can even see the
characters break into laughter a few times, which was kept in because it seemed authentic. They just
have the giggles because they're high. The show had some fun with high Eric when he has to speak
to his parents, and he finds out that he's getting the vista cruiser. This is another fun example of
its creative style. Future episodes would also take liberties with split screens and
voiceovers and edits to create something that you often didn't see in sitcoms of the day.
With a new set of wheels, Eric and his friends go out of town to a concert and get up to some
shenanigans. But the key part of this episode happens at the end with a pivotal moment for Don
and Eric. This first episode establishes the characters very quickly. We know who they are
and how they relate to one another. This show will be primarily about Eric discovering his
first love and rebelling against a domineering father. What also makes the show feel genuine
is that, while you can certainly tell it's set in the 70s, the kids aren't slavishly following
the trends to set up cheap jokes. They have their own tastes, and the humour is built around that.
In this example, Eric and Donna are mocking the Brady Bunch, but Jackie is a fan. It shows us that
Jackie is into the trendy sitcoms of the day, whereas Eric and Donna are more outsiders to
pop culture. Jackie is conventional, while Eric and Donna aren't. This is how the decade informs
us about the characters, rather than using the characters as a vessel to explore the decade. In
other words, it's how it establishes itself as a character-driven comedy rather than a premise-driven
one. It's also interesting how it reframes memories of the 70s. It's not a show from that decade,
after all. Rather, it's a show about what people from the 90s remembered about the 70s. And sitting
here, over 20 years later, were even more removed from the era. As someone who wasn't alive in 1976,
I have no idea if teenagers mocked the Brady Bunch or not. But I do remember what it was like
to have my first kiss, which is a big part of why the show is so fondly remembered. Not because it
captured an era, but because it presented memorable characters whose experiences transcended that time
period. We get another example in the very next episode, Eric's birthday. Eric wants a cassette
player for the Vista Cruiser, and not an eight-track player.
The point is, I don't want an eight-track tape player.
Then you won't get one.
Oh, but honey, he wants one.
No, I want a tape player, just not an eight-track.
So naturally, he gets this.
I mean, yeah.
It's an eight-track tape player.
I see that.
Just what you asked for.
You made such a big deal about it, I wrote it down.
If a 17-year-old was watching this episode, would they know the difference between an
eight-track and a cassette player? Here's a picture of both of them. A lesser show would
have had the characters hold up a cassette player and make a comment about it being cutting-edge
technology, never to be surpassed. That might get a chuckle, but it's a laugh you probably wouldn't
remember. On that 70s show, it's not about laughing at the technology of the past. It's
about laughing at growing up with parents who don't listen. That's something you can laugh at
and relate to, and it's what makes this show particularly memorable. Eric's birthday also
introduced another important first, Eric's sister, Laurie, played by Lisa Robin Kelly.
Hello, Laurie.
Red treats Laurie a little differently than he does Eric.
Laurie, you're not driving a vista cruiser.
It's old and undependable.
It could break down, you'd be at the mercy of any maniac who came along.
That's okay for Eric, but you're taking a Toyota.
And I should mention, not every scene in the circle involved passing a joint around.
That 70s show ran for eight seasons, though it only took place over roughly three and a half
years. If you've ever been watching an episode and wondering when exactly you are, at the end
of the opening credits when we see the vista cruiser's license plate, the renewal sticker
tells us which year the episode is set in. This does make things a little awkward at times,
as the timeline, particularly because of episodes with holidays, doesn't always line up. By honing
in on each year, we can split the series up into four distinctive eras. And as we follow the lives
of these characters, we'll see how the series gradually evolves. That 70s show spends only a
brief stretch in 1976. In fact, only the first 12 episodes of the series take place in that year,
before we move on to 1977 for the second half of the first season. One exception is Episode 23 of
Season 1, which also takes place in 1976, in part because the order of the episodes was
shuffled around while airing. This creates a few instances of confusing continuity, like Eric
mentioning he and Hyde hadn't yet sprayed the water tower when we had seen them do just that
in the episode that aired the previous week. In addition to Eric and Donna's love affair,
one of the big overarching themes in these early episodes is the precarious economic spot of the
I've noticed that the pop selection has really went downhill since your dad got laid off.
He's not laid off. He's just part-time. And shut up. When the president comes to visit point
place, Red is selected to ask the president a question. When he's given a question,
rather than being allowed to ask his own, Red gets frustrated. A man has to stand up and be heard.
I will not sit quietly by while everything is taken away from me.
They took my job, my stability, and now they want to take away my right of free speech.
You still have the Toyota, it gets great mileage.
It being 1976, the president right now is Gerald Ford, who assumed office after Richard Nixon
resigned. This is why Nixon was on the cusp of being impeached and removed from office.
What Red is feeling here is not just the indifference towards him from the federal
government, but the general sense that America is leaving him behind, and that the country is
corrupt from top to bottom, letting him lose his job as he's lost in the shuffle of the marketplace.
What Red doesn't realize is the America he thought he knew as a boy wasn't a whole lot better,
or at least not as free as he imagined it was. It's not so much that the country has changed,
as he just happens to be one of the people it's left behind. And the show doesn't make it such
a big secret here that the problem lies much with a business class that uses people like Red as pawns.
Bob, a member of the local community of businessmen, represents that world when he thinks of Red to
ask the president a question. The important thing is to choose the right person. You know,
a working class guy, your average Joe. I guess someone you and I would call a loser.
So, of course, I thought of you.
Although Red planned to go off script at the presidential event,
at first he seems a bit too nervous to ask any question at all. But after Erica makes
a rash political protest by streaking the president, Red finds his nerve.
Hey, Jerry. Here's my question. How the hell could you pardon Nixon?
Sometimes a man's gotta do what he thinks is right.
These early episodes probably have Red at his most relatable, perhaps because of the economic
insecurity that people are feeling in the present day, and something that people in the 90s might
have felt as well when this show was first airing. And back then, it was when a booming economy was
raising questions about who the economy is exactly booming for. One of the early plot lines, just to
get the obvious out of the way, was having the gang go disco dancing. One part of this
episode has Fez noticing one of the disco's inspirations. And Fez is revealed to be a fantastic
dancer. Although Fez is a mystery throughout the series, it's early on when he's at his best.
He seems like he's genuinely from somewhere, with a history and culture that only seems
especially foreign in contrast to the relative ignorance of the largely white small town in
middle America. There's something sweet seen Fez struggling to understand American culture,
and it offers members of the audience less familiar with 70s culture the chance to have
it explained to them in a less heavy-handed way. There will be much more to say about Fez as the
series progresses, but over time this innocence would vanish, and we'd be left with another
early trait he showed in these episodes, being a bit of a creep. The early episodes of That 70
Show also featured a landmark moment in TV history. In the episode, Eric's Buddy, We Meet Buddy,
played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Eric's lab partner and one of the most popular kids in school.
As their friendship grows, so does a misunderstanding, at least in Buddy's mind.
And I feel like I'm playing this part, right? But it's not me.
This is the first kiss between two men on network TV. Although sometimes that's credited to the
Dawson's Creek episode True Love, Eric's Buddy beat its air by about five months.
Eric being straight has to turn Buddy down, but the two agree to stay friends.
If you don't want to be my lab partner anymore, then I'll understand.
No, no. Oh, I didn't mean it like that. Um, look, we're still friends. Really? Yeah.
And as the rules of sitcoms go, with a one-off guest star destined to be a one-off guest star,
we never see Buddy again. At the time, this moment was heralded as a very positive depiction of a
gay character. Buddy is cool, popular, and charming, not at all living up to any of the
stereotypes of gay characters you might see on other shows, including this one in later seasons.
The episode was even nominated for a GLAAD Award as an outstanding TV individual episode.
What's probably most notable about this moment is the audience's reaction, though,
which is genuine shock from something they likely hadn't seen on a TV show before.
Looking at it 20 years later, it seems almost tame compared to modern television,
and it's a little disappointing to see Buddy play the token gay character who's there and gone now
that the gay episode has been handled. It does reveal how little representation there was for
gay characters on TV at this time, and perhaps what makes it age less gracefully is that it was on
the cusp of a growing change in television, which would see an increase in the number of gay
characters on sitcoms. Buddy wasn't even the first character to appear on the series, as the pilot
featured a gay couple, one of whom was a mechanic who traded a car part for concert tickets to the
gang. Aside from these brief moments, the romance on the show was overwhelmingly heterosexual,
and one of the top concerns for its characters. Jackie and Kelso, being the established couple
in the beginning, struggle to stay together. Or rather, Kelso is constantly trying to convince
his friends he's about to dump his very annoying girlfriend. Knowing that Mila Kunis is only 15
throughout season 1 does make a few of the scenes a bit uncomfortable to watch, though because of
the age difference between her and Ashton Kutcher, who was 20 at the time, most of the scenes where
they're making out happen hidden behind car seats and other obstacles. Kelso's attraction
to Lori in particular reveals he's not entirely committed to Jackie, and while Lori is no stranger
to hooking up, Kelso's chances largely only exist in his head. Of course, the biggest romantic
plotline in the early episodes is the Eric and Donna relationship. It's immediately obvious from
the first episode that these two would be getting together, so a bit of intrigue is thrown into the
middle of it, with Hyde attempting to create a love triangle. A few flirtations from Hyde
doesn't really do much to interrupt Eric and Donna getting closer, often in the most embarrassing
way possible. As the year comes to an end, Eric and his friends hold their own Christmas party.
It's about as close as Hyde gets to winning Donna's affections.
Even with this magical Christmas, Eric and Donna still seem like the couple destined to be together,
and by the time Valentine's Day rolls around next year, this subplot is put to bed,
with Hyde backing off after being rejected by Donna.
Throughout 1976, the innocence of the series is apparent, with Brad losing a kind of innocence
when he learns that America isn't the land of dreams he once imagined. Through Fez's ignorance
of his new homeland, in Eric and the gang learning about gay people, and Eric and Donna discovering
their first love. The world is becoming a more complicated place, and the idealized version of
the world these characters imagined is fading away. This is a common theme in most coming-of-age
stories, but it feels even more prominent on that 70s show, because we in the audience have the
advantage of knowing a future that these characters don't. We may not know what happens in our future,
but we know at least some of the major events that will happen in theirs.
And their ignorance of those facts helps make the impression of innocence even more pronounced.
Once Hyde stepped aside from the Eric and Donna pairing, it gave his character the
chance to grow into something more interesting. In the season 1 episode Career Day, we meet Hyde's
mother Edna, played by Katie Seagal. She works as the school's lunch lady, and she has a troubled
relationship with Hyde.
This is sadly the last we see of Hyde's mother Edna, though he would have a number
of father figures throughout the years, including Red. In the episode Punk Chick,
when Hyde falls for Chrissy, played by Jade Gordon, he's tempted to follow her to New York,
where she plans to start a punk band.
Red and Kitty try to convince Hyde not to run off to New York.
And so does Eric.
Hyde eventually decides to stay in point place.
Although it's never made clear whose advice convinced Hyde to stay,
we do learn that what Hyde is missing most in his life is the good influence of the Foreman
household. Something that becomes essential when Edna runs off with a trucker at the end of season
1, leaving Hyde without a home.
Even though Edna's not coming back, Hyde rejects help at first.
But Eric goes to his parents, who are struggling to afford the kids they already have.
Ultimately, it's Red who has to step up and make the decision to help Hyde,
with some encouragement from Kitty.
And Hyde quickly makes himself the model son in the Foreman household.
What this consistently reinforces is that Hyde needs a stable family life,
and in particular a father figure like Red to keep him on the straight and narrow path.
It's a very old-fashioned message. A young boy needs a father figure.
In the second season, Hyde even gets a second quasi-father figure in Leo,
played by Tommy Chong, who gives Hyde a job.
The money goes towards the noble goal of supporting the Foreman household.
Hyde is the model wayward child, taken under the wing of a strong father who sets him on the right
path, and by season 2 he's slowly transforming into a respectable member of society. It's a sort
of arc you might see in a family drama from the 70s, though thankfully that 70s show doesn't fit
so neatly into that sentimental cliché. In the season 2 finale, moon over point place,
Jackie is busted for holding marijuana, and Hyde takes the fall for her.
And then Red finds out.
Red threatens to kick Hyde out, but Jackie eventually takes responsibility for what
happened, and Hyde is allowed to stay in the Foreman household. Hyde was on a promising path,
but to save Jackie, he throws himself in harm's way. What's particularly interesting is how he
does it, though. He calls himself a dirtbag, and in some ways Hyde still sees himself like that,
in spite of all of the work he's done on improving while living with the Foreman's.
The Foreman's can take him in and give him a home and give structure to his life,
but in his heart he still sees himself as an outsider. Hyde is a strong representative for
1977, because if 1976 was about the loss of innocence, 1977 is about finding this new
sense of home in a strange new world. Only Hyde has felt that way through most of his life.
As much as he had hoped his mother would pull herself together and be a better parent,
going so far as to be the bigger person and apologize first when they fight, he ultimately
can't get her to be the mother he needs, and when the Foreman's offer him a new home,
he can't see himself as a part of it. At least, not right away. The show's answer,
at least in this year, takes the shape of Bud, Hyde's father, played by Robert Hayes.
He returns to point place, and after he's discovered by Hyde,
tries to make amends for abandoning his son.
Bud, you're doing great now, huh? Color TV? I remember when I was a kid, I didn't even have
a father. I got no excuse. I was a jerk. I've been a jerk my whole life.
And all I can do is tell you I'm sorry and hope that you'll believe me.
But even if this seems like recreating the childhood he lost, there are hints that this won't last
either. There is this strange episode where Red tries to teach Bud how to be a better father.
Steven doesn't need another friend, Bud. Steven needs somebody to ride his ass.
It seems as though the answer to Hyde's feeling of alienation is… more strict fathering,
from a blood relation this time. But as we'll see in later years, Hyde's life is not so easily
fixed with that, and his rebellious streak isn't something that needs to be disciplined out of him,
but rather channeled into something more productive, such as protecting a friend,
the way he stood up for Jackie. Jackie and Kelso had had something of a rocky year in 1977. In the
very first episode of that year, Season 1's ski trip, Jackie breaks up with Kelso after finding
out he was making out with Pam Macy. They get back together by the end of the episode, though,
but this would establish a pattern. Four episodes later, in the episode titled The Pill,
Jackie has a pregnancy scare. After Kelso melts down in response, they break up again.
Only to get back together in the episode, Prom Night.
In Season 2, their relationship is tested once again with Eric's sister Lori becoming a part
of the main cast. She takes an interest in Kelso and his new van.
This isn't Lori falling for Kelso, though. It's something a bit more basic than that.
Much of the season then focuses on Kelso trying to balance
dating Jackie with cheating on her with Lori.
While Kelso was clearly the bad guy in all of this, he might be mistaken as being a hapless
fool being used by Lori. Eventually, the truth comes out in Kiss of Death. Kelso has finally
realized that the genuine love of Jackie means more to him than the lust represented by Lori,
and he decides to break things off with her. While Lori is
always insufferable, it's pretty clear that this is, and has always been, Kelso's fault.
More than just being a fool, he actively hurt Jackie, and when she ends things with him,
it looks like it will be sticking around for longer than an episode or two this time.
And so ends the show's first relationship.
Jackie seemed like a challenging person to date, but it doesn't excuse what Kelso did to her,
and with naive Kelso being the more affable character in the affair, it's interesting
that he was the bad guy in the whole thing. Often in stories of an infidelity, characters are more
helpfully coded as heroes or villains of the story, but especially for a sitcom, the dynamic
here is surprisingly not straightforward. It shows us how trust is broken by deeds rather than persona,
and that someone's personality doesn't always tell you who they are as a person. At least, not
entirely. Although it took many twists and turns to get here, Jackie and Kelso both get the chance
to grow beyond the high school romance they had. Jackie moves on to other romantic interests,
as the show teases her possibly dating Hyde or Fez, while Kelso tries to date Lori for real.
This leads to some classic confrontations between the two ladies in the Foreman basement.
Eventually, and completely unsurprisingly, Lori cheats on Kelso,
and he apologizes to Jackie.
Kelso's apology is pretty good, and in time he realizes that the only woman he wants to be with
is Jackie. Jackie still might be interested in him, so she tests Kelso to see if he's truly changed.
And we're back where we started. Albeit with Kelso seeming to have grown up a little, and Jackie
deciding to forgive him again. Although it's nice enough for Kelso to have become a more mature
character, it does reveal that the show wasn't entirely sure how to evolve Jackie. While her
being a year younger than everyone else in the gang, and two years younger than Kelso who is held
back a grade, it still seems odd that she's only been able to identify herself based on whether or
not she's dating someone. She's of course rich and popular, but after the first season, these
aspects of her character seem less important, as neither are quite as relevant when she's hanging
out with the other characters. Aside from being fodder for a few jokes here and there. Much in
the same way Hyde's answer to the alienation he felt was to end up back with his father, Jackie and
Kelso respond to their separation in the same way. Fear of the new normal certainly makes sense, and
it reveals that perhaps these teens aren't quite ready to step into adulthood just yet. They've
still got some growing to do. Another reason Jackie and Kelso may have been put together is because
Lisa Robin Kelly, who played Laurie on the show, exited the series in season 3. Although her
character was adding a lot to the show, the actress was having personal issues behind the scenes. In
an interview with ABC in 2012, she described having had a miscarriage at the time and then falling
into alcoholism. Although she would briefly return in season 5 for four more episodes,
Laurie would eventually be recast, with Christina Marr taking over the part.
Eric and Donna's relationship becomes official in the second half of season 1,
with the first step being Eric giving Donna his class ring.
And in season 2, they finally say they love each other.
Well, Eric says it eventually.
And after nearly two seasons, the two of them finally do it in the episode, the first time.
Eric and Donna have largely made the journey comfortably, and 1977 is probably their best
year as a couple. They handle most challenges that come their way pretty well, with my favorite being
the episode, Eric's Panties, where Donna finds a mysterious pair of panties in the backseat of
the Vista Cruiser. She assumes they belong to Shelly, a girl who had been flirting with Eric,
played by Mamet Patterson.
Even with things mostly going well for the two, the third season's episode,
Baby Fever, did give us a hint that Eric and Donna might not have the happy ending they imagined.
And the comfort Donna gets from Midge has an ominous undertone.
One interesting part of why Donna and Eric clash is that Donna wants more for herself
than to be a housewife, unlike what happened to her mother, whereas Eric is modeling his future
on what he sees with his parents. One of the keys to understand Donna and Eric's mindsets
is to look at what their parents were going through in the same year. In 1976, Red was
struggling to put food on the table as his hours were reduced at the auto plant. In a special
Star Wars themed episode called A New Hope, we find out that the plant is going to be shut down
for good, leaving Red without a job. This leaves the Foreman's in a rough spot.
While it seems dire, Red gets an opportunity to turn things around when a Price Mart opens up in
town. On the other side of the property line, Bob is threatened by the arrival of Price Mart.
While Red may not seem like the best of friends to Bob, his reasons for going after that job
make a lot of sense, as his family heads closer to going broke. For Bob though, Price Mart is the
beginning of the end of his appliance store, and it goes under in season 3. Red throughout his life
is at the mercy of the big businesses that come and go through point place. When the auto industry
started outsourcing abroad for its parts, his plant got shut down and he was out of work. But
when a big box retail store opens up, he suddenly has a job again. There isn't much room for him to
decide where his life will go. At first it seems as though Bob is the wiser person, investing in
his own business and providing comfortably for his family, until a big business comes in and turns it
all upside down, leaving him without a job. Bob isn't quite the master of his destiny that he
imagined, and even though he was a big wheel in the business community in point place, there are
always bigger fish outside that very little pond. When we look at Eric and Donna, we can see their
parents' outlooks reflected in their own lives. Eric has a more traditional conservative vision
for his future because the system seems to be keeping his family afloat. Even if times can get
tough, eventually it all works out. For Donna, her father's failure reflects a system that shows how
a bigger force can wipe you away in an instant. This is compounded by Eric growing up as a boy
and Donna as a girl. Eric is comforted in the idea that society has been built for someone like him,
and challenges are temporary roadblocks. Whereas Donna knows she has an uphill battle. When luck
turns against Bob, she's reminded of a system that doesn't work for her, but rather only values
her as a commodity. And when she looks at her mother, she sees someone who's opportunity at
being something other than a housewife taken from her because she happened to get pregnant at a young
age. So Eric assuming he and Donna will just get married and settled down, while Donna dreams of
something more, explain why there might be some confusion on where the relationship is headed.
The irony for Eric is that he's wrong to have any faith in the system. Red getting a job at
Price Smart, saving their family from financial peril, is pure luck. To be fair, Red had originally
been offered a job as a cashier, and then insisted on a management position. But even with the benefit
of his hard head, that opportunity would be nothing if Price Smart hadn't chosen to open up a store
in point place. But Eric does have the opportunity to learn better, and that comes in the shape of
his mother Kitty. Kitty works as a nurse at a nearby hospital, a job she took on to help the
family with her finances. When Eric goes to the hospital with Kitty for career day, he learns just
how capable she is. You know, your mom does the work of five nurses. This place would fall apart
without her. And she's so funny. Oh yeah, she is. Um, wait, no, she's not. And even more than that,
Eric learns about one of the real challenges of working at a hospital. I mean, for Mr. Anderson,
but you knew this guy, mom. How do you deal with all of this?
While Eric and his mother would bond as the seasons went on, Kitty never quite becomes the
force in the foreman household that Red is. If her job as a nurse symbolizes her strength,
it's telling that she seems to quit and go back throughout the series, which reflects an
insecurity in her status. That insecure status manifests in Eric, who has a less than perfect
understanding that Donna wants to be more than a homemaker. Eric assumes his mother is happiest at
home, when we'll see in later seasons that isn't really the case. For Donna, her faith in relationships
is also reflected in how her parents seem to be falling apart in theirs. As Midge empowers herself
through attempting to understand feminist theory, Bob grows worried that it may make her want to
start becoming a radical and do something crazy, like get a job. Well, I'm the man of the house,
and I say you're not going to community college. You can't tell me what to do, you big ass.
Midge's interest in feminism is a bit fleeting, though, as she and Bob seem to drift with
every fad that comes their way, from fondue to nudism.
They used to be normal. What the hell happened to them?
Well, I don't know. How can she not eat meats? That can't be healthy.
And over time, we find out that Bob and Midge just aren't happy together.
Donna, your mother was fine until she met those feminists and started thinking.
Well, excuse me, Bob, but I'm not happy.
With her parents constantly fighting, the last thing Donna wants to create is a mere image of
them with Eric. And without that positive role model for a happy relationship, she wants to
create something new and different. Although feminism was a passing interest for Midge,
it seems to have had a stronger impact on Donna. Hyde, Red, Jackie, and Kelso all respond to the
changes of 1977 with a return to the familiar. For Hyde, it's a chance to have a father again.
For Red, it's back to working as management in the corporate machine. For Jackie and Kelso,
it's giving their troubled relationship another chance. But for Bob, he can't go back to running
a store again, and he and Midge aren't returning to the happy marriage they once had. So Eric and
Donna have to ask themselves where they are in this year of change, going down the familiar
path of Eric's parents, or finding something completely new.
1978 brought with it some major changes to the show. Eric is slowly realizing the relationship
he has isn't like the one his mom and dad have. Eric tries to escalate his relationship with Donna
by giving her a promise ring in the season 3 finale. As Donna considers the meaning of this
promise ring, she realizes she's not ready for the commitment it represents. So she gives it back to Eric.
The important thing is when you see yourself in Paris, or wherever, I'm there, right?
Right? I don't know. Not always. We're together now. Isn't that enough? No! I mean...
I mean damn, Donna! If you can see a future for yourself without me,
and that doesn't like break your heart, then we're not doing what I thought we were doing here,
and you know what? Maybe we shouldn't even be together at all. Are you breaking up with me?
Well, are you getting back that ring?
That's... Then...
Yes. It's ironically not the present that breaks up Eric and Donna, but the future,
and their different visions for it. Donna wants to see where life will take her, and Eric wants
to start building a life he already imagines. And ironically, they end up heading into a direction
neither of them wanted. After the breakup, Eric is left shattered in a way that anyone who's
gone through their first breakup can probably relate to. Geez, huh? You look like you've just
been dumped! Later on, Red actually offers some good advice. Listen, I'm gonna give you a few
days to pull yourself together. You can stand bad and sleep, watch TV, whatever you need to do.
Thank you, Dad. The fallout of Donna and Eric's split would play out over several episodes,
with the two of them learning how to live among one another after some really nasty post-breakup
feelings. But this moment where Eric and Red bond is surprisingly sweet, and in many ways
emblematic of how the two have been growing increasingly close over the previous seasons.
Sometimes it took the shape of Eric standing up to Red.
Now you screwed yourself when you didn't return those books! Now go!
Okay. No.
Sometimes the bonding happened on a hunting trip.
I think you're angry, because life didn't turn out exactly the way you wanted it to.
And, uh, maybe you think if you yell at me, I won't let life push me around, too.
You came up with that answer awful fast.
Eric and Red's relationship is built on Eric's rebellion while understanding who his father is,
and Red trying to make Eric who he thinks Eric needs to be. By reconciling all of these things,
Eric is able to grow himself. Red is both a role model and cautionary tale for Eric,
and he takes the lesson to heart. But Red is also a father to him that offers comfort and love when
he needs it the most, like in that moment after his breakup with Donna. But there is something
in the relationship that's shaped by the less enlightened era Red comes from, where emotions
aren't so easily shared, such as when Red lies about crying after being dumped.
It's a major event when Red tells Eric he loves him.
I'm sorry, what?
When Kitty finds out Red was hopped up on medication,
she tries to stop Eric from returning the gesture.
Go to your room.
Red tries to explain the rules around saying I love you for men.
When he's drunk, when he's dying,
or when he's in big trouble and it's the only way out.
Other than that.
Other than that, it's just a given.
While the idea that love is simply understood is nice, but it's clear from the rest of this episode
that everyone understands that saying it out loud means something too, something more than that
implicit understanding offers. That outward expression of emotion is not something Red can
offer Eric. The relationship of a cold father to an emotionally needy son is an old trope,
and by setting it in the 70s, maybe it seems more acceptable. But being a show from the 90s,
it was aware of how limited this relationship could be, and watching 20 years on, it becomes
more apparent. Fathers and sons should be able to say they love one another without
slamming face first into this cliché of what masculinity should be.
There's still a lot of positives between Eric and Red, but something as simple as them being
open with their feelings is a sad limit for what could have been a more meaningful relationship.
1978 brought with it the departure of Mitch. Growing so frustrated with her marriage to Bob,
she takes off for California.
I can't believe she would just take off without even a hint or a warning.
No warning? Dad, she was always saying I'm unhappy and I'm gonna leave.
I mean, that's just what married people say.
Donna luckily has kitty to be there for her as a mother figure.
But it's been so nice having someone to talk to since my mom left.
I know. Someone who understands what I'm going through.
Behind the scenes, the reason Tanya Roberts loved the show was to care for her husband,
who had become terminally ill. Roberts would appear in later seasons in a handful of guest
spots. We don't get nearly as much insight into how Donna handles the breakup, since the show
focuses on Eric. But it's interesting that both of them turn to his parents for help getting
through it, and the comfort they offer in some ways reinforces the idea of a happy ending in the
future, that one day they'll find someone they won't break up with. They both try dating other
people, with Donna dating Kelso's brother Casey, played by Luke Wilson. And Eric dates a few other
girls, sometimes sneaking off with Red's new Corvette to attract them. None of these girls
last long, and while Donna continues to date Kelso, Eric realizes he's still in love with her.
And now, Donna, all of a sudden, it's like the day after we broke up. All over again.
Casey is revealed to just be toying with Donna, leaving her heartbroken. So she runs off to
California to be with Midge at the end of season 4. In the season 5 premiere, Eric goes to California
to get her back. I love you. And I have so much to say, but I just... And a few episodes later,
Eric and Donna get engaged. And the rest of season 5 largely see these two trying to win
approval from everybody else for their decision to get married in their final year of high school.
It's a very strange series of events when, in the space of roughly half a year, we go from
Donna and Eric breaking up to getting engaged. In terms of real-world time, this played out on
television over roughly a year and a half, which seems more reasonable, but the sheer volume of
episodes crammed into each show's annual time span creates a real decompression of time. This
can be understood as time feeling much longer when you're younger, and your teenage years
seeming so grand and important that everything can change in the course of a few days or weeks.
And two people can go from not knowing what their future might hold to knowing they'll be together
forever over the course of a few months. It also reinforces how quickly Eric and Donna are growing.
They manage to gain a lot of maturity in their time apart, and through the process of trying
to convince everyone that their engagement is a good idea, we see what feels like the ultimate
conclusion of the Eric and Red dynamic. As a disapproving Red throws numerous roadblocks to
stop the wedding from happening, Eric refuses to back down, and Red has one final confrontation
with him. You're stuck to your guns, and I admire that you're willing to go out on your own.
Eric is now a man. And ironically, it wasn't by obeying Red that he got there,
but by rebelling against him. And also by emulating him. Because Red Foreman is not
a man who backs down, and now, neither is Eric. It's a bit strange how this relationship stopped
being about Eric and Donna and gradually became more about Eric and Red. Eric's path to adulthood
meant he has to move beyond his father and grow into something better. It's an uplifting message
that reveals that Red can be a role model, but can't be a limit on who Eric can be. And Eric manages
to make it to adulthood, not losing that sweeter, kinder, gentler side of himself. Donna's dreams
of doing more outside of Point Place don't seem to come up as much in these episodes, and she
doesn't think the marriage will somehow hinder that. The loss of Eric, her mother, and being
messed with Casey has dropped her back into the arms of Eric, holding on to what certainty she
can find in life. In some ways, this reflects the limited options of women of the era. If Donna
represented this bold new feminist force ready to take on the world, a few bad turns are all it
takes to leave her ready to move into a trailer and begin living the domestic life. Although she
and Eric plan on going to college together, when Eric's plans change, so do hers and she stays in
Point Place. Comparing her and Eric, it seems Eric has the brighter future with the path to happiness
he wants right there for him when he's ready to take it. Donna has to compromise for him.
But all of this started happening in season 5 is important because that seemed like the season
where the show became more cynical and less thoughtful in its depiction of its characters.
Season 5, which starts in the summer of 1978, has a strange feel to it. The characters seem to behave
in a more exaggerated way. Red has always been mean to all of Eric's friends, Fez included, but
he seems nastier to him starting in this season, often drifting into outright racism.
Thanks for the help. You seem to have a natural talent for handling luggage.
And speaking of comments like that, we'll see characters casually drop in gross stuff
like this in random conversations. I'm starting to get into the Asian ladies.
I know what you mean. The mystery of the Orient. I'm very sexy.
Characters seem to bit flatter too. Eric, for example, started becoming far more nerdy in
this season. In season 1, we found out he really enjoyed Star Wars. But in the following three
seasons, it never really comes up. But starting in season 5, he's suddenly collecting action
figures and getting very upset when Red makes a homophobic comment about Luke Skywalker.
Luke Skywalker, this Luke Skywalker, that I'm sick of hearing about that little fruit.
Luke Skywalker is not! He and Leia, clearly!
Eric was never particularly cool, but he also wasn't so aggressively nerdy. By the way,
the future has some bad news for Eric about the Luke and Leia thing. Red becomes increasingly
patriotic in this season, even for some reason becoming a Nixon defender.
Thank God for the honest ones like Richard Nixon, huh?
What did you say?
I said that Nixon was framed and Kennedy was a commie?
That's right.
While Red always had a degree of patriotism in him, this is a far cry from the Red Forman
who confronted Gerald Ford about pardoning Nixon. Red's patriotism is now more of a cliche.
The biggest change in season 5 though is with Kitty, when she mistakenly thinks she's pregnant
but is actually going through menopause. She reveals this in front of her parents,
played by Betty White and Tom Poston. This major moment in her life might have led to her character
growing beyond motherhood and evolving to someone different. And while we do see some nice moments
between her and her parents, what we get far more of in season 5 are a series of bad menopause jokes.
Season 5 flattened its characters into cliches, making the dynamics less compelling than they
were in earlier seasons. Part of this is that the show's premise is literally trapping them
in this decade, meaning these characters are limited in the way they can grow or change.
If they have to forever be teens, it doesn't really offer the opportunity to truly become
adults. Not every change in season 5 was a bad one though, as it did also include the introduction
of Kitty's new dog, Shotzi. Shotzi even joins a very special circle.
At the beginning of season 4, Hyde is back living with the Four Men's.
When Jackie pressures Kelso to get married, he runs away to California with Donna,
finally ending his relationship with Jackie for good. With Kelso gone,
Jackie goes into season 5 in a very different direction.
This comes out of nowhere in the series, but there were a few hints leading up to this moment.
As you saw earlier, Hyde took the fall for Jackie's pop possession,
and between one of Jackie and Kelso's breakup, Hyde realizes he might have some feelings for her.
But it doesn't get too much further than a kiss.
A season and a half later, the two of them are exploring those old feelings for real.
Although a new development, the spark for their relationship isn't terribly inspired.
But it does offer a few nice moments that speak to their history,
like Jackie taking the fall for Hyde's pop possession. But when Jackie reveals she still
has some kind of attachment to Kelso, it puts a strain on her relationship with Hyde.
Although they smooth things over, Hyde's concerns get the better of him when he thinks
he's caught Jackie and Kelso being intimate when she was really comforting him after Fez
had an erotic dream about Kelso. Hyde responds by cheating on Jackie.
When the truth comes out, Hyde is left apologizing, and Jackie breaks things off.
They get back together early in season six.
If you note that when Jackie and Hyde got together, it was the summer of 1978. And now
looking at Donna and Jackie enjoying an afternoon run at the pool, it's still the summer of 1978.
Not literally, of course. The show has actually gone through an entire season where the gang
finished their final year of high school. Yet, for some reason, the license plate still reads
1978. The kids of the show are trapped in the 70s and trapped in the show's cyclical storylines,
in a sense making a commentary about how shows like these are limited. Instead of its characters
growing over time, they're stuck. Even a show that was primarily designed to be driven by its
characters is eventually trapped by its premise. Season 5's trip to California had that 70s show
trap its characters in its own version of Hotel California, which, by the way, was originally
recorded in 1976, the first year covered in that 70s show. While Hyde continuously tries to escape
his circumstances, constantly getting pulled back into where he was before, Jackie's struggle is
a bit sadder. She only seems to ever be defined by who she is or who she isn't dating. While her
character is very much the vehicle for discussing relationships early on, particularly for Donna,
who needs someone to help her make sense of her feelings for Eric, Jackie doesn't get a chance
to be much more than the relationship character. Jackie is very much carried by Mila Kunis'
performances, who manages to make the character both lovable and obnoxious in near-equal measures.
She's a great part of the series, but the series doesn't do well enough to give her more varied
things to do. One change I haven't mentioned yet is that Tommy Chong joined the principal cast in
season 4 but left the show in season 5. The reason Chong left the show is because he was arrested
for selling 7,500 bongs through a company he partially owned. He had to pay a fine of
$20,000 and was sentenced to 9 months in prison, but he would eventually return to the show once
he had been let out. Another change we have to talk about is one that had built building for the
last few seasons. Fez was starting to get really weird. As the last in the gang to lose his virginity,
one of the running gags for Fez was how his perpetual quest to hook up with someone never
seemed to work out. His dating life is a series of amusing fails, with my personal favorite being
Caroline, who he briefly dated in season 3. Caroline is not quite as sweet as she first appears.
As you might have guessed, they break up. When Fez isn't failing in the dating world,
he is making numerous jokes about how horny he is. And the more he jokes,
the more the bar gets raised where what counts as creepy.
Fez starts off as a little weird, but as the audience gets used to him, he has to say or do
something strange to remind everyone that he's not like everyone else, raising the bar for what
counts as weird. As the cycle repeats, the bar keeps getting raised, but at this point it isn't
as shocking because Fez has been building to this level for years. Fez also seems less like he's
from a real place anymore. In the early seasons whenever he speaks his native language, he defaults
to speaking Spanish. But now we're getting jokes like this. Fez seems more like a cartoon
character than an actual foreign exchange student. Fez's transformations is one of
the only ones that felt gradual in season 5 though. Even if the other characters all have some
degree of backstory, they still seem noticeably different as the show keeps them frozen in this
70s moment, while using a heavy hand to keep this impression that things are still fresh.
But Fez was frozen very early on in the series as the series struggled to give him any lasting
changes to his character. He was just weird, and he kept getting weirder and, as a consequence,
creepier. As season 5 moves along, Lori makes her surprise return. And as Fez is under threat of
deportation, having graduated high school, Lori does something drastic. In the season 6 premiere,
the kids are alright, we found out that Lori's newly turned over leaf of being a better person
immediately turns back over and she returns to being horrible, leaving Fez to be her husband
in name only as she dates around. And that's about it. We don't get much more out of this plotline,
and Fez continues to putter along. One of the recurring themes for 1978 is how the characters
have become frozen. If the previous two years were about discovering a new world, stepping out into it,
and then saying maybe that wasn't such a great idea and heading back the way they came,
this year was very much about being frozen in place, deciding that where the show needs to be
is not in the brave new world of adulthood, but frozen in time in the waning years of the gang's
teenage life. This is part of what makes it difficult for sitcoms to maintain an audience
over time. One of the remaining draws is the original situation in the Situation Comedy.
That 70s show was always meant to be character driven, which usually helps a sitcom overcome
that hurdle. But when those characters aren't allowed to grow, it means they can't drive the
series the way they were intended to. Because moving forward requires characters to grow,
and that 70s show's very premise means these characters have to stay locked in their teenage
years. Five years into the show should mean that Eric and Donna have gone off to college and be
halfway through it, but they're still only just graduating high school. Hyde should be striking
out on his own, but he's still learning lessons on growing up from the foreman's. Jackie should
be beyond her high school crushes, but she still hasn't even graduated yet. And Fez should be more
than this strange foreign exchange student, but none of his arcs ever amount to more than half a
season of antics. What this show does do well, though, is preserve the memory of who these people
should be. Much in the way it's looked back at the 1970s is preserving the memory of what that
decade was in the minds of certain people who experienced it. Maybe that's why this show had
such solid radiance around most of its run, because it was always about holding onto that
nostalgic moment, where you can hang out with your friends from high school and never worry
about them growing up and becoming completely different people. If sitcoms are comfort food,
maybe that's the way that 70s show is best memorialized. One of the hallmarks of that 70s
show was its frequent use of fantasy cutaways. That included parodies of pop culture from the
decade. There were some visual quirks that predated these parodies, though, with season one using
tableaus of famous works of art such as The Last Supper and Night Hawks. But it was the Star Wars
themed episode, A New Hope, that put characters in special costumes and sets, and really got the
parody ball rolling. From there on, there were dozens of other parodies, from I Love Lucy to
Charlie's Angels. I Love Lucy is obviously from the 1950s, not the 70s, but it worked because it
was something these characters were familiar with. And it was a necessity because, as the series
moved along, parodies from the 70s were harder to come by. It would be tough to include every
single parody, so here are my top three. The soap opera parody in season two's Van Stock episode
was an instant classic for me. I am leaving you for Dr. Cloak. Or should I say...
Eric's real father.
He has a job. What do you have, Red Forman? What do you have?
After Red discovers the gang is smoking up, we get a great Reefer Madness parody in the season
three episode titled Reefer Madness. You've been, you missed choir practice. Sorry dollface, but now,
thanks to marijuana, I'm incurably insane.
And the Happy Days parody in Jackie Says Cheese is double fun because it also makes a sly reference
to jumping the shark. Fez, you jumped that shark and you're not even wet!
One of the biggest changes in 1979 was Hyde learning that his father isn't the man he thought
he was. At the start of season seven in the episode, Let's Spend the Night Together,
we finally meet Hyde's father, William Barnett, often turned to WB, played by Tim Reed.
At first, everyone is a bit unsure of how to talk to a black man.
Considering this is a small town in Wisconsin in 1979, it makes some sense
that no one on the show knows how to talk to a black person, as the town is almost certainly
mostly white. But Hyde does take an immediate shine to his new father.
Although there's a little friction at first, the two eventually start forging a relationship,
with Hyde working at one of the record stores his father owns. The introduction of WB introduces a
new dynamic to the mostly white show, though only insofar as we get a lot of jokes like this.
Hyde also meets his half-sister Angie, played by Megalyn Etchikunwoke.
It is interesting to see the introduction of a black family that's not only wealthy,
but so wealthy they're on a higher class level than any of the white characters. The impact of
race on these characters doesn't really come up though aside from the many jokes about how they
are, in fact, black. Though that might reflect how wealth offers some degree of protection from
more common types of bigotry, none of the black characters are a big enough part of the series to
really explore that issue though. What this means for Hyde is that he once again has a new father
figure. His fourth of the series, it's not too difficult to parse that the show is telling us
what a troubled young man needs, is a father giving him some kind of guidance and structure,
a lesson so important it's repeated four times. Five if you count Eric in red. And with Tommy
Chong out of jail, the show brings back another father figure for good measure.
In season seven we see Hyde and Jackie once again back together, only to break up once more. Then
get back together again. And then break up one last time. That last breakup is particularly
galling as it happens with Hyde walking in on Jackie and Kelso, again, mistakenly thinking they
slept together. This moment reinforces how cyclical the narratives on this show can get as
they're trapped in this decade repeating the same mistakes over and over as their show gets
extended long beyond its expiration date because of its need to make a profit for its corporate
overlords. Or at least that's how I suspect Hyde would phrase it. In season eight we find out Hyde
is permanently moved on from Jackie and married a stripper he met in Las Vegas. His new wife Samantha
is played by Jude Tyler. The marriage doesn't last when Hyde finds out his new wife already has
a husband. Heading into 1979, Kelso was making some major strides towards growing up. He had
decided on the career path of becoming a police officer. I'm gonna be a cop!
Not too long after, when Kelso was trying to convince everyone he hooked up with Donna's
friend Brooke, played by Shannon Elizabeth, the truth comes out in an unexpected way.
Although Brooke tells Kelso he doesn't have to be involved with the baby since she doesn't see
him as father material, Kelso eventually decides he wants to be a part of the life of his child
when they're born. Brooke's mother, played by Morgan Bearchild, plans on taking Brooke to Chicago
to raise the child. When the baby is born, she's named Betsy. And eventually Kelso decides he can't
stand to be away from his daughter, and after the police fire him, he moves to Chicago. Kelso's
maturing is difficult to pin down. If having a career wasn't the path to adulthood for him,
but being a father was, it does suggest the value of family over one's career. Though the
idea of Kelso being a cop is more a nightmare scenario than a standard career path. Kelso's
departure was more likely triggered by Ashton Kutcher deciding to leave the series after its
seventh season, although he would make a few guest appearances in season eight to give his
character a proper send-off. And Kelso leaves point place for good. Well, I guess it's time to go,
so, see ya.
After his marriage to Laurie, Fez finally becomes an American citizen. He would go from working at
the DMV to getting a job as a shampoo boy at a salon, and of course being increasingly weird and
creepy. And this is the stuff he talks about when he's not hiding in Donna's club.
Yeah, it's starting to get really weird with Fez. Jackie's life gets complicated after her
father goes to prison, and Jackie is left to fend for herself. This eventually leads to her and Fez
moving in together. For a brief moment, it seemed as though Jackie would have a story arc that wasn't
about her dating life when she starts working in television for local TV star Christine St. George,
played by Mary Tyler Moore. But the job doesn't last, and eventually Jackie's story intersects
with Fez for yet another romance. There are better reasons not to date Fez, mostly because
he has no boundaries in impressing himself upon women. But one of the strange quirks about Fez's
gradual change over the years is that it simply gets put in the bucket of him being odd. It was
his character trait at the beginning of the series, and even though it's elevated dramatically,
to the point where he's creeping around in the closet of his friend, he's still covered by the
odd foreigner label, and it's the second part of that Jackie has trouble with. Or at least she does
for a little while until she gets over it and decides to pursue Fez in earnest, heading toward
the show's finale. In the final year of the show, Kitty's journey through menopause finished,
and she went on another journey into heavy drinking. It's a far cry from the woman who
once struggled with her need to nurture and how it led her to nursing. Post-menopause, most jokes
from Kitty were about her drinking problem. Kitty going from being the mother who brings
her kids cookies and cocoa to the one who spends most of her time mixing drinks for herself would
be an incredibly sad character arc on most other shows, but it's played with some levity here.
It does raise the question of what menopause did to Kitty's psyche,
but that's never really explored on the show. Kitty's menopause and drinking reveal how tragedy
is molded through the candy colors of a sitcom to make things seem brighter, and maybe they're
doing the same thing with the whole decade of the 1970s. That could be why people love this show so
much. It lets you smile through tragedy. It's good for coping. If it was too real, it would be too
heartbreaking. If it wasn't real enough, it wouldn't resonate. The balance is key. In earlier seasons,
I think the show did a better job of that, but even in later ones, it does attempt to strike
some kind of balance. Red manages to find some new ventures when he stops working at Price Mart
and ends up opening a muffler shop. You might wonder where Red got the money for a muffler shop,
but he was creative with that. Red struggles to keep the shop open when a rival store from a big
chain opens up nearby, but luckily for him, they make an offer and Red decides to sell the muffler
shop. So now Red has enough money to retire. What might have been some bad luck hitting Red
once again ends up in his favor since he's the guy who owned the muffler shop and not just someone
who worked there. Although Bob wasn't quite so fortunate in previous seasons, Red does show at
once odds improve if you can position yourself as the business owner than its worker. Although
looking at this in totality, it really seems like business is something of a crop shoot. Maybe
you'll succeed, maybe you won't. It all depends on whether or not big businesses come in and
stomp you out of business or decide to buy you off. Although there is one consistent that remains
true for all business ventures on this show, the only way Red could get into this position is that
he had to sell out his own son's future. It certainly says something that all the major
business successes on this show involve screwing over another person. The Eric and Donna saga
continued with the wedding at the end of season 6 being called off when Eric got scared and ran
away before it could happen, in part because he realized the wedding was keeping Donna from
pursuing her dreams since she chose to stay in point place to be with him instead of going to
college. The pair spend season 7 together unsure of how their life will move forward. Donna decides
to dye her hair. The real reason for Laura Prepon doing this was because she needed to be blonde for
an upcoming movie she was starring in called Carla. Eric spends most of season 7 trying to
figure out what to do with his life before finally settling on becoming a teacher. Since
Red spent all of Eric's college money on the muffler shop, Eric needs to find some other way
of paying for college, and he comes up with an unorthodox solution. There's this program where
you go and teach an impoverished area for a year and then they pay for your college. I signed up.
That's wonderful. So where then? Africa.
Africa, Wisconsin?
Eric will be spending next year teaching in Africa. We don't know where exactly,
and the show never quite goes into detail. We only know it's somewhere in the second biggest
continent on the planet. I need these shots. Africa is very strict about these things,
and they're not strict about anything. I mean, the women walk around with their hooves hanging
on. There's something that needs to be addressed that occurs constantly throughout this series,
particularly in the later seasons. Characters are increasingly ignorant or sometimes outright
disrespectful and racist towards any culture outside of their Midwest bubble. This is excused
by the context of the series, since it's just assumed that people in the 1970s were more likely
to be culturally insensitive. While that may be true, that 70s show in its inception seemed to
want to be a little more enlightened than that. For example, Fez being welcomed into the gang of
friends was a gesture of kindness that was at odds with more ignorant characters such as Red,
and while they often didn't understand his cultural references, as his oddness perhaps
became too central a point of his character, there was a genuine attempt to not just make him a
walking collection of stereotypes. Similarly, when the first season introduced gay characters,
they resisted being tired cliches or harmful stereotypes, and the characters around them are
far more accepting than one might expect from a group of straight teens in the 1970s. But by
season 7, some of that care had faded away, and in the interest of letting us, the audience,
laugh at the racism of the past in the presumed comfort that it doesn't exist in the present.
Something that certainly isn't true, and breeds a degree of complacency towards racial issues.
When the show has its fun making fun of Africa in a broad context, it's nudging the audience with
a knowing wink saying, isn't it great people aren't this ignorant anymore? When the truth is,
a lot of people would struggle to come up with the name of African countries where Eric might
be headed to. On the flip side, the ready acceptance of Hyde's new black family is lovely to see,
even if, in the case of characters like Jackie, it's motivated by greed. So, like many things in
the later seasons of the series, there is a generous mix of good and bad that complicates
characters that, ironically, behave very simply. It's an uneven tone that speaks to the strange
lens sitcoms use to make the word simpler, yet complex enough to be convincing. At least for a
couple of laughs. As Eric prepares to head out to somewhere in Africa, he waves goodbye and is on
his way east, across the Atlantic. The real reason Eric has to leave the show is because
Topher Grace had been looking to go beyond the series and would soon be appearing in movies.
To replace him, the character of Charlie Richardson, played by Brett Harrison, was introduced.
And when Harrison was offered the lead in his own show, The Loop,
he was quickly killed off at the beginning of season 8.
To replace him, the character Randy Pearson, played by Josh Myers, was introduced.
When Eric breaks up with Donna over a letter,
Randy becomes her love interest through some of season 8. The fan reaction to Randy was not great,
and while Randy's presence wasn't the sole reason, ratings for season 8 were on a steady
decline. Without Eric and Kelso, that 70's show just didn't have the magic it once had.
It was then that the network decided to cancel it, with its final two episodes airing together,
Love of My Life and That 70's Finale, ended the decade for good on May 18th, 2006.
In the penultimate episode of the series, characters are quickly moved into place for
the finale, so they can finally escape the 70's. Hyde is given a record store by his father.
Yes, you're the proud owner of the last remaining grooves.
Holy crap, I own this place?
Jackie and Fez get together.
And we find out that Eric is coming back to point place.
Yeah, you're not going anywhere.
The final episode of the series takes place, as you might expect, on New Year's Eve,
1979. But the surprise return we get isn't Eric. Rather, it's Kelso.
There you guys are. Kelso!
Hey man, why don't you get back?
Man, come on, I'm not gonna spend New Year's without my friends.
Come on! It's like, the turn of the century!
As everyone celebrates the coming New Year inside, Donna waits outdoors,
before finding out that Eric was coming back, she had already made a remind to finally go to
college. But with him returning, she can't bring herself to get on that bus out of town
just yet. Not without seeing him first.
And as she reminisces about all the time they spent together, Eric returns.
Happy New Year.
Eric.
Red was right.
I am a dumbass.
Donna.
I'm sorry.
And we end the series with one final circle.
Did you guys hear about that car that runs on water?
It's got a fiberglass air-cooled engine and it runs on water, man!
It's like we never run out of things to talk about down there.
And we count down the end of 1979.
Three, two, one!
Eric going away made his relationship with Donna so much more meaningful.
They both understood what they were missing in a way that a breakup doesn't quite match when
they see each other all the time. And it's that old saying of, if you love something, set it free.
If it returns, it was meant to be.
As the show sends everyone away for the new decade, it seems to be telling the audience that
everyone is gonna be okay. They'll all be fine no matter what might lay ahead.
One touch I really liked was that the ending credits of the series are the same as the first
episode of the series. The gang is singing Tom Rungren's Hello It's Me. At the end of the pilot,
seeing this was an endearing introduction to these teenagers making their way through a decade
that was only vaguely familiar to me. But here at the end of the series, it's nostalgia for the
beginning of a show that was built on nostalgia. That 70 show is about these kids driving down the
street, taking their first step into the big new world. But this show isn't about that journey in
the new world. It's about being in that moment on the cusp of that journey. It's why everyone in the
series is trapped in high school, in their teen years, in the 70s. It's a memory of that moment
that stretches for as long as the series can hold on to it, when you felt like the world was going
to be something new and exciting. While it didn't always have the best grasp of its premise, it did
have a firm hold on that feeling it wanted to evoke. And those final lyrics we hear from Hello
It's Me sound even clearer. It's important to me that you know you are free, because I never want
to make you change for me.
The success of that 70 show spawned a spin-off a few years later. Although a lot of the same
creative talent was responsible for the show behind the scenes, that didn't manifest itself
into another hit. That 80s show debuted on January 23rd, 2002, to a warm response initially,
but quickly sank in the ratings throughout its first season. It was quickly cancelled after 13
episodes. There are a number of reasons cited for why the show failed, leaning a bit too hard on
gags about the decade instead of having characters drive the series. Also, people had less nostalgia
for the 80s than they did the 70s, and the cast didn't quite have the same chemistry as the ones
on that 70s show. Watching it again 20 years later, I personally didn't think it was as bad as I
remembered it being, but it definitely doesn't have the magic of the original series it spun
off of. One interesting bit of trivia about the series is that it stars a young Glenn Howerton
who would go on to play Dennis in It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia. It's rumored his character,
Corey Howard, supposedly was Eric Borman's first cousin, but this never actually comes up in the
series itself. On February 12, 1999, another That 70s Show program aired in England, under the name
Days Like These. This is a nearly identical remake of the American series, except subtly changed to
move the show from Point Place, Wisconsin to Blutton, England. The scripts were kept nearly
identical aside from a few cultural references being changed. Only the British cast didn't quite
perform it with the same energy as the American one. Here's an example of two scenes and how they
played out in each show.
It's not quite the same, is it? British audiences weren't very impressed and the show only aired
at 10 of the 13 episodes produced. In October of 2021, Netflix announced they were producing
a new spin-off of That 70s Show titled That 90s Show. It would bring Kurtwood Smith and Deborah
Joe Rupp in their roles as Red and Kimmy Borman back. The premise of the series was that Eric
and Donna's daughter Leah was spending the summer of 1995 in Point Place. Aside from Smith and Rupp,
the rest of the cast is made up of Callie Heverda, Ashley Afterhide, Miss Coronel, Maxwell A.C.
Donovan, Rainn Doy, and Sam Morales. Other original cast members slated to appear are
Topher Grace, Laura Prepon, Mila Kunis, Ashton Kutcher and Wilmer Valderrama. Although, as of
the time of writing this, it seems they'll only be making guest appearances. Running for 10 episodes
and shot in the multi-camera style of the original, it's already been filmed and is currently waiting
for its premiere date on Netflix. Topher Grace left That 70s Show to star in Spider-Man 3 as
Eddie Brock slash Venom. He would go on to star in a number of other movies as well, including
In Good Company and Win a Date with Tad Hamilton. Most recently, he's been a part of the TV series
Home Economics. Laura Prepon would appear in several TV and film projects following the end
of That 70s Show, most notably as the character Alex Vance in the Netflix series Orange is the
New Black. Most recently, she and her husband celebrated the birth of their second child in
February of 2020. Mila Kunis has been featured in several projects following the end of That 70s
Show, including Black Swan, Bad Moms, and Voice in the Character Meg in nearly 400 episodes of Family
Guy. In 2012, she began dating her former co-star, Ashton Kutcher, and the two would eventually
marry in 2015. They currently have two children together. Ashton Kutcher starred in a number of
movies and TV shows, notably No Strings Attached, What Happened in Vegas, and he replaced Charlie
Sheen on Two and a Half Men. He's most recently starred in The Branch on Netflix, which ran for
four seasons, split into eight parts. In his personal side, in addition to marrying Mila Kunis
and having two children, he's also in the process of treatment for a recent diagnosis of vasculitis.
Wilma Roald Rama went on to appear on several TV shows and movies following the end of That 70s
Show, perhaps most notably as the character Nick Torres on NCIS. He's also currently cast as Don
Diego de la Vega, better known as Zorro in an upcoming Zorro TV series. Kurtwood Smith would
continue his very prolific acting career with appearances on 24, Agent Carter, and doing voice
work on a number of different animated projects. Although it was a role he had before That 70s
Show, I personally remember him most fondly for his role in the Star Trek Voyager two-parter,
Year of Hell. Deborah Jo Rupp has been working both on screen and on stage, including several
productions on Broadway. One of her most recent high-profile roles was on the WandaVision series.
She was also nominated for a Drama Desk Award for her portrayal of Dr. Ruth in the stage
production Becoming Dr. Ruth. Don Stark has been consistently working since the end of That 70s
Show, often with guest spots on a number of different TV programs. He also had several
reoccurring roles on Hit the Floor and Marin. Tanya Roberts had largely stepped away from
the world of acting following her departure from That 70s Show to take care of her husband,
her final roles in 2005 in the TV series Barbershop. Sadly, on January 4, 2021, she passed away due to
complications from an advanced case of sepsis. Lisa Robin Kelly left the world of acting after
That 70s Show, only to briefly reappear in two shorts. She had a series of high-profile arrests
related to substance abuse and domestic violence. She passed away on January 3,
2014, while in rehab, and her cause of death is reported as multiple drug intoxication.
Tommy Chong has been working regularly since the end of That 70s Show, including a reunion with his
longtime partner, Cheech Marin, to revive their classic stoner duo of Cheech and Chong. In 2012,
he announced that he was diagnosed with prostate cancer and was receiving treatment. As of 2019,
he announced that he is currently cancer-free. In 2017, Danny Masterson had three separate
allegations of sexual assault filed against him, and on June 17, 2020, he was charged with three
separate instances of rape. He is currently scheduled to be criminally tried on October 11,
2022. This is the part of the retrospective where I give you all some parting thoughts
to close this off, hopefully fostering some understanding of the good and bad of a classic
series. Maybe one you might want to go watch yourself and come up with your own reading for,
or maybe one you'd just be happy knowing a little more about. I want to try something a little
different, though, with this one. While working on this video, one problem I could not solve was
how to talk about Danny Masterson. Unlike Roseanne Barr or Bill Cosby, Masterson was not the driving
force behind this production. His alleged sexual assault happened in his personal life and seemingly
didn't impact the production of the series. But even so, if you believe the women who have accused
him, and I am inclined to do that, it makes it difficult to watch without that knowledge
constantly floating around in your mind. While researching this video, I also learned one of the
women who accused him, Chrissy Carnell Bixler, appeared in an episode of the series. What seems
to be just a fun little throwaway line in an episode takes on a different tone when you
understand the context behind it. There's also the claims that Masterson is being protected by
the Church of Scientology, which is such a messy and complicated claim that I can't possibly do
it justice in this video. There's lots of other resources, I'll link a few below if you'd like
to learn more about this case. It raises important questions, like do the actions of this one man
wipe out an entire series? That 70s show wouldn't be the same without Hyde, but it wasn't exactly
his show. And the work of all those people being forgotten because of the actions of one man seems
unfair. If you're someone who wants to enjoy the show in spite of knowing what's been alleged
against Masterson, I think that's okay. But for some people, that just isn't possible. They can't
watch this series without that knowledge tainting it and in some way undermining the experience,
and I think that's okay too. People are allowed to have complicated relationships with art,
and you're allowed to take what you want, or skip the process entirely if you don't want to deal
with it at all. Regardless of how you feel about that 70s show, though, I do think what is very
important is that all claims of sexual assault should be taken seriously and thoroughly investigated.
Ultimately, I think that's far more important than whether or not you can sit down and enjoy
a sitcom without feeling guilty about it. That 70s show can decolored nostalgia, holding onto
that naive optimism of your waning teen years. It's a show that helps you remember the good parts
of the past while forgetting the bad. Just remember to keep one foot in reality, and get
ready to face it again when you're ready to leave the circle. The ending to this retrospective is
making me think there is a video that will one day need to be made about how to engage with art
that was, at least in part, created by people who have done harmful and sometimes heinous things
behind the scenes. Speaking of values, though, if you think this video had any sort of value,
do consider becoming a patron or member like the lovely names you see scrolling up the screen.
You'll have early access to videos in the future and a little extra say on what the next sitcom I
cover will be, and there are other little bonuses I've thrown along the way. If you would like to
support this channel in a non-monetary fashion, you can like, comment, subscribe, and do hit the
bell for notifications. Thank you all so much for watching. And for sticking around to the end of
the credits, I want to share one of my favorite jokes from that 70s show. This is Red counseling
Eric after he accidentally ran over Donna's cat, Mr. Bonkers.