Tucker Carlson hosts the most popular cable news show on television his most recent ratings show
He averaged 3.2 million viewers a night on Fox News with his Tucker Carlson tonight program
It debuted on November 14th 2016 originally at 7 p.m
But following the cancellation of the O'Reilly Factor Tucker inherited the 8 p.m. Time slot in 2017
The show grew in popularity topping out at four point three three million viewers in the second quarter of 2020 the most viewers ever
For a cable news program in the United States the show proves so popular that Fox News expanded its relationship with Tucker Carlson in the spring
Of 2021 by giving him a morning show Tucker Carlson today that errors three times a week and Tucker Carlson originals
Which airs once a month both of these appearing on the Fox Nation streaming platform
If you're not familiar with who Tucker Carlson is a very brief recap is that he lived a middle-class life as a child
Until his father married into the wealthy Swanson family whose fortune come from those frozen TV dinners
His privileged life led him to a career in journalism where he wrote for a few conservative outlets in
2000 he worked at CNN on a show called crossfire
This show ended when he was embarrassed by John Stewart on camera and Carlson did not renew his CNN contract
He then spent some time at PBS had a show on MSNBC for a few years before finally finding a home at Fox News in
2009 where he was eventually given his own show in 2017 if you want more details about the history of Tucker Carlson
I highly recommend this recap of his life from some more news with all this Tucker Carlson content on offer
I decided to consume a whole week's worth of his stuff to get an idea of what it's like to be in the Tucker Carlson
Audience and what it feels like to get the full effect of his work. This is for the week of October 18th
2021 now
The first part of every episode of Tucker Carlson tonight is the feature story typically rating from 15 to 20 minutes
It makes a path of each episode and is usually the part that has everyone buzzing the next day
These feature stories are largely centered around a monologue where Carlson builds his case and they're capped off with a brief interview
The October 18th edition of the show offers a great example
It began with the recent passing of former United States Secretary of State Colin Powell
Unlike other people in Washington Colin Powell got where he was on merit and that was inspiring to watch and eventually it turned
Into a rant about how Americans are living in a medical apartheid state
We have a division medical apartheid
We have rules but some people have exempted themselves from the rules and they're not ashamed of it
Here's how he made the jump the crucial step in drawing a connection between
Powell's death and this authoritarian nightmare is that Powell died of complications related to COVID-19
Even though he had been vaccinated once this connection is made two minutes into this 14-minute segment. It stops being about Powell entirely
Like almost everyone his age Colin Powell was fully vaccinated against COVID and yet according to his family and doctors
Colin Powell died of COVID. Of course that fact does not make his death any less sad
Nor is it unusual many thousands of vaccinated Americans have died of COVID
Former CDC director Robert Redfield announced just today that about 40% of all recent COVID deaths in the state of Maryland
For example are among those who have had both shots
This is a deeply deceptive stat looking at Maryland alone the eighth most vaccinated state with at the time of writing
65.8% of its population being fully vaccinated
This would mean that breakthrough cases that is cases of vaccinated people suffering from COVID would be more common because such a large
percentage of the state is fully vaccinated
The State Department of Health agrees writing in a statement as the number of our residents who are vaccinated
Continues to increase we expect to see an increase in the proportion of COVID related deaths occurring in vaccinated individuals
Many of these deaths are linked to comorbidities that make patients more vulnerable
Even on its face though if most people are fully vaccinated and the majority of deaths are still attributed to the unvaccinated
It seems like getting a vaccine is a good idea
A wider view of the numbers available from the CDC reveals that COVID deaths are dramatically more common among the unvaccinated
With the unvaccinated being 11 times more likely to die of COVID than the vaccinated
Powell's death is an anecdote a high profile case of something that isn't terribly common
It's being used to push a narrative about skepticism towards the vaccine
It's all a pretense to get to the real message of the segment. What tells you you've been lied to
Vaccines may be highly useful for some people but across a population they do not solve COVID
The language here is crucial. What does solve COVID even mean that a vaccine will completely eliminate it?
Vaccines rarely eradicate illnesses with the only transmissible one among humans that has been wiped out so far being smallpox
The vague usage of solve and how it will never be achieved is how carlson can apply that the vaccine really isn't worth getting
At least for most people without outright denying it has any significant effect at all his earlier statement implies that it's a very narrow effect
Vaccines may be highly useful for some people
The covet vaccine has been demonstrated to dramatically reduce one's chance of death
But the number of deaths aren't the only talking point carlson uses
Carlson also says the vaccine doesn't effectively slow the spread of covet. This also isn't true
Craig spencer an emergency medicine physician and director of global health and emergency medicine at new york
Presbyterian columbia university medical center writing for the atlantic said
Despread the coronavirus you have to have the coronavirus and vaccinated people are far less likely to have the corona virus
period
Even in instances of breakthrough cases where a vaccinated person is infected with the delta variant of covet
Preliminary data shows that transmission is reduced by 63 percent
Albeit for a period of a few months for the alpha variant of covet transmission is even more greatly reduced by a vaccine
Increasing to 73 percent a lot of this data is still being peer reviewed
But so far the majority of the science seems to be saying the exact opposite of what tucker carlson is asserting
But he doesn't say any of it in intent to accurately discuss the science of the day
It's all the guys to get to what he really wants to talk about president biden is demanding obedience and people are fearfully obeying him
They're afraid of you
They can't explain why they're afraid of you the president told them that you are dangerous and so they're afraid
The question is over time. What does that do to your most cherished relationships to your friendship to your family relationships?
What does it do to the country?
The biden administration is apparently using the pandemic to destroy american families or as tucker would put it
America has once again become what it was when colin powell got his commission in the army
America has become segregated not between black and white but between vaccinated and unvaccinated
This is how tucker creates the illusion of a coherent narrative
Colin powell being alive during segregation is purely incidental and segregation itself was a deliberate attempt to restrict black people from positions of
Powered influence within american society because of the color of their skin
Which is hardly the same as not letting someone who is far more likely to carry an infectious disease eat at an applebee's
But what makes tucker carlson particularly effective is that he isn't just spreading partisan talking points
His monologues also include a healthy dose of conspiracy theories
This is a pandemic of the chinese government born in a lab in wuhan and brought here either accidentally or not
That's the fact of it
This is also not a fact
The current state of the debate according to an article in the new yorker is that there is no conclusive evidence to support that claim
And most scientists who study viruses are inclined to say it was a naturally occurring virus
The most plausible version of this theory is that it was being studied at this lab and was accidentally leaked because of a lack of safety precautions
Not that it was created by the chinese government
The rent continues like this for nearly 10 minutes
It's a fire hose of misinformation and by 10 minutes in it's spiraling into madness as a few seconds of video of joe biden
Not wearing a mask at a restaurant is used as evidence of him declaring himself
Some kind of grand ruler as only servants wear masks, but he didn't wear a mask
Why?
Because masks are for servants and he's the president. He's not a servant
The official explanation here is that biden was eating at a restaurant and was in the process of putting his mask back on
Having taken it off to eat his food
Something that I am inclined to believe since you can clearly see him molding the mask as he walks
The video was widely circulated on right-wing media as biden flaunting the rules
But tucker carlson takes it even further saying biden meant to be filmed to send a message to americans
A message that ironically never would have been heard had not right-wing media figures like himself obsessed over it
This clip itself is not a story
But it does offer a wonderful example of how right-wing media takes innocuous footage to concoct a narrative biden being slow to put
His mask on is now him telling america that he is their god king
And wasn't this whole segment about colin pal's death?
And now we're talking about how joe biden being filmed in a restaurant not wearing a mask for a few seconds
Means he's crowning himself the emperor of america
It was as if this whole monologue was written independent of pal's death
And then that part was inserted later to make the narrative seem newsworthy
And one last detail about colin powell carston did eventually share with us also seemed important
So being the show we told you about colin powell
We left out that colin powell was suffering from a number of different health problems
But of course, that's the point the point of vaccinating the vulnerable is so
People with other underlying health problems won't die of covet
But unfortunately that didn't work in the case of general powell and it didn't work for many thousands of other americans
And of course, that's the point we're making in the first place
Colum pal was suffering from multiple myeloma which compromised his immune system making the vaccine less effective
An important detail if you're trying to claim that the vaccine itself is ineffective a detail that completely undermines his entire rant
Which is why it happens more than 25 minutes after the segment is over just as the show is going off the air
Because this rant was a con and tucker carlson knows it
But that monologue was believe it or not the strongest and most convincing one I saw that week
I want to talk about two other ones that show us how things can get really crazy on this show
On october 20th tucker carlson started a show with a segment that had an impressive number of jumps
We started with a statement about how america was changed by the black lives matter movement of 2020
This really was the pivot point
It was the height of the blm riots early last summer
Which turns into a story of how the media lies to people msnbc's explicit editorial policy
To lie about what you were watching live to characterize violent riots as peaceful protests
And then this moves to a discussion about looting the country your ancestors built is on fire
But shut up because your ancestors also burned it down
Which pivots to an article about supply chain issues in the u.s
The washington post just ran this headline and we're quoting
Don't rant about short staff stores and supply chain woes
And apparently america is now falling apart. Don't complain
As your life becomes worse and as your country degrades this leads to a point about store closures
You notice the wall greens is for example closed and so is the cvs because everything in there has been stolen
By thieves who have now been redefined as civil rights protesters. Stop complaining karen
And suddenly we're talking about cities being overrun with drug addicts. Oh, wait a second
They're junkies living intense right across from your kid's school
Well that they've always been there too. They were there when you were a kid
You just never noticed just readjust your expectations settle down karen and their undocumented immigrant rapist on trains
Last week several people on train they got on the train and then they got to watch as a man raped a woman
On the train for minutes and biden's border policy is destroying america
You want more of this? We may be getting it today joe biden's nominee to lead the border patrol a guy called chris magnus
Set for his confirmation hearings
Now it turns out that magnus if anything is to the left of biden
Even to the left of barack obama on immigration matters
Did you follow all that black lives matter is somehow connected to joe biden destroying america with immigrants?
Or the impression carlson's audience more likely got that america is being destroyed and it's biden's fault
The house and wise aren't important. The segment isn't designed to be coherent
It's designed to create a vague feeling of fear about the state of america and to direct that fear and possibly anger towards joe biden
The segment itself is of course filled with misinformation
Take the op-ed from the washington post which tucker claims is an attack on americans telling them to lower their expectations
As if they need to be ready for some kind of socialist hellscape
Lower your expectations. What did you expect in america?
Come on
Bread lines we've always had bread lines
It's sort of charmingly retro these bread lines if we read beyond the headline what the article by micheline manard
Actually says is
Rather than living constantly on the verge of throwing a fit and risking taking it out on overwhelmed servers
Struggling shop owners or late arriving delivery people. We do ourselves a favor by consciously lowering expectations
Rather than being an attack on americans
It's a simple plea for americans not to take their frustrations out on workers who have no control over supply chain issues
Carlson also claims that wall green stores in san francisco are closing because of organized shoplifting. San francisco has
Very few wallgreens or cvs or stores like that left because they've all been looted
by civil rights protesters
This is contradicted by numbers from the police which do not support this wave of shoplifting at wallgreens a narrative codman on social media
Based on a handful of cell phone videos wallgreens has not only refused to share internal data related to shoplifting with reporters in san francisco
Their parent company wallgreens boots alliance was forecasting between 150 and 400 store closures by 2024
since 2016 wallgreens has closed 22 stores in san francisco and those numbers include the recent story tuckers responding to
In which wallgreens had announced it was closing five stores
Now san francisco has very few wallgreens or cvs or stores like that left because they've all been looted
It still has 53 stores operating in san francisco a far cry from what tucker claims
Also not mentioned in this segment is that in new york city wallgreens is shutting down 16 stores
I suspect it might have made it into the segment had they found cell phone footage of a black person stealing something though
Which by the way is used to justify the earlier mention of black lives matter, which was about making shoplifting legal according to tucker carlson
It's also interesting to see how tucker carlson who many describe as a populace parroting the talking points of a corporation like wallgreens
Which happily spreads the organized shoplifting talking point to disguise the fact that it had been planning to close stores
regardless of this supposed wave of shoplifting
Perhaps tucker is happily towing this corporate line because it at least lets him demonize black communities
It's the jumps that really make this segment more than misinformation though
The narrative through line of america's decay is barely held together as tucker jumps from one sensationalized story to another
And he uses folksy little turns of phrase or rolls out the carrot insult to engage his audience emotionally
This isn't designed to get people thinking about the news of the day. It's designed to rally their emotions against the left
Tucker carlson's opening stories are so narrative focused that sometimes he doesn't even need to misrepresent actual news stories
In some cases he just presents something made up entirely out of nothing
That is so obviously true in the october 21st show
This segment opens with some truly shocking footage released by the biden administration
Happy birthday to you, happy birthday to you, happy birthday to my president, happy birthday to you
Before moving on I want everyone to take a moment and think about what this video says
And you don't need any deep analysis here
Just think about the events you saw unfold and what they were about really ask yourself. Does anything seem amiss here?
Does this footage reveal some hidden truth?
Okay, here's what tucker thought when he watched that video
It's like a room full of aliens have gathered to act out this concept. They've just heard about called happiness
The head alien is a super naturally strange being called
Kamala harris who for reasons no one ever explains walks into a room in the most secure building in the world
With a piece of elasti-sized fabric over her face like that's totally normal just another masked birthday celebration
harris suddenly yells surprise at her own surprise birthday party like she's hosting the event for one of her multiple personalities
What the hell is going on here?
I can answer that question harris acted awkwardly during a surprise birthday party and everyone is wearing masks because of covet
But tucker has to pretend this is some bizarre
unthinkable scenario where people are acting in strange and confusing ways ways that reveal a deep mental rot at the core of the
biden white house
He goes on for several minutes about these videos making a number of strange points like that. No one says gorgeous anymore
She goes on to use the word gorgeous a word that no actual human being has used since 1977
I am completely willing to believe no one calls tucker gorgeous, but that doesn't mean no one says it. First of all is the answer. Yes
Ready to work. I am ready to do this with you for you. I I just i'm just deeply honored and i'm very excited
Whoa
Indeed nearly six minutes in and all tucker is talking about are these social media posts
He's calling them staged and even if they are
So what their pieces of pr are designed to make president biden and vice president harris seem more human and relatable much like your grandpa
Joe biden also doesn't know how to turn off a speakerphone
If these moments are staged the fact that none of these people are actors should explain the awkward delivery
But to tucker carlson, there's something far more sinister more sinister than north korean military propaganda
But what's the message of the joe and kamala videos?
All your nightmares are real the people in charge are even worse than you thought they were
Kamala may have seemed kind of fake to you joe may have looked a little out of it
But actually the white house is now telling us you don't know the half of it
According to tucker the white house is trying to tell everyone that these people are losing their mind or robots
These are presented as basic readings of these videos and not right-wing spin and that's what makes it so effective
The phrasing demands the audience accept the basic premise just to get to the conspiracy theory
You must believe joe biden is senile before getting to the idea that this is a deliberate move by the white house to rub it
in everyone's faces
Why they would do this is never really explored the conspiracy theory is a bonus
Because the main point here is to reinforce the idea that joe biden is senile and that kamala harris is some kind of robot
This is one third of the way into this night's commentary and have you spotted anything newsworthy so far?
All we've seen is tucker carlson opine about some harmless social media pr posts, but it does get even more intense
In december of last year kamala harris who grew up in canada a foreign country
I appreciate the subtle menace tucker carlson has when he describes canada as a foreign country
We usually don't get much credit for how scary we are tucker is really shocked at how brazen a lie harris told was though
Swore that she witnessed quote multiple generations of her family celebrating kwanza an american holiday
That was invented in long beach california after kamala harris was born. Not one word is true, but not one word is believable
Again, it was a prepared statement. It was carefully considered. They didn't even bother to look at a calendar
Luckily for us. I did look at a calendar kamala harris was born in 1964 in california
The american celebration of kwanza was first held in
1966 so the idea of kamala harris celebrating this with her family including parents and grandparents as a child seems pretty reasonable
This is likely what she meant when she said celebrating across generations
As for the canada part harris was born in california and moved to montreal when she was 12
She moved back to the us at 18 to attend howard university in washington d.c
So is it really hard to imagine that between the ages of 2 and 12 she might have celebrated kwanza with her parents and grandparents
Also kwanza may have started in the u.s
But it's celebrated in canada too and even if it wasn't there are no canadian laws preventing american families
From celebrating kwanza in montreal the segment is nearly 10 minutes through and it's completely filled with stuff like this
Tucker carlson reacting to dopey videos released by the white house
This is the news he thinks is worth commenting on and to make it seem worthwhile
He needs to make it sound as dramatic and scary as possible. It goes as far as to compare it to a cult
It's kind of nuts when you think about it
These people literally have no idea how absurd they look and how could they they live in a tiny airless cult
Wherever one pretends that joe biden is fully competent. Kamala harris is a civil rights hero
It's jones town and he brings a guest on to tell us that these videos are somehow related to communism
It's because every part of the system is so corrupt now and rotted with this communist filth
And that would you think of everyone here as sociopaths these people are not capable of that kind of shame
It's not in their nature. They are completely lost. They're sociopaths all of them
This is literally all this segment is I suspect the jesse keller interview only went on as long as it did over three minutes
Because of how little substance was actually present
I'm genuinely impressed that tucker carlson took something as flat and sparse of content such as pr videos on white house social media
And turned it into a narrative about some kind of biden cult slash obama's third term
This is obama's third term and these people are picked because they're compliant and hollow
But this segment more than all the others demonstrates what this show does it takes news stories or sometimes things that are barely news
Events lies about them and then builds these fantastic narratives of cults and oppression to oppose the biden administration
Isn't to have a political disagreement. It's to be standing against the monstrous sociopaths who want to destroy america
It catastrophizes political reality to such an extreme that the opposition can only be understood as the most dire of threats
And then tucker will in the same breath complain about how the other side is trying to divide us
Which is rich coming from someone who uses a video about flowers being delivered to push a narrative about a cult destroying america
While the opening segment is tucker carlson's show at its purest
The show does go on for another 20 to 25 minutes after it's over
These are the quick hits where five or six different stories are crammed into tiny segments that leave the audience less informed and more afraid
Here's a quick example of a story from the october 18th episode in recent weeks
Thousands of illegal aliens have been flown from the texas border into westchester county airport in new york on charter jets
Presented as breaking news is the story of children being flown from the southern us border to new york
He interviews conservative new york post columnist miranda divine for details by the government
They were all unaccompanied children
But several of them did look to us to be males in their 20s late teens
Some of the language here should raise some alarm according to the government the people being brought to new york are all children
But according to divine some of them looked older the photos used on tv make it tough to tell
But if you look at the new york post article
There are much clearer photos of these people who are obviously children as they're significantly shorter than the man who is escorting them
Also when divine claims that these flights are coming in the dead of night that isn't what we're seeing in these photos
According to the article these photos were of flights that arrived at 9 52 pm and 10 49 pm
There is a record of two flights landing at 2 13 a.m
And 4 29 a.m on august 20th, but these are the only examples offered in the article that might be considered
The dead of night
It then describes that these children are being sent to family members and those without family members are going to an organization called
Mercy first which works with the u.s office of refugee resettlement to find kids who have been granted refugee status safe homes
These brief few minutes are used to illustrate that the biden administration is somehow breaking the law
and that it needs to offer greater transparency on where refugee children are being settled because
Well, they never really say why tucker does mention that some kind of federal law is being violated
But he doesn't say which one and the only evidence of something nefarious going on
Is that some of these flights might be past the bedtimes of these children?
They can't come out and say what they want their audience to think because that wouldn't be as safe as the dog whistle
They're using instead. This is a segment designed to portray refugee children as a danger to america
Tucker Carlson tonight crams in five to six of these segments every night in its second half
Much like the opening segment the rife with conspiracy theories such as vaccines for military personnel being used to get christians out of the military
So by forcing this
You get to find out who sincerely believes in god
And then you know, you know their names at that point and then you can expel them using the pretext of the covid vaccine
The ufo is going after american nukes
UFOs interacted with nuclear weapons platforms
And either rendered them inoperable or took them offline
The content matters less than the general feeling these segments create to distrust any mainstream narrative and to believe any story tucker
Is telling you no matter how outlandish
All these different topics
Particularly the ones that are highlighted in the second half of the show are a means to maintain talking points
That aren't necessarily the hot topic of the moment such as critical race theory or affirmative consent on college campuses
The vague general threats of non-white people and feminism is kept alive in the minds of viewers whenever stories like these are referenced
It also gives them the appearance of legitimacy as if these are ongoing issues that need to be monitored rather than
Completely fabricated stories that are simply maintained by a dedicated right-wing media to ensure that the audience doesn't forget that
Even though they're not the topic at the moment sometime in the future. This is a group. We might need to scapegoat again
So while the big monologues get a lot of the attention including in this video
These smaller segments really add up to something truly nefarious the impression that these right-wing narratives are part of a persistent
World view one that can be maintained in the minds of viewers through constant attention not through big tentpole stories
These segments typically include short interviews often not running for more than two or three minutes
They make a perfect backdrop for how tucker carlson presents stories on his show
Typically, there are four reasons why a news program might include an interview
The first is to provide additional information to a story in his october 21st episode
Tucker carlson had a short four-minute segment on a memo issued by attorney general mary garland directing the fbi
To investigate the increasing number of violent threats towards school board members over covid related safety requirements fears over critical race theory
And other culture war narratives popularized on right-wing media
These threats are very real as there are several videos that can be found of school board meetings being disrupted by crowds of angry parents
Who use incendiary language including death threats have you yourself received death threats?
I have
It's terrifying
It has an effect on you that you can't really put into words
when someone describes
the way they want to
Come into your home
And end your life. Here's another example of parents upset that their kids might be expected to wear masks at school
The threats have gotten so bad that the national school boards association has requested help specifically from the fbi
But this isn't the part of the story tucker carlson shares on his show according to carlson
The controversy here is that garland did not disclose that his son-in-law runs a company called panorama education
Which has in a various intent panorama makes a ton of money
Pushing racist propaganda the kind that parents are complaining about and how does panorama education do that?
By creating surveys for children that measure their school experience
He brings on azeron omani to provide the evidence
They are asking children from hawaii to mean
What what about their sexuality their gender and they're also asking these questions of their parents
Not being someone who trusts anybody who wears a shirt that says they aren't a domestic terrorist
Which is exactly what a domestic terrorist not wanting to be discovered would do
I decided to look into these surveys myself which are helpfully posted on panorama education's website
Although there are multiple surveys. I couldn't find a single one asking kids about their sexuality
There was one question about gender identity though. It dared to ask a child
What is your gender?
But other than that there wasn't anything else on sex and gender that I could see there were definitely questions about race and culture though
specifically on pages 28 and 29 out of 56 that asks kids in grades 6 through 12 questions such as
How often do teachers encourage you to learn about people from different races ethnicities or cultures?
And another one is how fairly do adults at your school treat people from different races ethnicities or cultures?
Not exactly what I would call nefarious and perfectly fitting in a survey that also asks kids
How much support do the adults at your school give you?
And how confident are you that you can complete all the work that is assigned in your subject class?
Merely asking a question about race is
According to nomani indoctrinating kids with critical race theory
These types of interviews that add additional information to a story are surprisingly rare though
Other interviews you might see on carlson's show are ones that add emotional context such as when a news event impacts a particular group
Interviewing someone from that group puts a human face on the issue providing emotional context
We'll have some better examples of that later on but the closest version of this I saw on tucker carlson tonight
Was when the show discussed the recent dave chappelle netflix special and the backlash over his comments about the trans community
Tucker carlson interviewed seth dylan of the babylon b apparently for his response as a comedian
Another type of interview you might see on tucker carlson's show is someone with an opposing viewpoint
Something that has happened in the past but did not happen on the week
I watched and for what I can gather doesn't happen all that often on the show in general
Particularly after carlson made the mistake of inviting on dutch historian rutger bregman
You might not like it
But you're a millionaire funded by billionaires, and that's the reason why you're not talking about these issues
Yeah, only now come on you jumped a bandwagon you're all like oh i'm against a globalist the lead blah blah blah
It's not very convincing to be honest
Honestly if I ever get the chance to be speaking to someone like tucker carlson
I wanted to go down exactly like that the type of interview that is by far
The most common on tucker carlson tonight is the supposed expert who comes on to affirm everything tucker carlson has been saying
Given it the illusion of authority
Examples of this are well more than I can fit in this video
Here's one I enjoyed though in the october 18th episode tucker had a brief segment about an interview with christopher steel
Whose dossier included a number of accusations toward president trump?
Perhaps most notably the one where there's apparently a tape in vladimir putin's possession of women who trump hired to pee on a bed
That obama had slept in during his trip to russia
This segment itself is a rehashed complaint about how the investigation into those supposed russian connections unfairly hamstrung the trump administration's foreign policy
And to discuss this carlson brings on cash patel and devon nunez
Patel and nunez add very little of substance in their interview
They vaguely allude to their own personal issues
But the interview lasts less than three minutes giving them in only moments to answer three questions between the two of them
Their primary purpose seems to be to agree with tucker about everything and then deliver zingers like this one
This guy is no hero. He is no james bond
He's inspector gadget on pseudofed and now he's crying for the world to love him
Maybe he can get a job with the babylon b these interviews are by far the most common ones
I saw during the week
I watched this show figures who show up not along with everything tucker carlson said and then make a quick exit
Used to cap off a segment as if it now has an authoritative stamp of approval
That's what tucker crossing gets from these brief interviews
But I imagine the guests themselves get to expose themselves to tucker's massive audience and be presented as a friendly face
They can trust because they agree with the same nonsense tucker carlson spreads on his show
These are the interviews tucker carlson only conducts on his tucker carlson tonight program
There are other sources for people to get their tucker fix
And in the case of tucker carlson today
It's a long-form interview show that airs on the fox nation streaming service
While short segments of these interviews find their way onto tucker carlson tonight the full 50 plus minute interviews are exclusive to fox nation
It's here where tucker carlson really digs into the thoughts and opinions of his guests
Not like the snippets we see on his fox news show and as you might have guessed tucker's guests also enjoyed agreeing with him
To be fair
These interviews are absolutely in the first category of the ones I outlined above
As these new guests provide lots of new information relative to the narrative being offered though
Ultimately these discussions support the same kind of narrative tucker carlson pushes on his main show
conservative conspiracy theories
Before diving in I should note that while this show typically airs three times a week mondays wednesdays and fridays
Tucker carlson took october 22nd off
So I only have two episodes to work with though for the sake of my own sanity
That was an hour of tucker carlson. I was spared
The first of the two interviews was with elbridge colby a former deputy assistant secretary of defense for strategy and force development
At the department of defense during the trump administration
He's a peculiar guest at least for a friendly interview considering how much of tucker carlson's branding is that he stands up to the elites
And insider types of washington when the interview starts tucker tries to establish that colby definitely isn't one of those people
If you scour the foreign policy establishment in washington, everyone's either implicated in the disasters
We're watching now or there's some kind of crazed neocon ideologue who you would not ask to babysit your children
Because they're that untrustworthy
So there are very few people whose opinion matters from our perspective on this topic and elbridge colby is one of them
Colby having some sense of the show he's on tries to do the same by claiming to have been against the war in iraq
But yeah, then i've been working in kind of the national security area for the last 20 years. I entered
Dc as a very junior guy right around the time of the iraq, you know fever before the war
And i'd say that kind of set me in one direction because I was not not a not a fan
I mean my opinion didn't matter at all at that time
A quick look at colby's bio reveal that he was part of the coalition provisional authority in iraq in 2003
Which was set up by the bush administration to help reshape the country and was also plagued by insider groans from washington
Something extensively written about in the 2006 book imperial life in the emerald city inside iraq's green zone by rajiv chandra
Sakaran being part of the authority that was reshaping iraq in 2003 is a curious place to be for someone who didn't support the war
After his time in iraq colby continued to work in government for a number of years and before joining the trump administration
Was part of the center for a new american security a think tank that is partially funded by a number of defense contractors
And of course the u.s
Government he's on tucker carlson's show to talk about the looming threat of china and how a military response might be the only option
In short colby seems like one of the washington insiders that tucker claims to have some deep resentment for but as we learn in this interview
Carlson and colby are friends and colby has a book to sell and those things are more important than the facade of tucker's anti-imperialism
Much of this interview is colby firing off talking points about the danger of china
And he doesn't make a terribly compelling case for his position tucker carlson is very weird in this interview
Although the fear mongering about china is on brand his questioning constantly reverts to the talking points
He usually has on his show while colby is more willing to give the typical answers
You'd see from a washington insider military hawk carlson keeps dredging up some of the bogus culture war narratives in response
greatest
adversary
was russia
Under vladimir putin and then biden is elected
And the new secretary of defense tells us that the single greatest adversaries in fact within our borders and it's white men
the u.s military seems demoralized
And its leadership seems completely distracted by irrelevant concerns like white rage and transgenderism
That's the outsider's perspective colby deflects a lot of these questions and comments and his tactic seems to be to constantly complement tucker and his show
And and I applaud your your focus on this issue and any institution that is above account accountability will fail
I mean, I think that's a point that you always stress and I completely agree with it. All the world
It's not a terribly interesting interview though
I was impressed that even in this dry discussion about american foreign policy tucker carlson still made time to insert some conspiracy theories
The japanese bomb for harbor. They did corregator the baton death march
They bended nurses in hong kong, etc, etc. And then we got really really angry. Well, that's where roosevelt allowed it, right?
He clearly did but whatever okay
I should stress that there is no evidence whatsoever that this is true
I've linked an article from npr on the subject below if you want to read more about it
And he cranks up some real fear on china by asking what one of their nukes would do to an american city modern nuclear weapons
Are more powerful
What kind of effect would a modern nuclear bomb have on an american population center?
Tucker carlson claims to be an anti-interventionist
And someone opposed to the american tendency to push itself into conflicts around the world in an effort to expand or maintain its hegemonic influence
But in this interview, he is reinforcing the very common talking point something you see in both parties about china being an existential threat
And discussing the need for a potential military response
It speaks to the game tucker carlson is playing claiming to be a populace speaking for americans
Specifically conservative ones who have been ignored by the republican establishment and then turning around and inviting insiders like colby on to have
A friendly chat about the american military possibly being in an open conflict with china
He does the same thing on tucker carlson tonight when in the week
I watched he had on politicians including senator josh holly and governor ron desantis for friendly conversations
Tucker carlson can pretend to be firmly against the neo-cons who sent the us into iraq
But the figureheads from back then are gone and carlson is happy to play nice with their ideological successors
While the branding of populism may be popular he'll happily cozy up to politicians
He can convince his audience represent their interests even when they clearly serve a wealthier class. It sure is helpful branding though
The other episode of tucker carlson today. I watched was far more on brand on october 20th
Tucker welcomed professor dorian abbott to talk about how he had recently been canceled by the woke mob
There is some backstory here in 2020 professor abbott a geophysicist at the university of chicago
Had some complaints about how diversity equity and inclusion groups were impacting the selection process for graduate student candidates and faculty hires
Like all reasonable academics
He voiced his concern via a youtube video since taken down which was responded to by a letter signed by over
100 students faculty and alumni calling for the university to allow students to withdraw from his classes without penalty
Ultimately, the university president sided with abbott and he faced no administrative disciplinary measures
Of course, this was not why abbott was brought on to tucker carlson's show
Most recently abbott co-wrote an article for newsweek with stanford associate professor evan marinovich once again
voicing concern about the impact of diversity equity and inclusion proposing that someone's identity
Should have no impact for post-secondary admissions
One interesting aspect of this article is that abbott briefly mentions that his proposal would also eliminate legacy admissions as well
Which is the practice of a school typically seen in elite ivy league schools
Giving students preference if they had a family member who attended the institution
While it's lovely to see this be mentioned
It seems strange that abbott only mentions it in passing and it comes off as a defense against people calling him racist
If anything legacy admissions seem far more unfair as it doesn't just help individuals from racial backgrounds that typically have privilege
But it goes that extra step of ensuring that someone from an already wealthy family gets special consideration for a spot at some of the best
Schools in the world so it discriminates based on class as well
Had abbott come out hard against legacy admissions rather than diversity admissions
We might be viewing him entirely different, but it was diversity that was his main target
In this article abbott makes no mention of the research that demonstrates how his field of geophysics is hostile towards faculty
That aren't white men such as himself and that there are active biases against women and non-white racial groups
And that these diversity programs are designed to undercut that bias by breaking down the systems that prevent inclusion
He also seems unaware that greater diversity within groups creates more novel hypotheses and actually expand research potential not limit it
Professor abbott seems to be under the impression that science faculties are untouched by these biases and exist in realms of pure reason
Where facts and evidence are all that matter and a person's identity couldn't possibly impact their work
He seems unaware of the academic research that undermined this idea
Which is strange because those studies that you saw flash on screen as I was talking about those topics
Were all included in the letter complaining about him in 2020
It's almost as if he either didn't read them or simply has no interest in acknowledging them
That aside what probably drew the most attention in this article is this passage towards the end 90 years ago
Germany had the best universities in the world then an ideological regime obsessed with race came to power and drove many of the best
Scholars out cutting the faculties and leading to sustained decay that german universities never fully recovered from
We should view this as a warning of the consequences of viewing group membership as more important than merit and correct our course
Before it is too late
If professor abbott is interested in starting a conversation about university admissions
I'm not sure comparing diversity equity and inclusion programs to the nazis is a helpful talking point
Also, there's something truly grotesque about comparing an effort to help marginalized peoples have better access to higher education
With the effort from nazis to keep those groups out of universities
It seems more like the exact opposite of what's going on anyone can make grossly reductive points like this
I could say the allies in world war ii were just like the nazis because when they were at war both militaries killed soldiers on
The opposite side, but that would be a silly comparison that removes all nuance from the discussion
But maybe tucker carlson will bring this up in the interview
Except no, definitely not we're gonna get stuff like this instead. I don't think i've ever seen a college professor
Lay out in such clear and I will say gentle
Terms, um as you did what's at stake?
I'm not sure a nazi comparison is all that gentle the rest of the interview goes the way you might expect with tucker praising abbott
At every turn and some questionable responses being treated as a matter of fact, for example, professor abbott complains about certain ideologies
I was uncomfortable with
With ideologies that discourage discourse because when you can't speak with the other side
The only recourse is violence. Yes, and I saw that playing out in the summer of 2020
This is a weird comment
Obviously the summer of 2020 refers to the black lives matter demonstrations and in other contexts
It could be generously understood as violence in response to an indifferent state
That doesn't care about the impact of harsh policing on black communities and won't have that difficult conversation
But in the context of this interview with tucker carlson
It is more like a condemnation of black lives matter for not wanting to talk about their problems instead of resorting to violence
Putting aside the fact that the violence in blm protest has been grossly overstated by the media
The only way someone can assume black people don't want to talk about the violence inflicted upon them by the state is to deliberately ignore that conversation
Which has been happening for a very long time and has been conveniently ignored by people such as professor abbott
It's a great example of how someone like professor abbott was completely ignorant of a problem until it boiled over into a mass movement
And even now his response is that we need to think even less about the negative impact of the social construct of race
This is not the mindset of someone ready for a conversation
Except when it's with tucker carlson in a softball interview
The interview muddles along and I feel like I could spend a whole hour on how so many of these answers are wrapped up
In gentle language but reveal a deep ignorance of the many issues at play
But I want to once again mention how conspiracy theories rear their ugly head
Here's professor abbott talking about who's really behind all this diversity stuff. But the problem is that there's a small group
That's extremely committed
You could call them the woke activist or the social justice
Justice activist and they're willing to spend all their time on this stuff and they sort of steamroll
And there's some kind of twitter mob that organize in this as well
There's there's almost like a playbook
To try to take someone down who disagrees with the ideology
so the first thing that happens is people go on twitter
And they organize and they write lots of messages about the person
And the messages say mean things so they'll say this is racist bigoted white supremacists like very
Scary sounding things the idea that some people have genuine criticisms of him and are simply responding to his words doesn't seem to occur to him
He just waves it away as some kind of conspiracy to advance the fourth rank
This interview isn't strictly about the newsweek article getting some criticism though
Professor abbott is a victim in all of this because he was about to deliver a guest lecture at mit
But was disinvited because of the blowback of that article abbott's response is slightly telling in this interview
Uh only the top people in the field are invited
To do this you give a large public lecture for like 500 people
And then you visit the department at mit about your research about a outreach level of your research
It sounds like this lecture was a big deal
But what is this outreach level comment?
It turns out that this lecture at mit was intended not strictly for faculty or university students
But also for high school students
robert vander hilst head of mit's earth atmospheric and planetary sciences department clarified in a statement
The carlson lecture isn't a scientific talk for fellow scientists
It has a very specific format and public outreach component seeking to build public understanding of climate science and to inspire and engage with
Area high school students. We felt that with the current distractions. We would not be in a position to hold an effective outreach event
I made this decision at my discretion after consulting with faculty and students in the department
And knowing that some might mistake it as an affront on academic freedom a characterization. I do not agree with though
This particular lecture was cancelled mit did invite professor abbott to give another lecture this one instead with faculty and university students
This isn't a case of someone being cancelled. It's a case of someone's lecture being rescheduled
But that's not the narrative we see on tucker carlson's show. It's a way to cripple someone's
A scientific career and put pressure on them not to speak out
I don't know how speaking to high school students would mean more for his career than presenting his research to practicing academics
But there's one more aspect of this interview that was very informative after abbott had that letter written about him in 2020
The minor controversy that followed drew the attention of many supposed free speech groups
Apparently abbott suddenly found himself networking with a number of different groups and individuals ready to champion his cause
That the worst thing that happened to him was a letter didn't matter. They welcomed him into their fold
I was already a part of the heterodox academy. I got involved with fire foundation for individual rights and education
I I met with some of the leadership at acta the american council of trustees and alumni
I started networking and trying to understand what had happened and how I can be effective
He unironically calls this a group of classical liberals and even mentions how they set up a little safe space for themselves
They have controversial speakers
And it's the faculty. It's only faculty who attend by invitation only so everyone can trust who's there
And as is typical with these conversations
We see tucker carlson and professor abbott pat themselves on the back for having a conversation
Even though they might disagree on some stuff and you speaking to me is not the same as ratifying all of my different
Exactly crazy opinions which you may disagree with but that's not the point if you didn't talk to everyone you disagreed with something on
You wouldn't talk to anyone, right?
It's like this program turned into an episode of the ruben report where the hapless dave ruben happily nods along with whatever right-wing
Goal he's invited onto his show only in this case
It's a bit more sophisticated with tucker carlson bringing on a sympathetic face to advance similar talking points
And he's actually capable of marching to the same beat alongside with them instead of vacuously nodding his head like dave ruben
I hate how hollow the whole comment about how they can disagree about things but still talk to one another
At no point in this interview did the two of them have any sort of meaningful disagreement about anything
It's the same line dave ruben would have about not having to agree with all his guests
If there is no active airing of these disagreements in this case tucker carlson doesn't even bring them up
Then this is just platforming ideas with no pushback. The invisible disagreements don't matter because they're not talking about them
These are two people who agree about everything they're discussing in this interview
Their disagreements could be about fundamental policy issues or what kind of potato chip they like to eat
It doesn't matter. We don't see it
Professor abbott not only faced the horror of having his mit lecture rescheduled
He was also rewarded with an additional lecture at princeton, which so far has over 10 000 viewers registered
Which is a lot more than the 500 he expected at his first mit lecture
The interview ends on an optimistic note that really reinforces the idea that this man has in no meaningful way been cancelled
That there is an entire apparatus ready to make him the next darling of the free speech crowd
He might make the rounds on exclusively right-wing shows talking about the left being out of control
And if he plays his car, right maybe he'll get a job at the blaze or maybe we'll never hear about this guy again
Because to be perfectly honest guys like this have limited appeal their tools to talk about the phantom menace of cancel culture
It's really just the media savvy ones who can parlay that into a career
I don't know if this guy has it in him for that
Remember when I said about how I got lucky that tucker took friday off
Well that luck ran out when I learned that he also dropped an extra bit of content onto fox nation
One of his monthly tucker carlson originals this one titled blown away the people versus wind power as you might have guessed
It's about how wind power is a threat to america this 25 minute special which calls itself a documentary is so thin and cheesy
I struggle to take it seriously
It's lavishly produced and leans very heavily on interviews that give emotional context to the supposed threat of wind power
That's the second type of interview. I mentioned above
The vast majority of subjects are either regular people or activists upset that wind turbines have been or are being built near them
Here's an example people who look at some of these wind proposals
Figure out quickly that one of the reasons their community is being targeted
Is it's poor and they're perceived as being desperate for revenue
This sure seems like a case of the little guy being troubled by big business. So let's see who we meet first
The consequence of this affluent nimbyism is that the high cost of green energy falls on poorer places
Places like rural, iowa home to mike and tanya lamb
I'm not sure what property values are like in iowa
But there is no way that anyone living in that home is one of the poorer and desperate described earlier
Tanya lamb who lives in the house literally calls it her dream home
It is our dream home
The special is a collection of shots of windmills breaking up otherwise flat scenery
And if you're guessing many of these complaints about windmills is that they will ruin the view
You'd be right in 2019
The wind farms came this is our view from our dinner table
Turbines every direction and you know, we get a lot of shadow flicker in here, too
I mean just imagine being in a room and someone's turning the light switch on and off on and off on and off
I mean and this it's in the middle of the day. Well, it's actually the morning is when it's the worst and
It I mean it almost makes you dizzy
There are some other assorted complaints like the wind turbine creates a lot of noise
And the only time we hear noise from a turbine is when we get one of these weird close-ups where audio is almost certainly being manipulated
Our peaceful country living
That isn't to say that these things are completely silent and I suppose whatever noise might be generated is annoying
Anyone can find plenty of these complaints online
But a problem with this criticism is that it's couched in the idea that these wind turbines are in rural areas
Because people in cities don't want the burden that comes with building them. That is supposedly the noise they create
As someone who currently lives in a city that is one of the most ridiculous things i've ever heard as I type this
I can hear a plane flying overhead as it approaches the city's airport 30 minutes ago
There was a siren as an ambulance drove by and a few days ago
I spent most of the day listening to a construction crew repair a water main down the street for me
We get noise in the city the occasional whooshing noise would not be a big deal
The reason you don't see a lot of wind turbines in cities is because they're more effective in wide open spaces
Such as coastal areas or open planes if you live somewhere like a flat part of iowa
That's what makes it an attractive spot for a wind turbine
When is it nearly strong enough when the turbine is surrounded by buildings?
We get some laughable complaints about how subsidies are used to create wind farms wind farms only exist because they're heavily subsidized by
Politicians with your money. They wouldn't exist. Otherwise, there's no mention at all of subsidies that go towards fossil fuel companies
This is where the special really drops the ball
Any discussion about energy needs would of course mention that there is always a cost associated with them both financial and environmental
And while wind turbines have one
Comparatively their cost is lower than that of fossil fuels
An article in nature describes the amount of spent on fossil fuel subsidies as more than triple what is spent on renewables like wind energy
It's irresponsible to discuss these subsidies without presenting that context
But it certainly doesn't end there what really annoyed me in the specials when it got personal and tucker tried to use the birds
To push his agenda from the federal government and other studies that show that hundreds of thousands of birds are killed every year
By wind turbines again a comparison needs to be made here every year
Far more birds are killed by power lines buildings and cats than wind turbines
And if we're going to reduce this discussion to energy production fossil fuels are driving climate change
Which will and does have a dramatic impact on bird habitats devastating populations and threatening entire species with extinction
This isn't to say that we shouldn't consider birds when building windmills
Particularly species that are more likely to be impacted by them
And this can be addressed by considering migration patterns and habitats when it comes to placing windmills
But climate change is by far the bigger threat and if someone truly cares about the birds
Fossil fuels are a much greater danger to birds than windmills
There is very little to comment on in this special
We spend some time with a fisherman worried about his business failing because of wind turbines that haven't been built yet
And activists who say that wind turbines would mean new york has changed its political composition this state. It's not a democracy
It's the socialist republic. Oh, it might be fun to just dunk on these people providing evidence that building windmills around water
Typically has no meaningful impact on fish populations
Or when this guy holds up a map to demonstrate that new york state would never build wind turbines near new york city
Is completely contradicted by the fact that there is the empire wind project an offshore wind farm being built right next to new york city
That is planned for completion in 2026
Ultimately, this is the smallest of potatoes being presented
The previous tucker carlson original special to air was about ufos if you're in a series that includes a special about the dangers of ufos
I hate to break it to you
But you're not on a serious program
And so we come to the end of our odyssey through the many programs of tucker carlson
And this was all from a single week what I found most surprising about this venture was how diverse tucker's talking points were
He truly had something for everyone. He had conspiracy theories of all flavors. He had racism
He had sexism transphobia anti-semitism neo-con republicanism and religiosity
Part of my research included trips to the facebook page for tucker carlson tonight where clips of the opening monologues were often shared
And the comments were completely uninteresting
Some I guess i'll call them highlights include if we the people want to keep our freedom
We must stand up and not submit to the mandates
We must push back
We must ask the one and only true god to have mercy on us and shine the light of truth on the evil
Being played out right in front of us. No wonder the left hates tucker carlson. He mops the floor with them
every single night
With the exception of the colon pal monologue
Which sparked a bit of debate between those who respect his position and those who hate his disapproval of donald trump
The comments are mostly filled with screeds against democrats and adulation for tucker
No one is watching the show critically. They're coming here to have their biases served
This observation I imagine will shock no one nor will my debunking of tucker carlson's content
His program has long been understood as a pack of lies used to push far-right talking points
But by washing it for a week what surprised me was how artificial it all felt so obviously rehearsed. Here's a quick example
Like white privilege family privilege is an unacknowledged and unearned benefit
Instantiated if that's even a word these people are so stupid
Instantiated in u.s. Law's policies and practices just right like an american for the benefit of tucker according to oxford
Instantiated means to represent as or by an instance. It's a little examples like these that exemplify or
Instantiate the somewhat folksy attitude tucker presents on a show much like the rolled up sleeves and wood paneling on his today program
Or the photo ops he does in his definitely real and not at all staged
Cabinsque room tucker carlson's audience have bought into this fiction of him being a man of the people even though he comes from
A wealthy background and continues to make millions on fox news
pushing hollow narratives designed to misinform and distract his audience from the fact that he
And people like him are actively working against their interests
It speaks to the problem of personalities in political commentary people aren't tuning in for the news
They're tuning in to see tucker
He gives them a version of the world they want to believe in so they outsource their thinking to him
And he shapes the news of the day into a version that confirms their biases
Whether it's distracting them with bogus stories about menacing refugee children or misinforming them about vaccines that will save their lives
The objective is to rile people up and make them angry with empty narratives and then direct them towards republican politicians
Will devote more money to the military and undermine projects that might benefit the american people
The interview with retcord bragman summed it up perfectly when he called tucker carlson a millionaire working for billionaires
And that is why that segment never saw the light of day on tucker's show and we only have evidence since bragman recorded it himself
Tucker carlson needs that facade to keep this whole thing going. It's not about standing up to the powerful elites
It's about distracting the people with nonsense so they don't notice those same elites exploiting them
That is what tucker carlson does with his programming each week
This one was quite a ride tucker carlson's show really spins your head around
Just constantly firing off information at you daring you to even try and understand it
If I wanted to debunk every claim he made on his show this video would have been like five or six hours
It's the eternal problem of debunking videos where the truth takes so much longer to explain than the lie that is repeated so easily
If you enjoy this video and would like to see more like it
You can be like the lovely names going up your screen now and join my patreon
You can also become a youtube member
You will get early access to videos download links to my theme songs
And of course your name in the credits to support this channel in a non-monetary fashion
You can hit the like button leave a comment subscribe if you haven't already and hit the bell for notifications
Thank you all
So much for watching