If you want to have an honest conversation about race on the internet, here's what you do.
You set your computer on fire, you flee to the forest, you drink a mimosa laced with toad venom,
and you simply wait for the wolverines to eat your legs.
Trust me, you're better off that way. Because if you look for videos on YouTube about race,
well, here's what you get. You get fascism, racist pseudoscience,
racist debate fascists, tag team title match tonight at 9, or if you're lucky, you get this.
So perhaps our legal system isn't going around willy-nilly convicting innocent black people of
crimes they didn't commit. Perhaps individuals who happen to be black are making bad choices
for which they have to deal with the consequences. Racism isn't the explanation for everything bad
that happens to black people. If blacks are getting shot and going to jail more,
it's their fault for committing crimes. That's right. Racial inequality in America
exists because black people simply decide to commit more crimes for
now. That's right. Racial inequality in America exists because black people simply decide to commit more crimes for now.
I guess he's probably going to blame the rap music. Or deadbeat dads with their sagging pants.
I'd say that this is the most common right-wing view of race in America. It's not outright
fascism or race realism, but simply the classical liberal view that racial inequality is the product
not of injustice, but of… black people simply deciding to make bad choices. Usually this idea
gets whipped out as a way to wave away the indisputable facts of racial inequality and
dismiss those pesky protesters always complaining about things.
Mmm, they make me uncomfortable and I don't like it. This is what I'm going to
argue against in this video. We're going to take a break from talking about fascism. In the past,
I've focused too much on the alt-right. I think we all have. I mean, don't get me wrong, it definitely
is a dangerous movement, but it's just not the most consequential kind of white supremacy that
exists in America. In this video, I want to talk about the real root of racial inequality in America,
which is the structural injustice that disadvantages many people of color.
And from now on, I'm going to try not to get so distracted by this circus sideshow of Pepes and
racist Odinists and neo-Nazi LARPers. All that stuff, it's very last season. I'm kind of
over it. Oh, God damn it. Hello, people. Fritz, get the hell out of here. No one cares about you
anymore. Nein, ich heiße nicht mehr Fritz. Nenn mich jetzt Freya. What? Ich bin jetzt eine Frau.
Great. Get out. Well, don't you want to hear about my transition? No, I don't care. No one cares.
You're still a Nazi. Get out. But I'm trans. How could I possibly be a Nazi? That's a good
question. It's almost as if you're an irrational person and your worldview makes no sense.
Get out. She calls me a Nazi, and yet she's the one trying to silence
my free speech, an excellent example of how truly fascist the left has become. Look,
if your ideas stand up to rational scrutiny, why aren't you willing to discuss them in the free
marketplace of ideas? Well, I'm going to discuss them in the free marketplace of ideas as soon as
you get out of my room. Mom, get out of my life. Well, can we at least talk about the Jewish
question? No. It's just ideas. What are you afraid of? I'm afraid that I'm going to have to blow the
tabby whistle if you don't get out of here in ten seconds. Ten, nine, eight, seven, six. Oh,
baby, come on. I thought you liked to bake. You used to whisper in my ear. I'm afraid that I'm
going to have to whisper it to me so sweetly. Well, not anymore. Well, do you at least want
to buy some Vitalimax? Hey, Jesus. I don't like doing this. I prefer to have conversations about
disagreements. I don't enjoy waving a bat around and hissing like a cat, but it's these people,
they just give you no choice. Where were we? Right, so racial injustice. When I talk to people
about this issue, they often claim to have this experience that leftists react to them in two ways.
One, by saying, you're racist. And two, by saying, it's not my job to educate you. And I'm
sure this isn't as universal as people say it is, but it does seem to be an experience a lot
of people have. And that's not good, because most people are pretty ignorant about this,
no offense. And there's no shortage of fascists, race realists, and classical liberals who are
more than happy to educate people in their own special way. So as I see it, the left needs to
step it up. Now, to be fair, if you're bothering random people of color on Twitter to demand they
explain racism to you, you're being called a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're
a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're
a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're a racist. You're being kind of
an asshole. And it's true. It's not their job to explain it to you. They have other shit to do
with their lives. But I, on the other hand, do not have anything better to do than swerve wildly out
of my lane and white-splain racism to you for the next 20 minutes. Because it kind of is my job,
and I have all the time in the world. It's a funny thing, time.
Whose job is it to mend the crimes of history? Do we have to take responsibility for things
that happened a long time ago? I don't even take responsibility for things I didn't do.
July. This person. Who the fuck is that? No, I don't have any white guilt. That's not what this
is about. That's just more white narcissism is what that is. So wipe away those white-ass tears.
Here. I'll pick you out a cotton ball.
1. Freddie Gray
On April 12, 2015, three police officers,
near a housing project in West Baltimore, arrested a 25-year-old black man named Freddie Gray
because he was carrying a spring-assisted knife that maybe was illegal? They handcuffed him and
loaded him into a police van. His leg broke and y'all dragging him like that.
When the van arrived at the police station, Gray was in a coma for some reason, with three
fractured vertebrae and his spine 80% severed at the neck. A week later, Gray died of his spinal
injury while the Baltimore police released contradictory and inadequate information about
his arrest. This led to widespread protests, and the police were forced to arrest him. This led to
widespread protests, and the police were forced to arrest him. This led to widespread protests,
all over the city, eventually culminating in the notorious Baltimore riots.
Now you might be thinking, what does this have to do with racism? If black people don't want to be
killed, then they shouldn't commit crimes and run away from the police. Well, the first problem with
that is that extrajudicial executions for non-violent crimes shouldn't really be a common
thing in a civilized democracy. And it's a little alarming to me how quick you are to defend this.
And the other problem is that that's a very superficial analysis that refuses to examine
the deeper reasons why black neighborhoods tend to have more poverty, more crime, and are subject to
more aggressive violence than black neighborhoods. And the other problem is that that's a very
superficial analysis that refuses to examine the deeper reasons why black neighborhoods tend to have more
of policing. So let's delve a little deeper, starting with Freddie Gray as a case study.
Gray had a long arrest record of mostly drug offenses, and a lot of conservative commentators
brought this out as evidence that he was no angel. The implication, I guess, is that Gray simply got
what was coming to him, that he deserved to die. But why did he commit all these crimes in the
first place? I don't think he was selling drugs for lack of entrepreneurial ambition. Did he just
do it for no reason? Well, let's see. Freddie Gray was born in 1989 in the West Baltimore neighborhood,
Sandtown, Winchester. You can see in this picture of him as a child that he grew up in
a dilapidated row house with peeling lead paint. Lead was used as a cheap additive in house paint
until Congress banned it in 1978 because it causes serious cognitive damage in children,
leading to deficits in attention and increased aggression, which may explain why children poisoned
with lead are seven times more likely to drop out of school, and six times more likely to end up in
the juvenile justice system. But shitty Baltimore slumlords often haven't bothered to comply with
the Congressional ban on lead paint. And that's not the only reason why Freddie Gray has been
banned from using lead paint. And as a result, 93,000 children with lead poisoning have been
added to Maryland's lead registry, and in Baltimore, the vast majority of these children are black.
Many of these kids were later awarded structured settlements as compensation for permanent brain
damage, and Freddie Gray was one of these kids. Now, you might be thinking, well, reparations were
paid out, so problem solved, right? Well, unfortunately, no. What's happened is a sub-industry
has emerged of shark lawyers who swoop in on the lead poisoning victims, some of whom can't even
believe it, and offer to buy out their structured monthly settlements in exchange for a lump sum
that's a fraction of the total worth of the settlement. And that's exactly what happened
to Freddie Gray. In 2013, a company called Access Funding bought the $146,000 remainder of his
settlement for $18,300. They also bought his sister's settlements, acquiring the entire $435,000
Gray siblings settlement for $54,000. Now, I hope we can all agree that this is objectively bad,
but to understand how it relates to structural racism, I'm going to give you a little bit of a
look at Baltimore's history of racial segregation. Or, you know, we could just keep doing livestreams
with Richard Spencer. Interviews with Nazis. The new YouTube craze. God damn it. I need to relax.
I need music.
2. Housing Discrimination
Take a look at this map, which shows Baltimore neighborhoods with children with elevated lead
levels between 2010 and 2013, and compare it with this map of Baltimore's racial demographics.
Yellow dots stand out.
Standing for black residents.
And blue dots standing for white.
Lead. Race.
Also, notice how sharp the divisions are between black and white neighborhoods.
Why, in the 21st century, is Baltimore still so segregated?
I thought racism was over.
Well, here's the thing about that. When your country's history is 400 years of slavery,
Jim Crow, and segregation, you don't just get to say,
Oops. Sorry about that.
It's all cool now though, right?
No.
It's not cool.
And these maps are a pretty good illustration of one of the major not cool things.
Let's look at how this shit happened in the first place.
I hope I'm not being too controversial if I propose that, 100 years ago,
America may have been somewhat racist.
In 1910, a Yale-educated black lawyer named W. Ashby Hawkins bought a house in a prestigious
white Baltimore neighborhood. This produced such an uproar among the white residents that the city
passed an ordinance mandating the segregation of every residential block. Basically, the ordinance
forbade black people to buy or rent houses on majority white blocks, and vice versa,
until the Supreme Court overturned the ordinance in 1917.
Well, if the Supreme Court overturned the Jim Crow laws, then what's the problem?
Racism can't exist if black people have all the same rights as white people.
Well, no.
That's actually not correct.
In 1934, Congress created the Federal Housing Administration to promote homeownership in the
midst of the Great Depression, when many homes were foreclosed.
One of the FHA's purposes was to establish a reliable credit system backed by the government,
which would regulate interest rates and ensure the terms of mortgages.
FHA-backed loans played a critical role in facilitating homeownership throughout the
middle of the 20th century, the period many white Americans now remember as the golden
age of the American Dream. But many black Americans were excluded from homeownership
and the benefits it conferred to white families, particularly the family financial stability it
enabled. So how was this exclusion possible? Well, basically, the FHA, city governments,
and white citizens adopted a variety of subtle methods to enforce residential segregation and
deny homeownership to black Americans. For instance,
1. Restrictive covenants
When the 1910 ordinance was overturned, Baltimore's mayor created an official
Committee on Segregation, which cooperated with neighborhood associations to pressure
landlords in white neighborhoods to sign covenants committing them never to sell or
rent to black residents. These agreements were enforced through strategic building and health
code citations issued against owners and by evictions of black renters who violated the
covenant.
2. Redlining
The FHA adopted a policy of refusing to
insure mortgages in black neighborhoods, which were colored in red on official maps,
giving the practice the name redlining. This effectively denied black citizens access to
government-backed mortgages, which, in turn, left them vulnerable to
3. Predatory lending
Unscrupulous white sellers took advantage of black buyers' exclusion from FHA-backed mortgages,
exploiting lax regulations to design unfairly-priced installment plans with
abusive terms, which allowed, for instance, sellers to repossess and resell homes after
a single missed payment. Many black residents had no choice,
but to buy into these exploitative contracts, and they often resorted to subdividing houses
or neglecting repairs in order to make payments, further contributing to the overcrowding and
decay of black neighborhoods.
4. Blockbusting
Predatory real estate agents often used a scheme known as blockbusting,
where they'd intentionally provoke fear of an impending minority takeover among residents of
a white neighborhood. They would then exploit the fear that they created to trick white homeowners
into selling their houses at below market prices, so they could resell those same houses at
extortionate prices to black families. The FHA used this scheme to avoid the risk of black
families desperate to escape the ghetto. The long-term effect of these practices was that
many black families ended up trapped in decaying neighborhoods with bad schools,
little opportunity, cyclical crime and poverty, and aggressive, discriminatory policing.
And even though most of these segregation practices have ended,
the injustice remains unredressed. No reparations have been paid to black families who were
effectively robbed of homeownership during this period, predatory lending having cost
black families an estimated $500 million in Chicago alone. But worst of all is that segregation
and ghettoization caused by government-backed discrimination of the last century is still
ongoing. I'm currently sitting in my gentrifying white fucking neighborhood like one mile away from
where Freddie Gray was arrested in a neighborhood that's like a whole different country.
Here's the 1937 redlining map of Baltimore. Now compare that to the 2013 population by race map.
If the 1937 map is the product of racism, and it is, and if the city still follows the same
pattern of segregation today, and it does, well, it's almost as if the effects of
racism have not entirely been eradicated. And it's not just Baltimore that's like this either.
Here are redlining maps of New York, Chicago, Philadelphia, Atlanta, Detroit, New Orleans,
Cleveland, LA. All these cities are still segregated as shit, and it's not like a
separate but equal situation either. Compare the 2013 population by race map of Baltimore
to this map of Baltimore police stops between 2010 and 2015. That's black neighborhoods in red
and green dots representing recorded police stops of black pedestrians. And finally, let's bring
back the map of childhood lead poisoning between 2010 and 2013. Now consider this information in
combination with some scientific studies linking lead exposure and violent crime, and it almost
starts to look like there's some problems going on here that might not be solved simply by telling
black teenagers to tighten their belts and do less crimes. But I don't want to overstate the lead
crime theory either, because that only accounts for a small fraction of what's going on here.
The bigger picture is the lasting economic deprivation caused by segregation,
the historical exclusion from homeownership, the lost upper
opportunities, the bad schools, and this country's ongoing insistence on treating a problem of
injustice as if it were simply a problem of criminality. I know I said my interest in this
topic isn't a matter of white guilt, and it's not, but also, fellow whites, how do we sleep at night?
In this guided meditation, you're going to relax your body and release your guilt. You're not
responsible for what your great-grandparents did. As you ease the tension in each muscle group,
exhale deeply, and repeat,
the mantra, black lives matter are the real racists.
3. Mass Incarceration
Since the 1970s, the United States' incarceration rate has rapidly risen to the point where nearly
1 in 100 American men are in jail or prison. We now have the highest incarceration rate in the
world, accounting for 22% of the world's prisoners, though we make up only 4.4% of the world's
population. More than a third of the total incarcerated population is black, and the black
incarceration rate is almost 2.5% of the world's population. This is the highest incarceration rate
in the world, accounting for 22% of the world's prisoners, though we make up only 4.4% of the world's
prisoners, though we make up only 4.5% of the world's prisoners. This is the highest incarceration rate
in the world's prison rate.
Now, without even bringing race into it, it's clear that America has a prison problem in general.
Sentences are too long, too many nonviolent drug offenders are in prison, too many defendants are
pressured into plea bargains, and a private prison industry incentivizes high rates of
incarceration. But disproportionately, people of color are victimized by this system.
Now, a lot of people are going to look at the incarceration data and say,
if the blacks don't like going to jail, they should just do less crimes.
Let's do another interview with Richard Spencer.
You know what, why don't we all interview Richard Spencer? Every single YouTuber,
free speech mandates that we all constantly broadcast fascist propaganda. Let's get them
all in here, every single Nazi in one giant livestream, and then we can finally give the
Jewish question the platform it deserves. God damn it, where's my toad venom?
Look, it's just not always the case that black people are imprisoned more because they commit
more crimes. For instance, black and white people use weed at about the same rate, but black people
are nearly four times as likely to be arrested for it. And we're talking about a drug that,
at this point, white America has basically decided shouldn't really even be illegal anyway.
So we've now got a $10 billion legal marijuana industry, and just look what white people are
doing to weed. Mark Smith is the CEO of Tumbleweed, a ganjapreneur. It's a strong, strong sativa,
very high in limonene. It's a great bronchodilator, so I like to use it when I work out.
Yeah, so, in fact, in the back of the limousine is only the,
one of the only legal places you can consume cannabis.
The whites are at it again. They have gentrified the marijuana. And now we've got white business
people making millions of dollars selling the same drug that black people are still
disproportionately incarcerated for having sold.
A ganjapreneur!
What do I do with the gold on my fingers?
This is the most basic kind of unfairness. And if this doesn't make you angry, then either you're
really ignorant about this, or you might just not care about black people.
I don't like to assume the worst of people, but when I look at the state of the conversation about
race in America, I see a lot of people who are willing to just wave away the extrajudicial
executions of black people by the police, the mass incarceration of people of color,
and the vicious history of discrimination and its ongoing repercussions.
And from those same people, I see a tendency to get extremely outraged by any black person who
takes a stand, or takes a knee, or speaks up about this in any way.
There's an endless mill of content about how authoritarian and evil Black Lives Matter is,
and how it's identity politics equivalent to white nationalism,
and it's unpatriotic, and postmodern, and racist.
And I'm sorry, but this group of creators are being really melodramatic.
Black college students complaining too loudly are not Orwell's night
mare. If anything in this country deserves to be called an authoritarian nightmare,
it's locking people in cages for decades over drug offenses.
But right-wing YouTube doesn't seem very interested in using their free speech to
talk about that. They're too busy complaining about people using their free speech to protest.
How dare they?
Now, I can also anticipate another objection that doesn't come from YouTube fascists or stock
salad-eating basic white girl caricatures. I imagine some black people will probably watch
this video and think, where does this white bitch get off telling me I'm a victim? I take
responsibility for my own life instead of blaming all my problems on racism.
And here's the thing about that. You're actually right in the sense that taking responsibility,
or taking control of your life to the greatest extent possible,
is actually a good way to live your life as an individual.
So by all means, don't allow yourself to be defined by victimhood.
Do take control of your destiny as much as possible.
So I'm not saying anyone should blame all their problems on bigotry and wallowing victimhood.
Please don't do that. Go succeed as much as possible.
But also, while you're succeeding, don't deny that oppressive circumstances exist.
Yes, it's possible for individuals to escape oppressive circumstances,
but we also have a collective duty to work to eliminate the unjust conditions
that create those circumstances in the first place.
Wow. I feel like I just gave a great speech.
Would you take my speech less seriously if you knew I had been drinking Bud Light
Lime this entire time? Look, I even put a lime in it.
Bud Light Lime with Lime. The official beverage of people who complain about people who complain
too much about people who complain too much about racism. For the final countdown.
I want to say two more things before I flee into the forest.
First, there actually are more racial groups in America than just black people and white people.
I've just narrowed the topic of discussion so this video isn't three hours long.
But there are lots of other kinds of racism in this country,
and someone should make videos about those too.
Second, please don't get all your information from YouTube.
I've put some links in the description with my sources and some further reading on the topic.
Also, don't get all your information about race and racism from white people.
Like, come on, that should just be common sense.
So when this video ends, what you should do is scroll down,
smash that unsubscribe button,
unclick that little bell so you no longer receive notifications about my videos,
and then you should go subscribe to a bunch of people of color and listen to what they have to say.
Um, so, I guess that's it.
I was just kidding about the forest.
I don't fuck with forests, I'm really more of an indoor tranny.
So, guess I'll just go sing a song about fighting racists.
My eyes have seen the glory of the coming day
The King of the Lord
He is trampling out the vintage
Where the graves of wrath are stoned
He hath loosed the fateful lightning
Of his terrible swift sword
His truth is marching on
Glory, glory, hallelujah!
His truth is marching on!
In the beauty of the lilies
Christ was born across the sea
With a glory in his bosom
That transfigures you and me
As he died to make men holy
Let us die to make men free
While God is with us
God is marching on!
Glory, glory, hallelujah!
His truth is marching on!
Death to capitalism and the patriarchy
Smash the binary
Hail Satan!
Ow!