Okay. Let's get started. I literally need a man. I need a man. Help! Alright, I'm gonna
get pliers. The lesbian solution. Okay. Let's get started.
I love my king. This is not really the most feminine moment for me. Not really my
2020 vibe, but it does proportionize my giant man hands.
Meow, meow, meow.
Alright, no one thinks I'm cute. Let's get started. Okay, look, this video is about
canceling, also known as cancel culture, formerly known as call-out culture. And I know you kids
know all about this, but before we dive in, I have to explain the basics to my fellow boomers.
So listen up, oldies. In the lingo of these young, avocado-guzzling, smartphone addicts
who killed Applebee's, canceling is online shaming, vilifying, and ostracizing of prominent
members of a community by
other members of that community. Like so much internet slang, this use of the word
canceling started out on black Twitter, where a few years ago, people, well, mostly women,
would tweet, cancel R. Kelly, and things like that. You know, it started out as this vigilante
strategy for bringing justice and accountability to powerful people who previously had been
immune to any consequences for their actions.
For example, the Me Too movement promised to use social media shaming to topple sexually abusive men in power,
who couldn't be held accountable any other way. The promise of canceling was that it was going to give power back to people who had none,
and bring justice to prominent abusers. It's in a way, the 21st century version of the guillotine, the bringer of justice, the people's avenger.
But also like the guillotine, it can become a sadistic entertainment spectacle. And I want to make the case that we do have, well, a teensy bit of a Reign of Terror situation on our hands, Gorg.
Now, there's a version of this conversation that's already been had to death, and it goes like this.
On the one side are a bunch of male comedians who constantly bitch about how cancel culture is out of control.
You can't joke about anything anymore without these millennial jackals trying to get you in trouble.
And the other side is mostly progressive think piece authors who argue that there's no such thing as cancel culture,
it's just that powerful people are finally being held accountable for their actions, and they can't fucking handle it,
so they go around bitching about cancel culture. Now, unfortunately, neither of those viewpoints,
is quite as correct as some people might hope. So it's a good thing I'm here to deliver the truth.
He didn't know I was transgender.
Story time. Emotional, not clickbait.
Let's start with an example. The most high-profile YouTube canceling of 2019 was the canceling of James Charles.
And again, I know you kids remember this, but I have to reheat ancient YouTube tea for the elders.
Put the kettle on, Karen.
So James Charles is a 20-year-old beauty guru, which means, um, boomers.
Look, there's these people,
who make YouTube videos,
teaching you how to do makeup.
It's worth checking out if you can figure out how to start up Internet Explorer.
I certainly can't.
It's pretty bomb. It's lit. It's, uh,
it's groovy. It's fab. It's far out, man.
It's a gas. I fully dig it.
Free love. Give peace a chance.
Nixon's a fascist.
So back in May of this year, James's colleague and
mother figure?
Fellow YouTube beauty guru Tati Westbrook
uploaded a 40-minute video
accusing James of endorsing
a different brand of hair vitamins
than the brand that she,
wait, that was a competitor of her brand of hair vitamins.
An enthralling plotline, I know.
And this was huge. This was covered in the New York Times.
And while Tati was at it,
almost as an afterthought to the, uh,
hair vitamin dispute,
she also accused James of being
a sexual predator.
Now, I actually went back and checked
Tati's original deleted video,
and she actually never uses the phrase
sexual predator.
It's funny, I remember her calling him that
because that became the story on Twitter.
But what she actually said was
James had tried to trick straight men
into thinking they're gay.
Oh my god, you tried to trick a straight man
into thinking he's gay yet again.
Which is pretty different from calling him a sexual predator.
But see, this is what cancel culture does.
It takes one story and transforms it
into a significantly different story.
You know, the headline I would write
about the James and Tati story might read
Tati Westbrook accuses James Charles
of trying to trick straight men
into thinking they're gay.
But cancel culture transforms that story
into the headline,
James Charles is a sexual predator.
Interesting.
Now, I want to make it clear that my intention here
is really not to defend James Charles.
I'm not a James Charles stan.
I'm a biological female in my 30s.
Close to death, I know.
Please leave a comment before I die.
That said, I do think the statement
James Charles is a sexual predator
is a stretch, to say the least.
At least, based on the information I have
in December 2019.
So let's analyze how this kind of truth stretching happens.
Cancel culture trope one.
And you should be writing this down, class,
because this will be on the test.
Cancel culture trope one.
Presumption of guilt.
There's a traditional understanding of justice
according to which,
before you condemn or punish a person,
you hear the accuser's side of the story
and the accused's side of the story.
You allow both sides to present evidence
and only after everyone involved
has had a chance to make their case
do you pass sentence and punish the convict.
Aww. Punish me, King.
Drinking this is punishment enough.
Am I uncanceled yet, please?
In the United States,
we legally have the presumption of innocence.
But canceling does not abide by the law.
Canceling is a form of vigilante mob justice.
And a lot of times, an accusation is proof enough.
Now, that's basically the point
of the progressive slogan,
believe victims.
It's a norm that was put into place in progressive spaces
because out in the world at large,
people generally don't believe victims.
But I think it's pretty obvious
how believe victims
is a norm that's easy to abuse.
Was Tati really James' victim?
No.
She's not some powerless woman
abused by a prominent man in her industry.
She's on top of the industry.
And she wasn't victimized by James at all.
I see this case more as she weaponized
cancel culture against a business rival.
Anyway, before James had even had a chance
to respond to Tati's accusation,
the story had already gone from
Tati Westbrook accuses James Charles
of trying to trick straight men
to James Charles tried to trick straight men.
And from there, it was generalized into
James Charles is toxic and manipulative.
Which brings us to cancel culture trope two,
abstraction.
Abstraction replaces the specific,
concrete details of a claim
with a more generic statement.
In the transition from Tati Westbrook
accused James Charles of trying to trick straight men
to James Charles is toxic and manipulative,
we've lost not only the sense of this behavior,
being an unverified accusation,
but we've also lost all the specific details.
James Charles is toxic and manipulative
is an incredibly vague statement.
It may as well be James Charles is bad.
But even without the presumption of guilt,
if someone tells me James Charles is accused
of toxic and manipulative behavior,
I'm gonna think, oh, that sounds pretty bad.
And I'm gonna start speculating about the specifics.
And whatever my imagination comes up with
is likely going to be worse
than whatever he's actually accused of.
Also, the specific accusation
that he tried to trick straight men
into thinking they're gay
is self-evidently kind of questionable.
How do you trick straight men into thinking they're gay?
If you find out, let me know.
It's bad. I'm bad. I'm super bad.
This is not a problem that straight men
usually seem to have.
At the very least, it requires further explanation.
It's the kind of story that sounds like
it has more than one side.
I'm not gonna be gonna feel a little bit skeptical
of the accusation.
And I'm also gonna side-eye Tati Westbrook
because this accusation is setting off
my homophobia detection alarm.
Leave the gays alone.
But I'm not gonna have an opportunity
to pick up on the potential homophobia
and be skeptical of it
if all I've heard about the situation
is James Charles is toxic and manipulative.
And I also wanna point out
a linguistic shift that's happening here.
When the claim was James Charles tried
to trick straight men,
the verbs in the sentence were try and trick.
So what we're criticizing here is James' behavior.
We're criticizing things he did, allegedly,
trying to trick straight men.
But once the claim morphs into James Charles
is toxic and manipulative,
the verb in the sentence is is, to be.
So these adjectives are characteristics of James,
and it's now not his actions we're criticizing
but his personality, his toxicity,
his manipulativeness.
And this is what I'll call
Cancel Culture Trope 3, essentialism.
Essentialism is when we go
from criticizing a person's actions
to criticizing the person themselves.
We're not just saying they did bad things,
we're saying they're a bad person.
And that's what takes us from
James Charles tried to trick straight men
to James Charles is a sexual predator.
So here we're targeting James himself,
not just his actions,
but the type of person he is.
A sexual predator.
And we've also really escalated the accusation.
Because I don't know about you guys,
but when I hear the phrase sexual predator,
the image that comes to mind is
a rapist or a child molester,
maybe an abusive boss?
Not a teenage twink hung up
on wanting to date straight guys.
I mean, not that a person like that
couldn't be a sexual predator,
but I really don't think that he's a sexual predator
is a fair summary of the accusation.
So this seems to me like a pretty nasty
and dishonest twisting of the story.
And it happened instantaneously on Twitter.
It totally dominated the conversation
in a community of millions of people
for weeks.
In a few days,
James had lost millions of subscribers,
and who knows what effect it had on his personal life.
Not that anyone seems to care.
In fact, most people seemed to be enjoying his downfall.
He was a teenage millionaire,
a young, beautiful superstar.
Easy to envy, easy to resent,
hard to relate to, hard to sympathize with.
What was the point of canceling James Charles?
Did we want to teach him a lesson?
Did we want him to learn from his mistakes
and grow as a person?
Imagine actually wanting someone to learn.
Imagine actually caring.
My hunch is that the average YouTube viewer
was not sincerely outraged and hurt
by their sincere belief that James Charles
was a sexual predator.
In other words, this was not a case of triggered SJWs.
This was a controversy manufactured from the top
by a handful of seemingly vindictive and envious people.
I honestly think that most of the
James Charles is a sexual predator crowd
just wanted to bring him down a peg.
Cancel culture trope four.
Pseudo-moralism or pseudo-intellectualism.
If you look at the world we live in,
would you say that people are usually motivated
by a sense of moral integrity and intellectual rigor?
No, maybe not.
Let's be real, America.
We are a bunch of morally impotent meatbags
constantly shitting ourselves out of fear and lust.
For Tati, calling out James, this was really,
it was about the hair vitamins, right?
I think sis was super salty that this millionaire kid
who she had supported and helped
had betrayed her by endorsing a rival brand.
And accusing him of trying to trick straight men
was just a twist of the knife.
But moralism or intellectualism
provide a phony pretext for the call out.
You can pretend you just want an apology.
You can pretend you're just a concerned citizen
who wants the person to improve.
You can pretend you're simply offering up criticism
when what you're really doing
is attacking a person's career and reputation
out of spite, envy, revenge.
I mean, it could be any motivation.
Twitter viewed James as an overprivileged,
spoiled little brat
and it was fun to wipe the smile off his smug face
at least for a few weeks.
It's schadenfreude, right?
This kind of petty sadism.
Maybe not the internet's proudest moment,
but not the most shameful either.
And it's not to say that everyone cancelling James Charles
was insincere.
But there's a world of difference
between Cancel R. Kelly
and Cancel James Charles.
And I'm interested to know
how these two things came to look the same.
When James was being cancelled,
I remember being kind of transfixed
by the sight of his life and career
falling from the sky,
full tailspin, black smoke spewing out.
And a lot of my YouTube friends were like,
lol, did you see James Charles is cancelled?
lolololololol.
But I looked up at James and I said,
oh god, that's gonna be me someday.
Stay strong, sister.
Don't let the bastards get you down.
Let's switch over to White Claw.
These are cute, these are fun.
A little more of a feminine moment for me.
They didn't even have these last time I was an alcoholic.
I'm not even wearing makeup.
I don't need makeup to serve a full biological fantasy.
Keep drinking, people.
We're gonna make it through this together.
So I was doing a little Twitter archaeology
when I was looking into the James Charles cancelling,
and I found a bunch of tweets
referencing earlier James Charles scandals.
Y'all forgiving James Charles?
He's still a transphobe.
Y'all are acting like just because James Charles has receipts,
he's no longer a racist transphobe.
Like, James Charles is racist, ableist, transphobic,
and a sexual predator.
A white woman.
Y'all are being too harsh on him and he's uncancelled.
So according to Twitter,
James Charles is not only a sexual predator,
he's also a racist and a transphobe.
That sounds pretty serious.
Let's investigate.
We'll start with the transphobia allocation.
Cockerels of the jury.
Exhibit A.
So you're not even full gay.
I mean, no, there have been girls in the past that I've, like,
thought were really, really beautiful.
There's also been, like, trans guys in the past, too,
that I was, like, really, really into for a moment in time.
And I oop.
As they say on Twitter,
yikes.
This ain't it, chief.
Friendly reminder that this isn't a good look.
Maybe don't be transphobic.
Disappointing.
So James did, uh, fuck up here.
The problem is he's suggesting that being attracted to trans men
makes him less gay,
which implies that trans men aren't really men,
which is at odds with the way trans men understand themselves.
So this does deserve criticism.
No doubt, no doubt.
However, what I see when I look at this clip of James
is not
a dyed-in-the-wool transphobic bigot.
I see a very young person
who's still working on understanding his own sexuality
and is trying to figure out
where his attraction to trans men fits into that.
And it seems to me that the proportionate response to that situation
is for someone to take James aside
and explain to him,
look, here's why what you said is hurtful to trans men,
and here are some tips on how to avoid saying that kind of thing in the future.
You know, ignorance is not the same thing as hatred.
Not understanding someone is not the same as wanting them dead.
Of course, there are committed bigots
who it's just a waste of time to engage with.
But sometimes just talking to someone
with a little patience and understanding is all it takes.
But that's not what cancel culture does.
Oh no, we have to immediately escalate every situation
to the highest possible level of conflict.
So by abstraction,
we get James Charles made transphobic comments.
And by essentialism, we get
James Charles is a transphobe.
We don't give him a chance to reflect.
We don't give him an opportunity to learn.
We go straight to branding him a bigot.
Nonetheless, that same week,
James posted an apology to his Insta story saying,
Regardless of whatever my intentions were,
that came across as me saying
I'm not fully gay because I have been with a trans man
and that is absolutely,
first of all, not true.
Like that doesn't make me not fully gay.
But that stereotype and implication
is really, really dangerous.
And I'm very, very sorry.
If you are a trans man, you are a man.
If you're a trans girl, you are a woman.
You are valid in your identity.
Could you ask for a better apology?
Like he not only apologizes for what he said,
but he also demonstrates a clear understanding
of why it was wrong.
So does that mean people stopped calling him a transphobe?
Of course not.
Cancel culture trope five, no forgiveness.
Cancelers will often dismiss an apology as insincere,
no matter how convincingly written or delivered.
And of course, an insincere apology is further proof
of what a Machiavellian psychopath you really are.
Now, sometimes a good apology
will calm things down for a while.
But the next time there's a scandal,
the original accusation will be raised again,
as if you never apologized.
That's what happened to James during the Tati scandal,
when Twitter decided he was a transphobic sexual predator.
And that's to say nothing of this racism
I've been hearing about.
Here's the receipts.
Exhibit B.
In February 2017,
when James was much less famous than he is now,
he tweeted,
I can't believe we're going to Africa today.
OMG, what if we get Ebola?
James, we're fine.
We could have gotten it at Chipotle last year.
Okay, well, that's a little insensitive, maybe.
It's not really something an influencer should tweet.
And fear of disease associated with Africa.
I mean, I can see how it's in the same vague conceptual area
as certain racist tropes.
But clearly, this was intended as a joke
about his friend mistaking Ebola for E. coli, right?
And anyway, he did apologize, saying,
As a white cis male,
I recognize my privilege
and would never want to take that for granted.
But I fucked up.
I feel awful for posting what I said.
I understand why what I said was offensive and ignorant.
And James hasn't made a habit of making jokes like that ever since.
So...
Is this one tweet from two years ago
that he apologized for
on its own enough evidence
for us to justify labeling him
a racist?
Well, according to cancel culture, absolutely.
Abstraction takes us from
Two years ago, James Charles made a joke
that referenced his fear of getting Ebola in Africa
to James Charles made a racist joke.
And then essentialism takes us to
James Charles is a racist.
Look, I want to pause to say
I really do believe in social justice.
At least, as much as trash like me believes in anything.
And believe me, I am well aware
that jokes, irony, and even complaints about cancel culture
are often used by bigots to cloak their real agenda.
The Southern Poverty Law Center even cited my video
about how far-right racists use jokes and memes
and mockery of SJWs
as a way to camouflage their hateful beliefs
and make them more palatable to a wider audience.
So I'm coming at this from a place of genuine concern
for anti-racism and anti-transphobia
as well as an awareness of the fact
that cancel culture is often just
a conservative red herring used to shut down
any and all complaints about racism or transphobia.
But I've also become very disillusioned
with the way these accusations are thrown around
so frivolously on social media.
By the way, they're used to escalate conflict
instead of promote understanding.
And by the way, they're sometimes weaponized
to destroy people who have made mistakes
but who really don't deserve to be destroyed.
Now maybe you're thinking,
destroyed? What do you mean destroyed?
James is a 20-year-old millionaire
on his way to owning his own makeup empire.
And you are completely correct.
If you're James Charles, if you're a superstar,
then being canceled most likely does not destroy you.
The cancelers blend in to the general backdrop of haters
and they can set you back a few million subscribers
and a lot of emotional turmoil,
but in the long run, they can't really touch your success.
But here's the thing.
What if you're not James Charles?
What if you're a small creator?
What if you can't afford public relations help?
What if you belong to a marginalized community
and you rely on that community for support?
Well, in that case, it's a whole different story.
Let's Irish up this coffee.
Shaken, not stirred.
Spilled it over my pussy.
Mmm, that's good.
Booze and coffee is a good combination.
I'm feeling amped right now.
I'm feeling hype.
So this is the part in the video where I should admit
that I'm not just a casual observer here.
At the time I'm making this video,
sweaty,
I'm super canceled.
You know, I try to make videos that are both informative and entertaining.
So in this video, the information is
you get to learn about cancel culture
and the entertainment is
you get to watch a worm try to wriggle off a hook.
Let's get started.
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned.
Hey, how are you?
God, I never wanted to be the kind of YouTuber
who would resort to making videos about my own drama,
but things have gotten to a point.
I feel like I cannot continue this channel
until I spill some tea.
So let's get started.
Okay, first, a little backstory, a little mise-en-scene.
I've never talked about this on my channel before,
so this is a super fucking vulnerable moment for me.
But I am, in fact, a transgender woman,
which may come as a big shock to many of you
since I'm 100% real fesh.
I get comments all the time from very solemn people like,
guys, I'm pretty sure this is a dude.
Great work, detective.
You cracked the case.
You're doing very good, sweetie.
Very, very good.
But yes, as one of YouTube's leading B-list transgenders,
I am a prime target for cancellation,
and I have been canceled many, many times.
And we're gonna talk about some of the things
I've been canceled for
and some of the things I've been criticized for
and the difference between criticism and canceling.
Because yes, there is a difference.
As we go along,
I will admit where I have made mistakes
because despite how I look,
I am not a literal goddess,
and I will apologize where I believe apologies are due.
However, where I believe that criticism of me
is excessive or unwarranted,
I will not apologize
because here at ContraPoints Industries,
we are not in the business of serving bullshit.
So, the reason for my current cancellation is,
in summary, that in my last video, Opulence,
I cast transsexual violence
on the beautiful porn star Buck Angel
in the role of John Waters.
And yes, it's a much better story
than the hair vitamin debacle,
so notify the drama channels,
put in a good word for me,
because, sweetie,
I'm not here to make friends.
I'm here to win.
So basically, I'm canceled
for collaborating with Buck Angel,
and a lot of trans people think
Buck Angel is a horrible person.
And so my collaboration with Buck Angel
is evidence that I, too,
am a horrible person.
Cancel culture trope six,
the transitive property of cancellation.
Cancellation is infectious.
If you associate with a canceled person,
the cancellation rubs off.
It's like gonorrhea,
except doxycycline won't save you this time, sweetie.
Look, this whole incident hinges, first of all,
on whether Buck Angel is, in fact,
a horrible person.
So who is Buck Angel?
Well, he's a trans man of my parents' generation.
He grew up in a world
where there was not anything like the visibility
and access to information about transition we have today,
and where there was a strict medical gatekeeping system
in place for people who wanted to transition.
In fact, Buck was the first female-to-male patient
his doctor had ever treated.
In the 2000s, he rose to prominence as an adult performer,
his gimmick at the time being the man with the pussy.
But he also became an activist.
He wanted to create more positive trans representation
within the porn world.
And from there, he became a more general educator
and advocate for trans people.
I first heard about him in the early 2010s
when I was doing some Googling
about some little gender issues I was having myself,
although I ended up deciding to remain a female.
And Buck was one of the first female-to-male people
I'd ever heard about.
And he made an impact on me,
in part because you take one look at him and you think,
honey, that's a man.
But he was born a woman.
You can do that.
So it's not that he inspired me to transition or anything,
it's just, it was one of many moments
along my whole entire gender journey.
So I had positive feelings about Tran-pa,
that's what he calls himself,
from back then.
And then a few months ago,
when I was feeling angry and miserable and despised
over another time I was being canceled by trans Twitter,
we'll get to that one later,
I saw this post from Buck on Instagram.
And those were exactly the words I needed to hear
at that moment.
So I commented a heart and then Buck DMed me
and he said, I love you.
And I was like,
senpai noticed me.
And so I said, I love you back.
Then when I was working on Opulence,
I needed a voice actor to do a line from John Waters' book.
And it was my co-director Theron who suggested,
don't you think Buck Angel sounds kind of like John Waters?
And I said, well, he just messaged me on Insta,
let's see if he wants to do it.
And I just loved the idea of having Buck Angel
as John Waters in the video credits,
like a trans icon playing a gay icon.
In my head it was just so, well, iconic.
So I got in touch with Buck about the line
and he was like, yeah, I'd love to do it.
So here it is,
the 10 second voiceover clip that ruined a month of my life.
One must remember,
there is such a thing as good bad taste and bad bad taste.
To understand bad taste,
one must have very good taste.
That's it children.
That's why mommy's canceled.
Now I was aware at the time
that trans Twitter hate
and hated Buck Angel,
but my thinking was,
well, trans Twitter kind of hates every trans celebrity
and they certainly hate me.
So I wasn't going to let that stop me.
Little did I know,
quite how vicious things were about to get.
Now, so far I've been telling this story
from my point of view,
but I do want to give a fair and balanced account.
So I want to pause and contextualize
why some trans people hate Buck Angel so much,
they're willing to cancel anyone who even associates with him.
Basically it all goes back to this old debate
in the trans community known today
and Tumblr lingo as true scum versus trans trenders.
So true scum are trans people
who distinguish between true trans people
and fake trans people,
who they call trenders or too-cutes.
Usually true scum think that what it is to be trans
is to have a lifelong struggle with dysphoria,
to pursue a medical transition involving hormones and surgery,
and to socially re-assimilate into your target binary gender,
so male or female.
Anyone who's not that,
according to true scum,
must either be a confused teenager,
someone just trying to get attention,
someone mistaking their trauma or their fetish for being trans,
in a word, a trender.
So that's a vige of transness
that usually excludes non-binary people
as well as people who don't want to medically transition
for whatever reason,
and for that reason this view is sometimes also called
transmedicalism.
True scum obviously being the derogatory term for these people.
So true scum are very hated by a lot of trans people
because their viewpoint is that not all trans identities are valid,
and Buck Angel is widely perceived to be true scum.
So the next question to ask is,
is this true?
Is Buck Angel in fact true scum?
Now my honest answer to that question is,
I don't know.
He's certainly said some things that sound like things true scum say,
I'll give you that.
A point he likes to make a lot is that he's transsexual,
not transgender.
And the difference between those terms is sometimes defined as
transsexual implies that you want to pursue medical transition,
so hormones and surgery,
and transgender doesn't imply that.
And people associate this,
I'm transsexual not transgender thing with true scum
because true scum often call themselves transsexuals
and say that anyone who isn't a transsexual isn't really trans.
And often those people will be very mean to people they call trenders,
especially certain transmedicalist YouTubers like
Vanessa LeBlanc and Too Cute Smasher 9000.
Too Cute Smasher 9000.
Roast me back Calvin, I dare you.
But I think it's important to keep in mind that the term true scum
is a product of the 2014 Tumblr wars,
and trying to apply it to trans people of an older generation
can sometimes be misleading.
Like when Buck Angel transitioned,
the word transsexual was just the word for his identity,
and he still identifies that way.
So when younger trans people tell him it's wrong to use the word transsexual,
he feels like these ungrateful millennials are invalidating his identity.
And I do understand where he's coming from,
but I also understand why a lot of nonbinary people
are skeptical about Buck.
Like he says again and again,
I'm transsexual, not transgender,
like don't mix me up with those people.
And that eagerness to separate himself from transgender people,
it comes across as hostility.
Like I don't think he's ever actually said that nonbinary people aren't valid,
but I personally don't like that he seems like he wants to distance himself from them.
And that's my disagreement with Buck.
It's not that he invalidates nonbinary identities,
because I don't really care.
I don't really see him doing that.
And if he was doing that,
I would have seen it.
Because for the last two months,
a lot of people have been doing nothing but sending me problematic Buck Angel tweets.
But as someone who cares a lot about nonbinary people,
and who loves the nonbinary people in my life,
it does upset me when he does this distancing thing.
And I hope he listens to this criticism,
because I think it would be cool if he got better about this.
Of course, Buck is technically right that there are different kinds of trans people.
And I agree it's important that we can make those distinctions
and talk about the differences when they're relevant,
but I also think that as a community,
trans people benefit from unity,
not division.
Like if you have an employer who discriminates against trans people,
they're not going to care if you're transsexual,
transgender,
nonbinary,
or gender nonconforming.
They're going to discriminate against you regardless.
So we're all in this together.
And there's a lot of disagreements among us,
and we often don't get along so well.
But politically,
I think we should work together as much as possible
instead of splitting into little factions,
because we share most of the same interests.
And I think the best way to do that
is to build bridges instead of burning them.
And that's why I'm willing to work with people like Buck Angel,
who I have some disagreements with.
It creates a connection, you know?
And having that connection can lead to communication
and build understanding.
Also, I need all the connections I can get, Gorge.
I am very lonely.
It's not a joke.
It's true.
Now I get that some people have views that are so harmful
that giving them a platform is potentially dangerous.
But in any case,
I didn't even give Buck a platform to share his opinions.
I gave him a platform to be a John Waters impersonator.
A bunch of people on my subreddit were like,
why couldn't she just get John Waters to do those lines?
Well, first of all,
I don't actually know John,
but I just have a feeling he would write me off
as some kind of millennial SJW.
Like, why is Buck Angel canceled,
but John Waters isn't?
Well, because trans Twitter does not know who John Waters is.
And let's try to keep it that way.
I actually mentioned this to a friend of mine who knows John,
and he told me that he and John
have actually watched Buck Angel's porn together.
So, plot twist.
Okay, so trans Twitter won't forgive me
unless I condemn Buck Angel as true scum
and apologize for ever working with him.
But I'm not going to do that,
because I don't think it would be the right thing to do.
And doing it just to get myself uncancelled
would be cowardly.
I'm happy to tell you I absolutely disagree
with Buck's divisive rhetoric
about transsexual versus transgender.
I wish he would be an ally to the whole transgender umbrella
instead of trying to distance himself from the rest.
And I'm happy to hear out the perspective of nonbinary people
who don't trust him,
because I totally get where they're coming from
and I think that's valid.
But I also respect the decades of good activism
Buck Angel has done for trans people,
and I am grateful to him for that.
And in light of that,
I'm willing to give him the benefit of the doubt
about where his heart is,
and express my criticism in a more measured way
than just attacking who he is as a person.
But Twitter needs to establish that he's a horrible person,
because this is the strategy they've chosen to use
to establish that I am a horrible person.
And if the true scum allegation isn't strong enough to prove it,
oh they have other pieces of evidence to fall back on
to hold up their conclusion.
For example, here's a tweet claiming
Natalie's trying so fucking hard
to make it sound like the only thing Buck Angel ever did
was write a few iffy tweets,
and that's just so fucking far from the truth.
Dude launched a targeted tabloid harassment campaign
outing a trans woman against her will
with the specific intent of causing her physical, emotional,
and professional harm.
The shorter way of saying that
is that he wanted to make her suffer,
and she very well could have been killed.
Yikes.
This ain't it, chief.
Friendly reminder that this isn't a good look.
Maybe don't try to get trans women killed.
Disappointing.
It sounds pretty serious.
Let's investigate.
Here's what I've managed to piece together.
Scene one.
The year is 2003.
Los Angeles,
where the movie world,
the porn world,
and the BDSM scene come together
in a tale of heartbreak,
betrayal,
and transsexualism.
La La Land.
Dramatis Personae.
Buck Angel,
transsexual porn star.
Ilsa Strix,
dominatrix,
then wife of Buck Angel.
Lana Wachowski,
wildly successful director of The Matrix,
at the time not yet out as a transgender woman.
The synopsis is that Ilsa Strix and Buck Angel's marriage ended
after Ilsa had an affair with Lana Wachowski,
who was not yet out as trans.
So Buck was understandably upset about the affair,
and in what seems like a petty act of revenge,
told a series of magazines
that this celebrity director Wachowski
was a cross-dresser who had stolen his wife,
which I guess was the information he had at the time.
So is that outing a trans woman against her will?
Well in retrospect it seems like it,
though that may not be what he thought he was doing at the time.
But to really get to the bottom of this,
we have to do some digging.
We have to trawl through the dirty details
of trans people's personal histories,
which I've noticed is one of the internet's favorite activities.
So I actually went on eBay
and I purchased Rolling Stone issue 991 January 2006,
and I'm finally able to reveal
that the seller cancelled the order.
God damn it!
But I was finally able to track down and translate
a Spanish version of the Rolling Stone article
from the Wayback Machine,
and I'm finally able to expose the truth.
Stop.
Freeze exactly where you are.
Take a look at yourself
and what all of us have been doing
for the last 30 seconds.
Who does this behavior remind you of?
If your answer is social justice advocates
fighting for trans equality,
you are incorrect.
If your answer is creepy stalkers who hate trans people,
I am very suspicious of anyone
whose online behavior prompts me
to dig through articles full of dead names
and sordid scandals involving trans people
from almost two decades ago.
This is very similar to techniques
used against trans people by internet fascists.
So I'm pretty suspicious of anyone
pushing this kind of investigation.
How can you tell the difference
between a trans anarcho-socialist
with an anime avatar
and a Nazi pretending to be
a trans anarcho-socialist with an anime avatar?
Well, you can't.
Anonymous is anonymous is anonymous,
whether it's on 4chan or Twitter.
So unless Buck Angel, Ilsa Strix,
or Lana Wachowski gets in touch with me
and lets me know that for some unimaginable reason
they want me to publicly dig up
their 17-year-old divorce drama,
this is none of my fucking business.
And it's none of yours either,
so shut up and go back to Kiwi Farms
where you belong.
Let's Irish up this tea.
Doesn't work as well with tea.
So, setting aside any tabloid drama
that may have happened during the Bush administration,
I'm saying this in the cuntiest way,
and they deserve it.
They fucking deserve the cuntiness.
I'm spilling whiskey tea all over my goddamn bathroom.
I'm a lady.
She's a woman.
The main argument against me
usually references a collage
of Buck Angel's problematic tweets.
And this is supposed to be definitive evidence
that he is a horrible person,
and therefore,
that I am a horrible person
for collaborating with him.
Well, here's the thing, though.
A collage of problematic tweets
does not define a person.
And I'm very used to being defined that way myself,
so I know how unfair it can be.
Before I ever collaborated with Buck Angel,
a lot of people on Twitter
were already calling me truscum.
That's been going on a year and a half now.
And anytime my name comes up on Twitter,
a bunch of people respond saying
Natalie is truscum,
Natalie is a transmedicalist,
Natalie hates nonbinary people,
and you should really think
what kind of message you're sending
to your trans and nonbinary followers
by platforming her.
And if the person defends me
or argues back in any way,
they say,
I can't believe you're ignoring
the valid concerns of marginalized people.
You know, they're weaponizing
their marginalized status as trans people
to isolate and attack
another trans person.
And sometimes this stuff gets to my head, too.
I start asking myself,
wait, am I a transmedicalist?
Do I really believe all these awful things
they say I believe?
But the answer is,
no.
I just don't.
These things they're saying about me
are 100% not true.
You know, believe marginalized people
is a norm that is encouraged
in leftist spaces for good reason,
much like believe victims
or believe women.
And these norms were established
to counterbalance the mainstream tendency,
which is not to listen
to marginalized people
or to victims
or to women.
But any norm can be abused.
And the blunt fact of the matter is,
sometimes marginalized people are wrong.
Sometimes people calling themselves victims
are obscuring a more complicated situation.
And it's even happened once or twice
that a woman has lied.
And the accusation that I'm truscum
is simply false.
I mean, first of all,
I don't even think of my own transgenderism
as a medical disorder,
much less everyone else's.
I have, of course, collaborated with Dr. Spiegel
at all,
but I will not have my artistry
reduced to mere medicine.
Second,
this accusation that I hate non-binary people
is just...
no.
Non.
Eh...
My thinking about trans identity
has always been informed by non-binary people.
I used to identify as non-binary myself
before I medically transitioned,
and some of the closest people to me
in my life today
are non-binary trans people,
some of whom are also transsexuals, incidentally.
It's complicated.
I've also made at least five videos on this channel
arguing for the validity of non-binary gender identities
going back more than three years.
So that's five out of around 50 videos,
or 10% of the content I've made on this channel,
is about non-binary identity.
A few months ago,
I even made a 30-minute video called TransTrenders,
which uses character dialogue to show
what I think are the shortcomings of transmedicalism.
But there's still hundreds of people on Twitter
saying that I'm truscum who hates non-binary people.
And their main piece of evidence for that
is a collage of my problematic tweets.
So let's take a look at that.
Here's the three tweets
that I usually see scrapbooked together
as definitive proof that I hate non-binary people.
This is the first one,
from September 2018.
Notice how it's taken out of context from the thread
so you can't even see what I'm talking about.
I'm sure this is not the experience of many NBs
.
I leave it to them to articulate
what NB existence looks like in a binary world.
I do not and I cannot speak for them.
But surely N-
God, I used to write like such a nerd.
The account that begins and ends
with I'm not a man because I don't identify as one
is pretty weak.
Okay, when I wrote the Twitter thread
that that tweet has been clipped out of,
I was defending myself from accusations
that my most recent video at the time,
The Aesthetic,
was anti-non-binary.
In that video,
there's a character named Justine
who defends a version of the performativity theory of gender.
And basically I made this video
to express some angst I was feeling
about the pressures of transitioning in the public eye.
This was a very one-year-on-hormones moment for me,
and I've already moved on in my thinking.
At that time I was very, um,
my behavior must be perfectly feminine at all times
or else I'm not really a woman.
My self-esteem is totally based on sleeping with heterosexual men
who resemble my father.
And anyone who knows anything about trans women knows
that most of us go through a stage like this at some point.
And some YouTubers never get out of it.
But personally, I mean these days,
it doesn't matter what I wear.
It's when I dream they're Lily's dreams.
Dragging the Danish girl.
Well, fuck the Danish.
I could never abide that sort of person.
We all know what I'm talking about.
You can tell the whiskey is getting to me
because I'm being bigoted against the Danish.
These things come out, you know.
You get honest, you get real
when you get a little bit of the Irish in your system.
Did I just fucking put lipstick outside the fucking lip liner?
This is all Lily's fault.
Lily Alba.
Fuck her dreams.
The point is, when I was making the aesthetic,
I wasn't even thinking about non-binary people.
And people will say that the fact that not every video I make
references non-binary people is itself NB-phobic.
As I've said, about one in ten of my videos
is about non-binary identity.
But not all of them are.
And I feel entitled to make some videos
that are just about trans women.
But still, some people on Twitter were saying
that the character Justine is a transmedicalist.
And because she maybe wins the fictional debate in the video,
I, Natalie Nguyen, am therefore a transmedicalist.
Here's the thing, though.
The performativity theory of gender,
the one that Justine defends in that video,
is conceptually as far away from transmedicalism
as it is possible to be.
Transmedicalism says that trans identity is biological,
it's neurological, it's hormonal,
it's diagnosable and treatable.
Whereas performativity says that gender is gesture,
it's expression, it's performance,
it's a social phenomenon.
Phenomenon. Phenomenon. Phenomenon. Phenomenon.
Phenomenon.
Performativity makes no reference to gender dysphoria
or to any kind of medical concept at all.
So whereas transmedicalism is a kind of bioessentialism,
performativity is a kind of social constructionism.
So these are exact opposite theories of gender,
are you following along, class?
I'm not.
I'm ready to drink Jameson tea until I die.
But some trans people felt invalidated
by things Justine says in that video.
And transmedicalism is another thing
that makes them feel invalidated.
So they decided that Justine is a transmedicalist
and therefore that I am a transmedicalist.
And this is literally just bad media comprehension.
Like it's a failure to plausibly interpret a video
that some people did find genuinely emotionally difficult.
And so much of the negative response to that video
is just pure emotion.
I always hear,
I don't care what you intended,
trans people were hurt by that video.
You hurt trans people.
But here's the thing.
Just because you were hurt by content I made
doesn't mean that the content is bad
or that I'm victimizing you in some way.
I'll give you an example.
I did a stream a couple years ago
with a BDSM and kink activist.
We were talking about various kinks
and we got to DDLG,
which is Daddy Dom Little Girl.
Basically, when consenting adults roleplay age difference
and the power dynamic that comes with that.
And me and this kink activist
were just casually discussing what DDLG is,
what it isn't,
when I noticed someone in the chat
was starting to totally freak out.
They were typing in all caps like,
MY ABUSER USED DDLG TO JUSTIFY RAPING ME.
WHY ARE YOU DEFENDING MY ABUSER?
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'D BETRAY ME LIKE THIS.
PLEASE STOP TAKING MONEY
FROM MY ABUSER'S SIDE.
PLEASE STOP.
I'M BEGGING YOU.
This was actually really fucking upsetting to me
because this person was clearly in a lot of pain.
They were having a panic attack
because they were having a trauma trigger reaction
to this conversation.
And I kept telling them to leave the stream
and take care of themselves,
but they wouldn't do it.
So I had to block them
and then later get in touch
and make sure they were okay.
Now, was their pain very real?
Yes.
Was it triggered
by the content I was streaming?
Yes.
But does that mean I did anything wrong?
No.
Is it wrong to talk about kink
in contexts where it's clear
you're going to be talking about kink?
No.
But when you produce content online
that's going to be viewed by thousands
or millions of people,
there's always some people out there
who are going to be hurt by it.
So if you want to argue that a tweet
or a video I made is somehow immoral,
I think you need more of an argument
than just,
people were hurt.
Alright, back to the tweet.
To this day,
people quote tweet the sentence,
but surely an account that begins and ends
with I'm not a man
because I don't identify as one
is pretty weak.
And they claim this is evidence
that I'm true scum
or that I think people have to prove
their identities somehow,
which is not at all
what I was saying in that thread.
What I was saying is
if you're trying to persuade a skeptic
that trans identity is valid,
simply saying I'm not a man
because I don't identify as one
isn't a very good argument,
which it isn't.
I mean, no one has ever been persuaded by that
so far as I'm aware.
That said,
I do now disagree with the mindset
I had when I tweeted this.
Back then, I still delusionally believed
that it was possible to rationally explain
why trans identity is valid,
and I was simply looking for
a more persuasive argument than,
this is how I identify,
you have to believe me,
no further questions.
But I no longer believe there can be
any rational justification of gender identity,
which is another reason
I'm not a transmedicalist.
Transmedicalism tries to be a rational theory
about why trans identity is valid,
and I don't think it succeeds as that.
I don't think anything does.
My current opinion about this is that
I'm not a man because I don't identify as one
is as good, or rather as bad,
an argument as any.
You know, some things in life just
can't be rationally explained.
Like love.
Why do you love the person you love?
Well, because you love them.
You could write a poem about it,
or some gay shit like that,
but you can't give any actual arguments.
And why am I a woman?
Because I'm a woman.
That's it.
I mean, I can describe my experiences
and my feelings to you
to help you understand better,
but I can't logically prove anything.
And I'm super fucking sorry
if you can't handle that mankind
was set adrift in an absurd world.
That must be super fucking hard for you.
Tell me all about it.
Next please.
Okay, again we're mid-thread
with missing context,
but the tweet says,
whereas I've met 20-year-olds
in full-on boy mode who are like,
hi, I'm a trans woman.
She, her pronouns.
So, I guess by including this tweet
in the ContraPoints' problematic collage,
people are implying that I don't think
it's valid for someone who presents male
to identify as a woman
and request she, her pronouns.
Well, that's not true.
I was surprised when I first experienced this,
but I think it's valid.
Next.
Okay, mid-thread, no context,
once again.
But now you go into these leftist Discord
slash Facebook groups
and like 20-30% identify as some flavor of trans.
Most of them are not conventional binary transsexuals.
That seems to be the future.
Okay, well,
it's true that many leftist Discord servers
are like this.
But reading this back,
I don't like the way the phrase
conventional binary transsexuals
is hitting my ear.
I can see how it could imply that
non-binary identities are somehow newfangled,
which isn't true.
There's been non-binary people for longer
than there's been medical transsexuals,
in fact,
so we'll call this a bad tweet.
I apologize for tweeting it,
and I apologize to any non-binary people
who felt trivialized by it.
Okay, this is the big one.
This tweet got its own article
in the fucking Guardian.
You know, I really wish people
would pay less attention to the tweets
I spend 30 seconds writing
and a little more attention to the videos
that I spend, you know,
hundreds of hours making.
Anyway, let's look at the tweet.
This is the most scrutinized paragraph
I've ever written,
and it's so mediocre.
This has happened to me before
in hyper-woke spaces.
Like, it's me and a bunch of cis women,
and we all have to go in a circle
saying she, her, because I'm there.
There's this paradox
where I can go to a sports bar
in North Carolina
and be Miss Mamed all night,
no question.
But in self-consciously trans-inclusive spaces,
I have to explain my pronouns
and watch woke people
awkwardly correct themselves
every time they say,
you guys.
I guess it's good for people
who use they, them only
and want only gender-neutral language,
but it comes at the minor expense
of semi-passable transes like me,
and that's super fucking hard for us.
So people interpreted this tweet
as me being against the practice
of sharing pronouns,
which I'm literally just not.
Like, I've actually been the person
who initiates the pronoun circle
many times.
The backstory of this tweet
is basically that
I once got triggered
in a situation
where I was with a bunch of cis women
and we all had to go around
saying our pronouns,
and like a typical triggered tranny,
I tiptoed over to Twitter
to tip-top type it out.
But here's the thing,
by the end of this thread,
I had already talked myself away
from the initial frustration
I was expressing.
If you know my videos and my voice,
then you know me saying
it comes at the minor expense
of semi-passable transes
and that's super fucking hard for us
is sarcastic.
It's a minor expense
It's not actually very hard
for us, Gorge.
It's fine.
But people on Twitter
don't watch my videos
and they don't get sarcasm.
So people flipped out over this.
I was getting dragged
and I made the poor decision
to try to solve the tweet problem
with more tweeting,
which 100% of the time
is like trying to put out a fire
with lighter fluid.
So me and my dumb brain
did another short thread
trying to clarify what I was saying
and defending my right
to talk about my own experiences.
That didn't make things any better.
So in a state of anger and frustration,
I tweeted out yet another thread.
And this time I said
some truly stupid things,
including the now infamous line.
I sometimes feel like the last
of the old school transsexuals.
I honestly don't know what the fuck
I was even trying to say.
I don't feel like the last
of the old school transsexuals.
I don't even know what that means.
I guess I basically meant that
offline, I don't have any radical aspirations.
You know, I want to be inconspicuous.
I want to blend in.
And that's what I meant by old school.
You know, I want people to assume my pronouns.
You know, it's funny because
it is very different from the way I am online
where I'm totally shameless and open.
I'm like,
sexual confession, everybody.
Sexual confession.
I have abnormal urges.
It's 1am.
My name is Amy.
My neighbors can definitely hear that.
They know I have abnormal urges now.
They already knew that.
But offline, I'm an inconspicuous pussy,
like a total coward.
So,
this was a rage thread
and I apologize for tweeting it.
Let's go back to Bug Angel.
I'm kind of a conscientious objector
to the practice of condemning someone
based on a collage of their worst tweets
taken out of context.
But I definitely do have anxiety about this.
Like, I think I'm doing the right thing
by not condemning Buck as true scum and evil,
but I mean, I could be wrong.
What if I am basically sacrificing myself
for the sake of a person who really is
as bad as Twitter says?
Maybe tomorrow he'll tweet,
fuck non-binary people,
and then I'll have fucked up.
This whole thing is incredibly stressful to me.
But I do believe that by refusing to participate
in the anti-Buck Angel pilot,
I am erring on the morally safer side of things.
Because even if he is a little true scummy,
excommunicating him from the trans community
is still probably not the best approach to take.
In my experience,
when people accept binary but not non-binary trans people,
it usually takes like a 30 minute conversation
to win them over to some level of non-binary acceptance.
And I'll give you a couple examples.
The first time I was ever canceled,
like totally trashed on Twitter,
was back in 2017,
when I had not yet medically transitioned,
and at the time I identified as non-binary.
And at VidCon 2017,
I met up with a YouTuber named June,
who had made some videos where she basically
mocked the idea of non-binary people.
And I posted a picture of the brunch I had with June,
and some other people,
but let's keep them out of it.
And people on Twitter totally dragged me
for being a peak liberal bootlicker
who's best friends with transphobic abusers.
Christ.
Fucking people, man.
It's so fucking frustrating.
And, you know,
I'm not gonna claim I changed June's mind,
because I don't know what her thought process was,
but I did talk to her about non-binary identity,
and she did remove her anti-non-binary videos.
And I don't have any regrets about that brunch.
Example two.
A couple months later,
I did a livestream with a conservative trans woman YouTuber
named...
What was her name?
Sharon?
Was it Sharon?
I guess she's just not a very memorable person.
Anyway, she had made some videos saying
that non-binary identities aren't real.
But I gave her a chance,
and she surprised me
by being super compassionate and thoughtful.
By the end of that stream,
she was pretty much totally accepting of my identity.
So again,
the point is not that I'm some kind of persuasive genius.
If I was a persuasive genius,
maybe I could talk myself out of being canceled.
The point is that sometimes,
people who seem ignorant or hate me,
just need to be given a non-judgmental space
to learn and grow and think.
And to just condemn them as hopeless bigots
actually prevents that growth from happening.
And Sharon,
despite her, you know,
totally forgettable personality,
turned out to be an incredibly open-minded person.
Like later on,
she actually made an apology video to non-binary people,
and I became good friends with her.
And we worked together on most of the videos I've made this year.
You know,
until she ruined my life
by recommending a canceled John Waters impersonator.
I guess the moral is,
NEVER
talk to people you disagree with.
It will only lead to pain.
I do think there's something off with my hormone dose.
Like,
I'm crying three times a day.
Oh, and I can't cum unless there's vibrators
in at least three of my holes.
It happens like once a month.
There has to be a full moon.
I honestly only still bother
because it numbs the pain for a few moments.
What I'm trying to say is,
I really do believe in conversation,
which means hearing out multiple perspectives.
I don't want my audience to get all their information
about trans people from me,
and I think it's important to listen to criticism.
So I encourage my audience to go watch
some non-binary YouTubers
who have criticized me and criticized Buck Angel.
For example,
go check out non-binary YouTuber Luxander's video about me,
and non-binary YouTuber Corviday's video about Buck Angel.
I think YouTube, as a platform,
is better at producing criticism
rather than canceling.
And I think that's because,
at least in the vlog format,
making a video forces you to confront the fact
that you're a human being with a face and a name
who can be held accountable for the things that you say.
But people on Twitter,
it's a different story.
And I think it's time we take a look
at what canceling really is.
I've given you enough context now
for you to understand what I'm about to show you,
which is what I saw on my timeline every day
for nearly a month.
All these tweets are from the aftermath
of my uploading Opulence,
two months ago,
when the Buck Angel scandal first broke.
And someone better hold my hand now,
because this gets ugly.
Hey, if any of you still support ContraPoints
after her bigging up and collaborating
with notable TERF favorite and true scum Buck Angel,
you're no friend to gender non-conforming,
non-passing, and non-binary trans people.
Fuck her,
and fuck her fucking rift.
I am absolutely furious right now.
Weird how I'm 30 and trans,
and manage not to be a true scum.
Maybe I'm just some kind of anomaly.
Or maybe ContraPoints is a conniving rat fucking capo
who could do with a fully wound backhand to the mouth.
Since I'm out of Twitter jail now,
I just want to say,
fuck ContraPoints,
her sycophantic stans,
and all her bread tube chums
who close ranks to protect her
after she throws the rest of the trans community
under the bus for profit.
Natalie Nguyen is a fucking grifter.
ContraPoints' videos are now just style over substance,
so that explains why she took to TERF ideology so well.
ContraPoints working with true scum,
now definitively proves
that pretty much everyone defending ContraPoints
just hates enbies,
and are also true scum.
Legit gonna start on following peeps
that continue to follow ContraPoints at this point.
Do know my wording of pretty much everyone.
I know there are some
that were probably blindsided by this somehow.
So long as you know that ContraPoints is true scum,
you're safe and cool.
Eat shit, Natalie.
For someone who used to identify as genderqueer,
we expected more from you,
but I guess when your head's this far up your own ass,
it's hard to consider others.
ContraPoints, more like DisaPoints.
That's a good one.
If you're gonna drag me, at least be funny.
Fuck Buck Angel.
Fuck ContraPoints.
Fuck any real transsexual.
Fuck your grift.
Here's what hashtag ContraPoints stands don't understand.
If Natalie refuses to accept
that she has an apology to make,
and continues profiting from it,
it will become our responsibility
to work on deplatforming her
just like every other racist, sexist,
bigoted content creator.
No one has actually suggested or attempted
to actually cancel her,
but the longer this goes on without an apology
and commitment to do better,
the stronger the case becomes
for actively working to deplatform her.
So, in other words,
no one has suggested we cancel her,
but we should cancel her.
Great.
Can everyone finally agree
that ContraPoints belongs directly inside a garbage can?
Here I am, sweetie.
ContraPoints collaborating with Angel Buck.
Angel Buck.
Thanks for letting us all know
that you had no idea who he even was
until Twitter notified you what to be outraged about.
ContraPoints collaborating with Angel Buck,
a transmedicalist who once outed a trans person
to try and destroy them,
and supporting him because
he looks and sounds like a proper man,
isn't a small, itty-bitty, tipsy-topsy fucking mistake.
This is a huge deal.
ContraPoints could be literally collaborating with Hitler.
We have a Hitler comparison.
We could be literally collaborating with Hitler today.
And you all would be like,
oh, well, she's just a little flawed, you know.
Fuck off.
Can Natalie Wynne stop being a coward
and commit to being a transmed?
It's really tiring to watch this happen every week.
Natalie Wynne is a spoiled brat
who refuses to take accountability.
Anyone who supports Natalie Wynne
does not support nonbinary people.
Natalie Wynne is such a terrible person.
My God.
Every cis and not nonbinary person
who thought Natalie Wynne wasn't transmed
now owes me and every nonbinary person $50.
Joe Biden has a better position on the validity
of nonbinary gender than ContraPoints.
My opinion is that ContraPoints really sucks a lot
and I don't like her.
I hate ContraPoints so goddamn much
it's unbelievable.
ContraPoints be like,
let's hear some nonbinary people.
This is a very good impression of me.
You're doing very good, sweetie.
You're doing very, very good.
Buck Angel is a TERF apologizer,
bootlicker, and true scum.
Any association with him
must be seen as hostile
to the trans community as a whole,
let alone denial of nonbinary existence.
That's the line in the sand, folks.
Where do you stand?
And here we fucking are, dude.
Buck fucking Angel on ContraPoints.
Eat my entire ass.
What?
This is Natalie.
Natalie is a transmedicalist.
This is Natalie's friend Lindsay.
Lindsay is a leftuber.
Natalie and Lindsay are still friends
because Natalie and Lindsay
are both cowards.
Leftuber's a griff.
Oh, and they made me the man.
The shade.
Issues that arose with
being in Contra's new video.
Her video on TERFs make no sense now.
Her video on trans trenders make no sense now.
You know, if your interpretation of why I cast Buck Angel
totally contradicts the videos
I've spent hundreds of hours making,
do you think maybe your interpretation could be wrong?
Apparently not.
Her apology is completely void.
Sends a message that she hates non-binary people.
She is reckless with her content.
Positives that arose from Buck Angel being in Contra's new video.
She, uh, has $400,000 this month from Patreon.
$400,000.
This number is completely made up.
Like, it is exponentially wrong.
$400,000.
$400,000 a month.
Hot take.
ContraPoints is the leftist PewDiePie.
Personally, I like to characterize her
as the blair-white wolf in leftist sheep's clothing.
Reminder that ContraPoints is a piece of shit
who still has not apologized for platforming truescum
and is actively taking their side.
Anyway, if you still support ContraPoints,
get the hell away from me.
Pee-pee-poo-poo, I'm ContraPoints
and I can't stop being a transmedicalist
and shitting myself in public.
Valid criticisms of marginalized people.
Fuck ContraPoints.
Fuck truescum.
ContraPoints is a truescum.
You know, when you repeat the same fucking sentence
over and over again, it does...
You know when you repeat the same sentence over and over again,
it actually doesn't get more persuasive.
In fact, it might get less persuasive.
Because true things usually only have to be said once.
If you still support ContraPoints,
then follow me immediately and never interact with me again.
In conclusion, fuck Natalie Nguyen
and fuck everything she has to say.
Okay, let's get started.
So, that was just a sample of hundreds and hundreds of tweets.
And all of this, let me remind you,
is over a ten second voiceover clip
in a 48 minute video
about a completely unrelated topic.
Like, how do you work?
How do you create
when a decision so trivial
can become the main event for weeks of your life?
And the tweets are just the beginning.
After that, there's the Reddit threads,
and the YouTube comments,
and the Facebook discourse,
and the Medium posts,
and the Newsweek article.
Opulence is a video
me and Theron spent hundreds of hours
carefully piecing together.
I think it's my best video.
And to have the response to it
completely overwhelmed by one minor casting decision
is heartbreaking and infuriating to me.
And it's left me with much less energy
to create new things.
But here's the thing,
people on Twitter saying mean things about me
is not the worst of it.
Not even close.
Like, I'm a politically opinionated trans woman
who publicly transitioned
while making anti-fascist content
on a notoriously right-wing platform.
Sweaty, I am so used to reading
mean things about myself online,
most of you probably can't even begin to imagine
how used to it I am.
And the way you psychologically survive in that situation
is you block the people and platforms
who are harassing you,
and you pay it no mind.
But there's some things you can't block.
And a big one is you can't block people
from going after your friends and colleagues.
And that is exactly what people did to me
at the height of the Buck Angel incident.
Lindsay Ellis,
Ollie from Philosophy Tube,
and Hbomberguy
all got inundated with tweets
demanding that they publicly disown me,
a person they've all been friends with for years,
or else.
In response to demands that she apologize,
Lindsay released a statement where she said,
I was not involved in Opulence.
My name was mentioned in it,
but I did not participate in the production.
Therefore, with regards to calls for me to apologize,
I have to ask, apologize for what?
There is only one logical answer.
Apologize for being friends with Natalie.
And here's a response to her statement.
I don't need to consider you my fucking friend
to disagree with beliefs you knowingly solicit
or allow on your platform.
Same with Contra.
It just means you're willing to allow awful ideas
to fester for the sake of financial gain,
which is fine,
but it makes you a piece of shit.
And here's a comment at Hbomberguy.
I doubt that you were going to read this,
but can you please just tell us your thoughts
on that whole situation
so we could at least know that you were on our side?
We don't want to have to cancel all of y'all
and cause BreadTube to go into a schism
as a result of this.
Thank you.
Nice YouTube channel you have there, friend.
Would be a shame if someone canceled it.
So fucking sinister.
Oli of PhilosophyTube released his own statement
affirming his support of non-binary people,
but adding,
Sadly, I've also been harassed, threatened, doxxed,
had my private life speculated on
and my loved ones insulted,
and recognizing the feelings of those
who kindly raised their concerns in a polite way,
I do not wish to legitimize the great many people
who use their hurt as a cover
for unacceptable toxic and abusive behavior.
And here are some responses to Oli.
As a non-binary fan of yours,
I'm disappointed in this non-apology.
Again, what exactly is he supposed to be apologizing for?
Ever having associated with me?
Things we are going to criticize Oli PhilosophyTube for.
Being a sniveling hypocritical piece of shit.
Refusing to listen to trans people.
Actively, openly, and repeatedly mocking the trans people
he refuses to listen to.
Thanks for the apology.
Now stop endorsing contrapoints.
Now keep in mind that what these Twitter people are doing
is demanding that cis people publicly condemn
a trans woman for loosely associating with another trans person.
Does that strike anyone else as wildly inappropriate?
Even Mia Mulder,
a trans woman who has never publicly associated with me,
got attacked because she tweeted a heart at Oli.
You know, after he made the post discussing being doxxed and threatened.
And just for that, she gets put on the enemy list.
I'm sad to say that Mia is on the list
of people that have stood by contrapoints
as she has continued to be a bigoted piece of shit.
To which Mia responds,
stood by contrapoints?
Jesus Christ.
No matter what I do, people call me out
and I'm not even related to the video
and I don't even know Natalie.
The chain of guilt by association
is so long and twisted,
I can barely even follow it.
So they're going after Mia,
who tweeted a heart at Oli,
who failed to condemn me
for my voiceover casting of Buck Angel,
who was retweeted by a TERF.
We're only missing a couple degrees of separation
before every living person on the planet Earth
is cancelled over the Buck Angel situation.
And several colleagues of mine, by the way,
Lindsay, Harry, Oli,
they all took a financial hit.
They've all lost some Patreon support.
One of Lindsay's former supporters
even demanded a $38 lifetime refund,
saying,
Dear Lindsay,
I'm sorry for being pushy,
but I really am going to be needing a refund.
I gave money to your operation
under the pretense
that you wouldn't do anything morally objectionable,
and supporting contrapoints
and blaming us for taking issue with that
is, in my opinion, amoral.
Please respond.
I hope she sent it to them in pennies.
So look,
I'm very grateful to my colleagues
for sticking by me through all this,
but I'm also aware that I'm becoming a burden
to anyone who associates with me.
I have no collaborators in this video.
I'm working on this totally alone
because I'm aware of how radioactive I am right now,
and I don't want to contaminate anyone else.
During the height of this most recent cancelling,
a creator I admire DMed me to let me know,
I cut the shout out to you in my last video
because I was nervous
to draw the ire of your detractors
who are getting genuinely scary,
but I wouldn't want you to think I was disavowing you,
regardless of how many people are asking me to.
Jesus Christ.
The situation here is that any cis person who defends me,
or even associates with me in any way,
will be labeled a transphobe.
Any binary trans person who associates with me
will be branded an enbyphobe.
And any non-binary people who associate with me
will be ostracized from their own community.
So on the internet,
I find myself increasingly alone.
I'm isolated by the harassment.
And that is ultimately the point.
To exile me from my community,
from any community.
And it's all because I refuse to participate
in doing exactly that to Buck Angel.
My experiences have made me so disillusioned
with the idea that social media callouts
can lead to any kind of justice
that I've essentially sworn off participating in them.
There's a fairly prominent figure in leftist politics
who I could absolutely hashtag immediately.
But I'm never going to do it.
Because I have no faith left
in the process of callout vigilante justice.
And I'm not saying I'm totally against meetooing people,
because I think in some cases,
it totally is the brave and admirable thing to do.
But in my case,
I feel like I just know too much
about the dark side of social media shaming
to ever want to participate in it again.
You know, I feel like the story would end up being
taken out of my control,
warped and twisted in all kinds of unpredictable ways.
It would end up just haunting me.
It would end up just haunting both me
and the person I'd be accusing,
which in this case,
honestly,
neither of us deserves.
So I'm just not willing to take that risk.
Except maybe in some very extreme situation,
which this just isn't.
It's not worth it.
And likewise,
when a mob is at my doorstep
demanding I condemn Buck Angel
to save myself from cancellation,
no!
I'm just not going to do that.
I'm a conscientious objector.
I'm willing to go to Twitter jail for this.
Take me away, boys.
If there's one thing I can't stand,
it's bread tube videos.
Part eight and a half.
The philosophy of being fucked in the ass.
Ugh.
I have done this to YouTube.
And I'm sorry.
So look,
canceling is not criticism.
It is not holding someone accountable.
It is an attack
on a human being.
In this video,
I use the word canceling
more or less synonymously
with what feminist Jo Freeman,
author of The Bitch Manifesto,
calls
trashing.
And I've linked her essay,
The Dark Side of Sisterhood,
in the description.
It was originally published
in Ms. Magazine in 1976,
but it is a perfect description
of what goes on on trans Twitter today.
It is not disagreement.
It is not conflict.
It is not opposition.
These are perfectly ordinary phenomena
which,
when engaged in mutually,
honestly,
and not excessively,
are necessary to keep an organism
or organization healthy and active.
Trashing is a particularly vicious form
of character assassination
which amounts to psychological rape.
It is manipulative,
dishonest,
and excessive.
It is occasionally disguised
by the rhetoric of honest conflict
or covered up by denying
that any disapproval exists at all.
But it is not done
to expose disagreements
or resolve differences.
It is done
to disparage and destroy.
Whatever methods are used,
trashing involves a violation
of one's integrity,
a declaration of one's worthlessness,
and an impugning of one's motives.
In effect,
what is attacked is not one's actions
or one's ideas,
but one's self.
And that's what distinguishes
trashing,
bullying,
or abuse
from criticism
or holding accountable.
Criticism attacks your actions or beliefs.
But when people are canceling me,
they're not bringing up
my problematic tweets
because they want me
to revise my beliefs.
No.
What they're doing
is accumulating evidence
to support the case
they've decided to make
that I am a horrible person
who must be shunned.
You know, the only sense
in which I am,
as they like to say,
the new Blair White,
is that I think I actually have now
snatched Vanessa's crown
as the most hated Tran
on Tran Twitter.
Vanessa, I'm trying to feud with you.
Feud with me, goddammit.
You can't have a one-sided feud.
I don't want to be one of those
trans YouTubers
that just drags other trans people all day
and they never respond.
That would be really pathetic.
The new Lacey Green.
That's the other one.
The newest in a series of women
you've decided to treat like supervillains.
Maybe reflect on that habit a little bit, hmm?
And supervillain is the right word.
Like, I'm the bad guy.
Duh.
I'm the enemy.
And what do you do with the enemy?
Well, you disavow,
disown,
deplatform,
and destroy.
As that one tweet put it,
that's the line in the sand, folks.
Where do you stand?
If you adequately demonstrate
your searing hatred of Natalie Wynne,
then you're safe and cool.
But if you don't,
you're on the wrong side of the line, sweaty.
And you, too, are now the enemy.
Cancel culture trope seven.
Dualism.
Certain ancient religions
teach their followers
to understand the cosmos
as a struggle
between light and dark,
good and evil.
And cancel culture
does more or less the same thing.
It's binary thinking.
People are either good
or they're bad.
And to add to that,
essentialism.
If a person says or does a bad thing,
we should interpret that
as the mask slipping,
as a momentary glimpse
of their essential wickedness.
And anyone who wants to remain good
had better be willing
to publicly condemn
anyone the community
has decided is bad.
There really is something
dystopian about this.
You have to be willing
to accuse other people
to prove your own innocence.
That's the line in the sand, folks.
Where do you stand?
In the most extreme version of this,
all bad people are equally bad.
So collaborating with true scum
means you may as well be true scum.
And of course,
being true scum
is tantamount to being a TERF.
And on trans Twitter,
it is a known fact
that TERFs
are Nazis.
And this implies that Nazis,
TERFs,
true scum,
people who associate
with true scum,
people who fail to condemn
people who associate
with true scum,
people who offer emotional support
to people who fail to condemn
people who associate
with true scum,
all of them must be treated
the same way.
De-platform her
just like every other racist,
sexist,
bigoted content creator.
A fully wound backhand
to the mouth.
I recently read a book
by Sarah Schulman
called Conflict Is Not Abuse.
Overstating harm,
community responsibility,
and the duty of repair.
Basically,
Schulman's argument
is that in various contexts,
from romantic relationships
to community infighting
to international politics,
the overstatement of harm
is used as a justification
for cruelty
and for escalating conflict.
So for example,
and this is my example,
not Schulman's,
TERFs fixate
on the exaggerated danger
that trans women supposedly pose
to cis women.
And in very classic
overstatement of harm,
they'll describe everything
they don't like
as rape.
Trans women entering
women's spaces
is rape.
Trans women existing,
Janice Raymond,
is rape.
And then they use
that exaggerated harm
as a justification
to retaliate against them,
to dox and harass and shun.
Well, the same kind of logic
is used to justify
abusive behavior
within the trans community.
The dualistic thinking,
the essentialism,
the pseudo-moralism.
All of this allows people
on Twitter
to treat me
in an obviously abusive way,
all the while feeling
like they're doing the right thing
because they're attacking
the enemy.
And I realize that some people
will say that I'm the one
who's overstating harm
to evade criticism.
Well look,
you've seen the tweets,
the furious demands
for me to be exiled,
the doxing and threatening
and ordering around
of my colleagues,
the attempts to isolate me
from my community,
the attacks not on my actions
but on who I am as a person.
There's not really anything
ambiguous about this,
it's just abuse.
But I don't think it feels
like abuse to the people
who are doing it.
They feel like they're punching up
because I'm a celebrity
with a platform
and lots of Twitter followers.
And it's true that I do have more power
than any of them individually.
But as a collective,
they have a terrifying power
that they don't seem to be aware of
as individuals.
As John Ronson,
author of a great book
on public shaming put it,
I suppose that when
shamings are delivered
like remotely administered
drone strikes,
nobody needs to think
about how ferocious
our collective power might be.
The snowflake never needs
to feel responsible
for the avalanche.
And that's how you get
these situations
where you have hundreds
of people endlessly bashing
someone who's already
been knocked to the ground
and feeling all the while
like they're punching up.
You know, there's actually
a kind of power and safety
in anonymity and obscurity.
And there are many ways
that being a public figure
makes you really vulnerable.
For example, you're more vulnerable
to doxing, stalking, and harassment
on a scale that most people
probably can't even imagine.
You're vulnerable to having
your reputation permanently degraded
in a way that people who are
posting anonymously
or pseudonymously
are pretty much invulnerable to.
And a lot of the people
who are attacking me,
they're not pausing to self-reflect.
They're not holding themselves
accountable for the consequences
of their actions.
They're just venting
their unfiltered rage.
But in response to these attacks,
I, as a powerful person
with a platform,
I'm not allowed to react
like a human being.
I'm not allowed to get angry.
I'm not allowed to show pain.
I'm not allowed to get defensive.
I'm not allowed to lash out.
All I'm allowed to do is
go totally numb on the inside
as I try to frantically calculate
the ideal public relations response
that pays due deference
to the valid concerns
of these poor marginalized people,
all the while ignoring
the tsunami of verbal abuse
that's crashing over me.
You know, people on Twitter,
they don't try to persuade me
like I'm a human being.
They order me around.
They tell me what to believe.
They demand that I say
exactly what they want me to say
or else.
It's extremely objectifying.
They don't treat me like a person
with my own opinions and feelings.
They treat me as this like
brand
of moral commodity
to be consumed or denounced.
And this is all terribly ironic
because of the conflicting demand
that creators be authentic
all the time.
One thing that always frustrates me
about these situations
is there's this demand
that you apologize instantly
and there's this perception
that a fast apology
is more sincere than a delayed one.
But in fact,
the opposite is true.
It takes longer than a couple hours
to cool down,
lower your defenses,
listen,
learn,
grow,
seriously reflect
on what you may have done
or said that was wrong.
That can take days
or weeks
or months.
I had to do my October AMA stream
for Patreon
and at the beginning of the stream,
I gave my emotional
half-formed reaction
to the Buck Angel situation.
And some traitor
on my Patreon
transcribed
that part of the stream
and disseminated it on Twitter
just to instigate
another round of canceling.
You're not allowed a chance
to think or feel.
And because supposedly
the best thing to do
from a PR perspective
is to apologize immediately,
canceling produces
a lot of insincere
bullshit apologies
from people who haven't in fact
learned anything.
And I think most people
are aware of that.
In fact,
I think the demand
for an apology itself
is often insincere.
If you're being canceled
rather than criticized,
then the line in the sand
has been drawn.
You and all your kin
have been declared
the enemy.
Apologize to Twitter.
At this point,
I may as well apologize
to 4chan.
Dear 4chan,
I am super fucking sorry
I called you
thin-wristed otaku shit weasels
who like looking at pictures
of little girls.
I have been trying
to educate myself
and learn from my mistakes
and I now realize
that's only 70% of you.
Like, once you're canceled,
you can really do no right.
If you apologize,
the apology will be declared
a manipulative attempt
to save face
and in fact,
it will be used
as further evidence
of what a Machiavellian
psychopath you really are.
If you try to explain
or defend yourself,
I mean, first of all,
you'll almost certainly
dig yourself in deeper.
But even if you're
articulate and correct,
you'll still be seen
as unable to take criticism
and as ignoring the hurt
of marginalized people.
And if you just go silent,
you'll be seen as a coward
fleeing accountability.
Even though there's
lots of reasons
why you might go silent.
Maybe you're taking
a few days away
from social media
to try to cool down
and think clearly.
Or maybe,
you're so overwhelmed
by the harassment
that you've just shut down.
Let's do shots.
Who wants to do a shot with me?
Do you want to do a shot with me?
Let's do a shot.
A tequila shot is my favorite.
I like the whole
salt, tequila, lime ritual.
It's just very satisfying to me.
It's the end of that bottle.
Okay.
Let's get started.
You feel warm right away.
You know that feeling
where it's like,
oh, hey, how are you, happiness?
Hey, how are you?
Feeling that life is worth living?
It's a good moment.
You're like, oh, this is good.
This is okay.
This is gonna be okay.
I can get through this.
It's how it starts.
Watch out for that.
So look,
I really don't like
to represent myself
as a victim.
That's not really a narrative
that I identify with.
But for the purposes
of communicating
what effect canceling has,
I feel like I should say something
about the pain.
Much of the happiness
that you might expect
to come along with success
has been taken away from me
by this constant need
and fury that surrounds me.
Try to think about this rationally.
I'm a Libra Sun, Pisces Moon.
Being canceled is hell for me.
You know,
I want to be liked by everyone.
And I'm starting to think
I might be in the wrong career for that.
In a way,
leftist Twitter finally accomplished
what 4chan, Nazis, stalkers, and TERFs
have been trying and failing to do to me
for years.
They've made Twitter into a platform
so hostile to my existence
that I've decided to leave it forever.
And they demoralized me to the point
I could barely get out of bed for a month.
And I know that sounds really melodramatic,
but I'm just trying to be honest with you
about what a melodramatic person I am.
I find I have trouble convincing people
of the severity of the pain
that being canceled causes
because I think it's just hard to imagine
if you haven't been through it yourself.
And I don't know a more succinct way
to convey it to you
than by telling you that
in the last few years,
I've been harassed by Nazis,
I've been harassed by TERFs,
I've been stalked,
I've been doxxed,
I've been threatened,
I've been sexually assaulted.
And the pain of being canceled,
of being totally trashed
by other trans people online for years,
has been more difficult for me to cope with
than all the rest of it combined.
Joe Freeman actually describes how I feel
better than I think I can describe it myself.
I was one of the first in the country,
perhaps the first in Chicago,
to have my character,
my commitment,
and my very self attacked
in such a way by movement women
that it left me torn in little pieces
and unable to function.
It took me years to recover,
and even today the wounds
have not entirely healed.
This attack is accomplished
by making you feel
that your very existence
is inimical to the movement
and that nothing can change this
short of ceasing to exist.
These feelings are reinforced
when you are isolated from your friends
as they become convinced
that their association with you
is similarly inimical to the movement
and to themselves.
Any support of you
will taint them.
Eventually all your colleagues join in
in a chorus of condemnation
which cannot be silenced
and you are reduced to a mere parody
of your previous self.
Yeah, that just about sums it up.
Now as it happens,
I am going to survive this
because I have very deliberately built
a support network that will be there for me
regardless of what online trans communities say.
And I have very deliberately done that
because early in my transition back in 2017
I relied very heavily
on the online leftist trans community
for all kinds of emotional support.
You know, when you're early in transition
I mean, it just sucks.
You feel like the whole world is against you.
And I talked about this a little bit
in my last video, you know,
feeling like a freak show
walking down the street.
And even if you're lucky enough
to have a supportive family,
like, it usually still is going to take them
a while to come around.
At first they don't get it.
They say things to you like,
aren't you worried you'll regret this?
And like, they struggle with your name and pronouns,
which is understandable.
But at the same time,
it makes you feel like you're not being seen
for who you are.
So you need a kind of second family
that understands how you're feeling
and acts happy about your transition
and validates your gender.
And for the first couple months of my transition,
I found that in this world of online transgender leftism.
Well, that didn't last long because,
well, I was what,
two months into my transition when
first I did an interview with the journalist
Jessie Single,
and then I agreed to do a debate
with Theron and Vanessa.
So that's a long story,
but in short,
I associated with a string of people
that trans Twitter considers the enemy.
And trans Twitter tore me apart over this.
And it completely broke my heart
because I was really leaning
on basically emotional support
from strangers online,
which seems really stupid in retrospect.
And after they turned against me,
I decided one,
that I was never going to rely
on this group of people again.
And two,
that I was going to have to find acceptance elsewhere.
And in retrospect,
I think this actually may have been good for me
in a roundabout way
because I was kicked out of the safe space
and I dropped that mentality.
And so basically,
I was thrown into the deep end of reality
and forced to sink or swim.
And I don't know if my transition
or my channel would be where they are today
if it hadn't been for that trial by fire.
Are we swimming through fire
or are we mixing metaphors?
The point is I'm more armored against canceling
than I was two years ago.
And the reason why is I have acquired
a certain level of privilege and security
and independence from any one community
so that if one community cancels me,
I still have somewhere else to go.
You know,
the people who are most vulnerable to cancel culture
are not white guy comedians.
They're not James Charles.
They're not me.
They are marginalized people
who feel like they have nowhere else to go
when they're rejected by their community.
That means struggling trans people
with a few hundred Twitter followers.
It means a lot of sex workers.
It means people
who totally rely on activist circles
for emotional and material support.
I'll quote Joe Freeman one more time.
I had survived my youth
because I had never given anyone
or any group the right to judge me.
That right I had reserved to myself.
But the movement seduced me
by its sweet promise of sisterhood.
It claimed to provide a haven
from the ravages of a sexist society,
a place where one would be understood.
It was my very need for feminism and feminists
that made me vulnerable.
I gave the movement the right to judge me
because I trusted it.
And when it judged me worthless,
I accepted that judgment.
There's a really irritating point
that people on the left like to make that goes,
well, canceling doesn't really end anyone's career.
Canceled people usually get a new job
or keep their platform.
So I guess it's not really that bad, huh?
I think people say this
because they're trying to mitigate any sense of guilt
they might feel about how they're treating people
because it's a really stupid argument.
There's lots of things that don't end your life
that are still terrible.
But also, there's cases where canceling
has ended someone's life.
On December 5th, 2017,
a porn star named August Ames
killed herself by hanging in a public park
after being canceled on Twitter
over a homophobic tweet.
On December 3rd, she tweeted,
Whichever lady is replacing me tomorrow
for erotica x news,
you're shooting with a guy who has shot gay porn
just to let you know.
BS is all I can say, shrug.
Do agents really not care about who they're representing?
LA Direct, I do my homework for my body.
So I've never worked in porn,
so I can't really tell you what the norms are
around women working with men who have done gay porn.
But the tweet certainly sounds homophobic to me,
and that seemed to be the consensus
of other industry people on Twitter.
So Twitter did its thing.
People in August's community called her a homophobe
and lashed out at her.
And as always happens,
plenty of passersby jumped in
to throw tomatoes at the woman in the stocks.
Over the next few days,
August tweeted several more times,
going through the usual stages that you go through
when you're being canceled.
First, she defended herself.
She claimed most other women in the industry
feel the same as her.
Then she said she's bisexual,
and therefore she couldn't be homophobic.
Then she said, fine, August will be fake
and not have opinions then.
Then she started bemoaning how mean Twitter is.
And she got really defensive
about her right to choose who she has sex with.
And she lashed out at the people attacking her.
And then in her final tweet,
she just said, fuck y'all,
and went to the park that night and killed herself.
This is all so familiar to me.
I feel like I'm able to relive with her
each stage of this emotional process.
There's that first moment
when you realize the outrage is beginning
and you get that sinking feeling in your stomach.
And then the anger, feeling misunderstood.
And then the bargaining, the fear,
and finally the shame and the despair.
And here's the thing,
I totally agree with her critics
that her tweet was bad.
Of course she has the right to say no for any reason,
but she publicly expressed this in a homophobic way.
But she was still a person who deserves to live.
And I think there's gotta be a better way
to deal with these situations
than just trashing someone until they kill themselves.
And I know it's never as simple
as Twitter made her kill herself.
There's always other things going on in the background.
But the point I'm making is,
canceling is more dangerous to marginalized people
because marginalized people generally have more things
going on in the background.
John Ronson did an investigative podcast about her death
and it goes into how she was saved
and sexually abused as a child, abandoned by her father.
She was living with a boyfriend
she was kind of emotionally detached from.
And a few weeks earlier,
she'd filmed a scene with a guy
who was unnecessarily rough and mean
and who mistreated her.
So she was kind of traumatized by that.
And so she was kind of on edge
and really defensive about who she worked with
when she was tweeting.
Then the backlash happened.
And since she had no other support network,
she probably felt like the only community she had
turned against her.
And that's a really painful feeling.
She must have felt so despised.
Which is how I've felt for the last two months.
I feel despised and burdensome.
And I can imagine how a person who feels that way
could have an impulsive couple hours
where they think their best option is suicide.
I mean, I can more than imagine it
because I've been there myself.
And I'm still here
because at those moments,
I've been with good friends who took care of me.
And by friends,
I do mean Xanax.
But I've also survived because
there's a lot of people on the internet
who'd be very entertained if I killed myself.
And I simply refuse to give them the satisfaction.
Oh no, bitch.
I intend to live as long as possible out of sheer spite.
I mean, who needs a guardian angel
when you can make it through Christmas after Christmas
on the fumes of total contempt?
What I'm really trying to say is,
Merry Christmas, you goddamn assholes.
Oh, holy night.
The stars are brightly shining.
Meow, meow, meow, meow.
Meow.
Meow, meow.
To get my lesbian pliers out again.
Have a super fucking happy New Year, George.
How am I gonna get this bathtub out of my apartment?
Anyone in Baltimore want a bathtub?
Leave a comment if you want a bathtub.
All right, I need to take a deep breath
because let's be honest,
I'm about one crack away
from attacking my own Twitter followers with an umbrella.
I am about one breakdown away
from going on a rampage
and making a suit out of women's skin.
Just kidding.
I would never do that.
Though on a bad skin day,
I've given it serious consideration.
Oh, I'll be fine.
I've gotta sober up anyway
because I'm having more plastic surgery in a couple days.
And plastic surgery,
that's about the only thing holding me together at this point.
What?
YouTubing?
This is a healthy profession.
This is great.
Anyone want my job?
Step right up.
All you have to do is make informative
and entertaining videos
about extremely controversial topics
while, of course,
representing the full range of experiences
in the LGBTQIAA plus spectrum
and being perfectly woke and irreverently funny.
Well, go on.
I'm waiting to be entertained.
Feed me, mother.
Oh, don't mind me.
I'll just sit back
and pour another glass of wine.
Oh, and I will, of course,
be obsessively scrutinizing
every word you say
for any hint of moral transgression
as well as critiquing your look,
you third-rate cross-dresser.
Zero out of ten.
Get off my stage.
He successfully spilled that everywhere.
It's good.
I do still want to talk about
why people cancel
and the effect that it's having,
but it looks like there's gonna have to be
a part two gorge
because I have hit my limit.
So why don't we all cut our losses
and try again in 2020, hm?
I realize that people on Twitter
aren't actually gonna watch this video.
They're just gonna make fun of the title
and how long it is.
Which, fair enough,
but they're the ones
whose accusations against me
are so numerous and convoluted
it required a feature-length film
to respond to.
But yeah, they're gonna see the title
and they're gonna transcribe
quotes out of context
and they're gonna say
I'm a fascist,
I'm a TERF,
I'm true scum,
I'm the new Blair White,
I'm the new Lacey Green,
I'm a cis bootlicker,
I'm an enlightened centrist,
I'm a shitlib,
I'm alt-right,
I'm a heartless grifter
raking in millions of dollars
over the bodies of dead trans women.
Mask off.
Yikes.
This ain't it, chief.
Friendly reminder
that this isn't a good look.
Maybe don't be a cis bootlicker?
Disappointing.
But there's something
about them saying
all those things already
so I'm inoculated.
See, their mistake
was completely breaking my spirit.
They should have left
a little piece intact.
But it's good.
It's good.
Because, basically,
my survival from here on out
hinges on my ability
to not care at all
what people say about me online.
So...
here's to not giving a fuck.
And to that,
I hope,
is to oxygenate
enough for the next
time we meet.
Mew men.
Sir,
but well,
I've been working out all about
this shit over the last 24 hours.
You're more than welcome
to the VIP stages.
But, uh,
cleared enough?
If you like what you heard about
it,
give this studio a steaming
shower.
Powered by Ang-ile.
Tremble is out ofachery!
The walls of our conversation
are close to this one.
You guys know
I believe this is gonna make
you a pin jerk.
Mhh!
We've got a deal,
baby.
Ay,
push through!
Thank you.
almost a norma desmond cosplay which is good because i'm not gonna age gracefully and
it's the best to get into character now youtube stars never die