Hello again, the gays.
Welcome to my garden party fantasy.
Straight people, you're of course welcome to tag along too, provided you're emotionally
damaged!
Hi!
Hey, how are you?
Cringe!
Let's talk about it!
The word cringe has taken over my vocabulary lately, it just pops into my head all the
time.
Like, when I randomly remember that month back in 2013, when all of my Facebook posts
were just lyrics to Kesha songs rewritten in iambic pentameter, why?
What audience was that for?
Who is this inconceivable person I used to be?
Cringe!
Mega cringe!
I think I say this word like 50 times a day, cringe, cringe, cringe.
And I'm not the only one.
Google Trends shows that in the US, search interest in the word cringe has dramatically
increased over the last decade, peaking in 2016 and remaining pretty constant ever since.
And if you look at worldwide trends, search interest in cringe has hit an all-time high
the month I'm making this video.
So what is cringe?
Well, let's start with some examples.
There was a recent thread on Ask Reddit titled, What Things Really Make You Cringe?
And here are some of the most upvoted responses.
The time I was talking too loud at a wedding when I wasn't supposed to, and everyone
at the wedding turned around to see what asshole wouldn't shut up.
Recordings of my own voice.
When I remember that I did the, I do have a boyfriend, he just goes to another school
thing.
Early teen me.
So many cringe stuff I did.
I hope all my old friends have forgotten about me.
This happened about two years ago.
I ordered some Pizza Hut online, and when it was delivered, the lady handed me the pizza
boxes.
I said thanks, and she told me my shirt was inside out.
I said, oh.
And then she hands me the receipt to sign and leave a tip, and I spend 30 seconds trying
to get the pen to work.
She looks at the pen and says, you have to click the pen.
I said, oh.
And then she reaches to get the receipt and tells me the pizza smells good.
Then I said, you too.
And then I closed the door and killed myself.
All of these responses illustrate exactly what writer Melissa Dahl said.
She said, oh.
Yeah, this is what I'm seeing.
But even though I had a better opinion on myself, I'm still disappointed in myself.
I'm not gonna be that person.
I'm not really that person.
So if she's gonna know who I am, I'm going to have to have to go live.
I don't want to.
She wrote from her book, Cringeworthy, A Theory of Awkwardness.
According to Dahl,
The moments that make us cringe are when we're yanked out of our own perspective, and we
can suddenly see ourselves from somebody else's point of view.
She quotes the anthropologist Edmund Carpenter, who in the 60s did a study of the Biyami tribe
in New Guinea, where he showed them mirror, video and photographic images of themselves
for the first time and described the results.
They were paralyzed after their first startled response, covering their mouths and ducking
heads. They stood transfixed, staring at their images, only their stomach muscles betraying
great tension."
So basically, they cringed at themselves. Maybe self-awareness always begins with cringing.
Like pretty much everyone seems to hate the sound of their voice when they hear a recording
for the first time. I guess because it sounds different from the way you hear it resonating
in your head. So when you hear the recording, you realize, oh god, that's how other people
hear me all the time. And you're suddenly aware of this clash between the way you appear
to yourself, and the way you appear to other people. That's when you cringe, the feeling
Dahl describes as the intense visceral reaction produced by an awkward moment, an unpleasant
kind of self-recognition where you suddenly see yourself through someone else's eyes.
It's a forced moment of self-awareness, and it usually makes you cognizant of the disappointing
fact that you aren't measuring up to your own self-concept.
When you're talking too loud at a wedding, and suddenly everyone turns around to see
what asshole wouldn't shut up, you suddenly realize how you look to them.
Because we've all at some point turned around to see what asshole wouldn't shut up.
But this time, you're the asshole. Cringe.
Often it's the violation of an implicit social norm that makes us cringe. There's no law
of state, or even of etiquette, that tells you exactly how loud you're supposed to speak
at a wedding. It's something you have to intuit based on context. How loud are other people
speaking? Is the ceremony about to begin and we're all supposed to be quiet now?
According to YouTuber Vsauce Michael here, the function of awkwardness
is that it sands social dynamics by smoothing out what even etiquette doesn't rule on.
Cringe is the electric shock, the emotional punishment, for being awkward. It enforces
the limits of socially acceptable behavior by wounding the ego.
And memories of your cringey moments are often just as painful as the moments themselves.
Ten years later, you'll be trying to fall asleep, and for no reason at all, your brain
will decide to remind you of that time you were talking too loud at the wedding, and
of the stupid thing you were doing.
You were saying when everyone turned around to stare at you, and you'll cringe all over
again. That's why remembering your teenage years is so painful. Because you look back
and you realize, damn, I was the asshole for like, seven consecutive years. Can I just
hire a hitman to kill everyone who remembers me before, I don't know, November?
Now all the examples we've considered so far involve self-cringe, but usually when
we talk about cringe on the internet, we're talking about cringing at other people. Popular
subreddits like r slash cringe are often just a way to show that you're not cringing at
other people.
Cringe, cringepix, and cringetopia host videos and images of people behaving in cringey ways.
For instance, a maternity photo that looks like a hostage crisis, grim moments of lamentation
and cuckoldry, and Mitt Romney attempting to communicate during his first encounter
with black people.
Who let the dogs out? Who? Who?
Ugh. Watching that makes me feel like my soul is on fire. It makes me want to crawl out
of my body and escape into another dimension. I think some people feel cringe more intensely
than others.
For me, it's uncomfortable to the point where I will reflexively pause a video like
that because I just can't stand it. In other words, it's like watching my own YouTube
videos, which… Sweaty, if you put that shit on, I will leave the room.
So why is it that cringing at other people hurts in the same way as cringing at yourself?
Well, one theory is that cringing at other people is simply vicarious embarrassment,
or secondhand embarrassment. Basically, it's a form of empathy.
When you cringe at someone, you're feeling the embarrassment that they're feeling,
just as if if you watch someone fall down the stairs,
you might wince empathetically with their pain.
But there's a problem
with the vicarious embarrassment theory of cringe,
or at least a complication,
which is that in the purest examples of cringe,
the person doing the cringey thing isn't feeling embarrassed.
In fact, often they're super confident,
and it's actually their lack of self-awareness
about their embarrassing behavior that makes you cringe.
Like when a woman posts
a ridiculously over-face-tuned picture of herself
as if anyone's gonna believe she looks like that,
or when a man thinks he looks like a badass tough guy
when he actually looks like an embarrassing dingus.
So in the internet sense of the word,
cringe is not just vicarious embarrassment.
Someone tripping and falling on stage is embarrassing,
and I do feel embarrassed for her,
but she knows it's embarrassing and she feels embarrassed.
You guys are just standing up
because you feel bad that I fell,
and that's really embarrassing, but thank you.
Nothing about this is cringe.
Maybe to her, it's self-cringe.
Maybe she looks back on it and it's still embarrassing,
but I don't cringe at her.
Maybe there's a difference between cringing at someone
and cringing with them.
When someone falls on stage, I cringe with her
in the sense that I feel vicarious embarrassment.
My feelings mirror what she's feeling.
But when I'm cringing at someone,
I'm feeling something very different
to what they're feeling.
I'm cringing at Captain Badass over here
because he doesn't have the decency to cringe at himself.
Another example is
bad American Idol auditions,
which are quintessential cringe content.
People try out for American Idol
because they think they're good enough singers
to compete in a national competition.
So they're effectively revealing their own delusions
when they show up and sing like this.
Is this the real life?
Or is this just fantasy?
It's not just that he's terrible that makes it cringe.
Most of us are bad singers, right?
When people sing happy birthday at a party,
usually they're singing
different keys at no particular tempo.
But that's not cringe,
because the point of singing happy birthday
is not to sound amazing.
Bad American Idol auditions are cringe
because of the contestant's misplaced confidence.
Who are you as good as, in your opinion?
The lead singer from Queen.
It's the hubris of thinking you sound like Freddie Mercury
when in fact you sound like a wounded street dog.
I admit that watching Red,
I'm actually not in very much pain
when I'm cringing at him.
I laugh at his ludicrous performance,
just like the judges do.
And because he's so cocky,
and because he doesn't show signs of embarrassment himself,
there's a part of me that actually kind of enjoys his failure.
There's almost a sense of karma,
a sense that because of his tragic hubris,
he deserves the humiliation he's bringing upon himself.
And my sense that he deserves it
suppresses my compassionate response
and helps remove any guilt I might otherwise have
about taking pleasure in someone's humiliation.
Contrast this with another Idol cringe contestant,
Misha, who's there with her mom,
and they both seem like such sweethearts.
I do believe in her talent.
That's very much.
And yeah, she's delusional about her singing talent,
but I'm rooting for her.
And when she embarrasses herself, I feel no joy,
only deep and agonizing cringe.
Don't you wish your girlfriend was hot like me?
Yikes.
My differing reactions to Red and Misha,
track a distinction that Dahl makes
between compassionate cringe and contemptuous cringe.
Compassionate cringe involves an emotional identification
with the person you're cringing at.
Even if they aren't embarrassed themselves
in the cringe-worthy moment,
you still feel the embarrassment they would feel
or perhaps ought to feel if they were aware
of how other people were perceiving them.
Contemptuous cringe, on the other hand,
involves an emotional distancing
from the person you're cringing at.
Just like with compassionate cringe,
you perceive that the person is embarrassing themselves,
but instead of feeling embarrassment on their behalf,
you feel annoyance and disgust at them,
and maybe even a little schadenfreude.
So these are actually two very different emotional responses,
vicarious embarrassment versus contempt.
We call both feelings cringe,
not because they're similar feelings,
but because they're responses to the same type of situation.
People lacking self-awareness
embarrassing themselves without realizing it.
Now, embarrassment and contempt seem, at face value,
like pretty unpleasant feelings.
So why are we so fascinated by content
that makes us feel this way?
Why do these cringe subreddits have more than a million members?
Why are cringe compilations and cringe reaction videos
so popular on YouTube?
Why does so much comedy feature cringey situations?
Well, I think the answer to that question depends
on whether we're cringing compassionately or contemptuously.
When I read that Ask Reddit thread
where all the people share their cringe stories,
I cringe compassionately.
That is, I feel vicarious embarrassment for them.
And with that compassion comes a sense of solidarity
and camaraderie with them.
I recognize myself in them,
and I'm reassured to hear that other people
are just as awkward and embarrassing as I am.
I'm not the only one who cringes at my past
or at videos of myself.
I'm not the only one who sometimes says,
you too, when the person says the pizza smells good.
When we collectively laugh at these situations,
we're bonding over our shared human frailty.
We're recognizing that we all say the wrong things sometimes.
That we've all arrogantly argued for an opinion,
only to later educate ourselves
and realize how ignorant and wrong we were.
That we've all tried to present ourselves as cool and likable,
as beautiful and talented and badass,
only to totally miss the mark
and completely embarrass ourselves.
And laughing at our shared absurdity,
our insecurity, our ridiculous pretenses,
it makes us feel less alone.
Now, this is all, of course, assuming
that we're cringing compassionately.
But I would argue that most cringe content on the internet
does not encourage compassion.
And that's kind of an uncomfortable fact,
because we like to think of ourselves as morally evolved.
This is the 21st century, right?
Pilleries and freak shows and public floggings,
these are barbaric practices from the dark ages, right?
Surely no one on the internet would ever entertain themselves
by humiliating people, right?
We've got maniacs.
We've got wackadoos.
We've got schizos, fatties, and spergs.
Come see sexual deviants on display.
That's right, folks.
We've got cackling perverts of every denomination.
Come see the panty sniffer.
He'll stop at nothing to indulge his twisted cravings.
Come see the skeleton girl.
She hasn't had a bite in 30 days.
That's right, we've got real, live lesbians.
And I'll be your master of ceremonies.
Half man, half woman, all freak.
Okay, we've heard enough heartwarming gibberish.
Welcome to the dark side of cringe.
Here on YouTube.com, we have a cringe culture.
And by that I mean there's whole channels making content
that centers the experience of cringing.
And there's a huge audience that seeks out cringe content,
including content the creator didn't intend to be cringe.
I first started paying attention to this back in 2016,
which was the heyday of the feminist cringe compilation,
or SJW cringe compilation.
Remember those?
This is ancient history by YouTube standards,
but in 2016, the word cringe was most associated
with a YouTuber called LeafyIsHere.
His videos followed the format of a cringe reaction video,
which means he would play someone else's content,
then pause it to rant in voiceover about how cringe it is.
No makeup or some sweatpants.
Oh my god.
It's so fucking bad.
He looks like he's gender fluid.
He looks like a fucking lesbian.
This format of cringe reaction videos was very influential,
and it was picked up by a rational herd of skeptical beasts
and free-thinking tuxedos.
What even is this thing?
It must be one of the 76 genders.
I didn't realize retarded was a gender.
Sorry, my dudes.
You were on the cringe side of history.
Obviously, there was a political angle to SJW cringe videos.
The logical antelope isn't inviting you to foster
a shared sense of humanity by recognizing your own weakness
in the embarrassment of screeching feminists.
No, this is an invitation to contempt.
Here's a YouTube video titled Fat Acceptance Cringe Compilation.
You'd expect from the title that it would be a video
of fat acceptance activists behaving in cringey ways.
But it isn't.
It's literally just a compilation of fat people doing things.
This is just a clip of a fat woman swimming.
Is this cringe?
What is cringe about it?
Earlier we defined cringe as either
vicarious embarrassment or contempt
for someone who lacks awareness about the way others are perceiving them.
But in this video of a swimming fat woman, there's no context,
so we don't know anything about her mental state.
And we certainly don't know whether she's self-aware about how she's being perceived.
If there is an interview where she talks about how she looks like a supermodel
or if she tried to photoshop herself to look like a size 4,
okay, maybe that would be cringe.
But that's not what's going on in this clip.
She's just existing.
In water.
What cringe are we being invited to feel over this?
Presumably, something along the lines of
ew.
Fat people.
Gross.
It's literally just disgust, right?
Disgust and contempt for a type of person, a type of body.
Here's another cringe compilation,
this one titled
and we're watching a young teenager discuss their plans to start vlogging about their genderfluid identity.
Honestly, it's kind of terrifying because,
you know, like,
genderfluid people just aren't accepted.
Yeah, apparently not.
And judging from the fact that I'm currently watching this in a cringe compilation,
it seems that the person in this video was dead on about how people would perceive them.
But despite that self-awareness,
we're being invited to cringe.
Because...
I guess being genderfluid, like being fat,
is cringe in and of itself.
Now the pedant in me wants to oppose this use of cringe.
This is not real cringe, I wanna say.
Cringe has to involve a clash between self-perception and perception by others.
But this usage of cringe as a mere synonym for contempt is so widespread
that there's really no point in objecting to it.
If you look at the banner image of Cringetopia,
one of the sleazier cringe subreddits,
you can pick out an otaku with a waifu body pillow,
a furry,
a couple bronies,
a fedora tipper.
These are subcultures associated with nerdy social outcasts.
They're types of people who are white,
widely ridiculed online.
I'd like to share with you a list that I put together
of groups that are often considered to be cringe.
Bronies,
furries,
otaku,
weebs,
incels,
neckbeards,
fedora tippers,
gamers,
TikTok teens,
not-like-other-girls girls,
fanfic writers,
beat poets,
SJWs,
feminists,
magas,
trans people,
non-binary people,
trans trenders,
queer afab ukulele players,
autistic people,
fat people,
the mentally ill,
and the mentally disabled.
Now I'm searching for some thread that all these groups have in common,
and a handful of themes do jump out.
Deviancy,
whether physical, mental, social, or sexual.
A combination of passionate sincerity and amateurism.
The perceived tendency to lack emotional composure.
Obsessive interests and unconventional hobbies.
Low social status.
It's pretty easy to wind up in the cringe category these days.
If you add up all the groups on this list,
I bet it includes most of the people watching this video.
It includes me three or four times.
I'm of course a fedora-tipping, queer, afab, ukulele-playing TikTok team.
Can't we just accept that we're all a bit cringe,
and try to be, like, compassionate or whatever?
Fuck no.
The internet will not abide any of that kumbaya bullshit.
Oh no.
This is social reject battle royale.
Clearly, contemptuous cringing is rewarding to people in some way,
and I want to explore what the rewards might be.
Let's start by looking at the role of cringe in internet politics.
Where manufacturing contempt is a powerful strategy.
At the height of YouTube anti-feminism, 2016 or so,
you couldn't escape clips of this woman, known as Big Red,
a Toronto resident who showed up at a men's rights event
and read off a list of feminist theses while swearing profusely.
It's part of patriarchy.
Part of patriarchy.
I don't know if you're noticing a theme.
Patriarchy.
I'm reading.
Fuckface.
Mr. Entitled.
Mr. Ego.
Patriarchy, fuckface.
She's one of these people who just
generates memeable phrases at an amazing rate.
I actually think she's hilarious and iconic,
but I have unconventional tastes, Anastasia.
Anyway, this video appeared in countless cringe compilations,
reaction videos, remixes, and even anti-feminist video essays.
Often Big Red was framed as, like,
THE feminist, the mascot of feminism,
a sort of metonymic stand-in for all feminists.
Which is highly dishonest, considering she's not even a high-profile activist or thinker.
She was literally some random woman on the streets of Toronto.
But because of this amusing 12-minute video,
it was insisted upon that we all take a stand on this random woman,
who, we were told, exemplified feminism in its purest form.
I call this strategy mascotization,
the construction of a strawman nemesis.
What you do is you select a cringe-worthy person
and you appoint them the mascot of an opposing political team.
It's very simple, but very effective.
And it's best paired with memification.
That's when you take a single moment in a person's life,
you freeze it,
and you declare that that moment fully represents a person.
Then, through mascotization,
you declare that this memified person represents an entire group or movement.
Other right-wing memes from this era include this protester,
You're fucking a white male!
memified as AIDS Skrillex,
and this protester,
Keep your hands clean! I'm a scoundrel! Keep your hands clean! I'm a scoundrel!
who was memified as Trigley Puff.
The two of them symbolized the wretchedness
of beta new male cuckoldry
and the hysteria of social justice cry bullies, respectively.
I guess the ultimate memified mascot was Anita Sarkeesian,
about whom hundreds of hours of salty gamer ramblings have been uploaded.
Sometimes Anita was caricatured as cringe,
as like this fake gamer girl,
this pleb-tier casual,
throwing a pathetic tantrum at real gamers.
But other times it was almost a super villainous caricature,
this sort of dark, devouring mother archetype,
threatening to confiscate your video games
and engulf you in her yonic abyss.
Now it's obvious why caricaturing your political enemies as super villainous is effective.
Though it comes at the risk of backfiring
by making your opponent seem a little bit too powerful,
a little too badass.
But the subtler strategy of symbolizing your political enemies
not with an evil, but with a cringe-worthy mascot,
works because it connects with a wide audience in an intense, emotional way.
Most people have a primal terror of becoming the target of public ridicule.
And if someone has been made a laughingstock,
it's much safer to take the side of the people doing the laughing
than it is to risk being laughed at yourself.
To be cringe is not to be in on the joke.
And because people crave acceptance and dread rejection,
I think one reason we're so fascinated by cringe content
is that our brains want us to learn how to avoid being laughed at.
When we see a mob of people, whether in person or online,
laughing at someone and ridiculing them,
we register an emotional memory of it as a warning.
Don't act like that, or people will laugh at you.
This is a powerful tool for anyone who wants to control human behavior.
It's why public humiliation has in many societies been a punishment for criminals.
You see a person in the stocks, in the pillory, at the whipping post.
You see the mob jeering and throwing rotten vegetables.
And it sends a powerful message.
Don't do whatever that guy did.
I don't think the internet has yet reached self-consciousness about the fact
that the fear of public humiliation rules us like it's the 17th century.
There's no judge sentencing people to a day in the stocks.
But instead, there's teenage YouTubers making cringe reaction videos.
There's ex-boyfriends revenge posting their girlfriends' nudes.
There's vigilante Twitter mobs harassing and shaming just about anyone
for alleged breaches of wokeness.
Public humiliation is a powerful force.
And it's usually...
It's not a good force.
But there are some rare exceptions.
Back in the Gamergate era,
Gamergate itself, of course, being a study in public humiliation,
slut-shaming on a massive online scale,
YouTube commentary was increasingly dominated by anti-feminism.
As far as leftist content, there was the Young Turks,
and there was a network of besieged feminist vloggers
who were constantly mobbed and harassed.
What I see is one of the turning points
in shifting the atmosphere from the pro-Gamergate days
to the left-tube world of today
was a handful of videos uploaded by then-obscure YouTuber Harry Brewis,
in which he mocked a misogynist pseudo-intellectual
called Davis Aurini.
Come on, Davis, we have to...
No, stop lecturing me about ethics!
We have to get out of here!
And can you please stop trying to start a forest fire?!
In his YouTube videos, Davis would pontificate
about the wickedness of women
while posing in front of a toy skull
and taking microscopic sips from a glass of whiskey.
Men of the West, women in our culture,
have become the most decadent sluts since the fall of Rome.
And so in discussing sluts versus whores,
I would start with the premise
that all women are whores.
Harry's videos ridiculing Davis attracted a lot of views
and a fairly positive response
even from a mostly male gamer audience,
who were overwhelmingly anti-feminist at the time.
Why did these videos work with this audience
where so many others didn't?
Well, I think it's because
Harry didn't moralistically call out Davis
for being problematic or misogynistic.
Instead, he simply drew attention to the fact
that Davis is a cringe-worthy buffoon.
And Davis was a perfect target
because he truly is cringe in the traditional sense.
He had no self-awareness about the fact
that pretty much everyone saw,
through his absurd posturing,
as a badass tough guy by day,
profoundly dark philosopher by night.
We exist in a world with feminized legislation.
I've spoken to men and boys who've told me
that Harry's videos inspired
the beginning of a feminist awakening in them.
Not just because they cringed at Davis Arrheni,
but also because they recognized
a little bit of Davis in themselves.
And they cringed at that too.
Recognizing part of yourself
in a cringe-worthy person
induces self-cringe,
which can motivate you to change your behavior,
your beliefs,
or even your own self-concept.
And it helps that Davis is a perfect instance
of a recognizable stock character on the internet,
namely the Fedora Tipper.
Basically a man who poses as a gallant crusader
for traditional masculinity,
but who's basically just a pasty nerd
who can't relate to women.
Davis was such an extreme version of this,
and he delivered unintentionally hilarious moments
so frequently that I would classify him
as what the internet calls a lull cow.
Lull cow is old 4chan lingo.
It means a person whose unintentionally eccentric
or foolish behavior can be milked for lulls.
Milking, in this context,
can mean simply watching a lull cow's behavior
and laughing at them,
or it can mean making reaction videos
where you make fun of them,
or it can mean actively trolling and provoking them
to get a response that you find entertaining.
I'd describe Harry's videos about Davis,
or my old videos about the Golden One,
as lull cow milking content,
with a political angle.
It was essentially an argument from ridicule,
an argument from cringe,
with the aim of convincing people
don't embarrass yourself like these ding-dongs.
But also,
and I'll just speak for myself here,
I am, at the end of the day,
an entertainer.
And I wanted people to laugh.
There doesn't need to be a political agenda
behind milking lull cows.
In fact, usually, there isn't.
The purest example of a lull cow I can think of
is actually someone from way before the internet,
namely Florence Foster Jenkins.
Jenkins, or Lady Florence,
as she liked to be called,
was an American soprano
who attracted a cult following in New York City
during the 1920s, 30s, and 40s
due to her being such a terrible singer
that people went to her concerts
essentially for the lulls.
She was described as
the world's worst opera singer.
No one,
before or since,
has succeeded in liberating themselves
quite so completely
from the shackles of musical notation.
Behold this fucking camp queen.
Oh, we have no choice but to stan.
Here's a short clip of one of the few recordings she made.
Cringe.
She was essentially the Tommy Wiseau,
the William Hung of her age.
Apparently she was oblivious to her own incompetence
until 1944,
when she was 76 years old,
and she booked Carnegie Hall for a concert
to which newspaper critics showed up.
The next morning,
the New York Sun reported,
much of her singing was hopelessly lacking
in a semblance of pitch,
but the further a note was from its proper elevation,
the more the audience laughed and applauded.
And five days later,
she had a heart attack and died.
I find something very touching about this story.
I mean, I'd probably be laughing as much as anyone
if I were at Carnegie Hall that night,
but I feel so much better.
I feel so much compassionate cringe for Lady Florence.
It kind of makes you appreciate the kind cruelty of Simon Cowell,
at least he tries to stop these people
before things get out of hand.
I think it's normal to have mixed feelings about a lolcow.
Like, yes, this is hilarious,
but on the other hand,
doth not a lolcow bleed?
On some level we know it's wrong to entertain ourselves this way,
but on the other hand,
other people's pain is incredibly entertaining.
There's a good book about this called The Joy of Pain,
Schadenfreude and the Dark Side of Human Nature,
by Richard Smith.
Schadenfreude is, of course,
the pleasure we take in other people's misery,
and Smith argues that we experience it
because psychologically,
we gain something when other people lose.
We're constantly evaluating our own worth
by comparing ourselves to other people.
So we get a reassuring self-esteem boost,
a pleasant feeling of superiority,
from comparing ourselves to people beneath us,
especially if we're kind of insecure to begin with.
Maybe I'm not perfect,
but at least I'm not this lolcow.
And we also get a boost
when people who are socially above us,
whom we envy,
get brought down a peg.
James Charles' cancelled party,
LOLOL.
I think Schadenfreude basically accounts
for just a huge percentage of the things that happen on YouTube.com.
Smith uses the word
for this type of media,
like reality TV shows
designed to produce spectacular moments
of embarrassment.
YouTube is basically a big reality TV show,
or some kind of carnival sideshow.
I mean, take a look around you.
We have Eugenia Cooney,
a YouTuber who, at the time I'm making this video,
remains apparently in total denial
about her eating disorder,
and continues to make videos
modeling skimpy clothes for millions of gawkers.
We have Wings of Redemption,
a bad-tempered gamer who,
for a long time,
was essentially confined by poverty,
obesity, and depression
to streaming video games all day
to an audience of trolls
that enjoyed tormenting him.
We have Onision,
a habitual
ALLENGE
abuser of women and teenage girls,
who earlier this year
essentially performed his own mental breakdown
on YouTube
after Patreon banned him
for doxxing an accuser.
I love kombucha!
Whose idea was it
to give hundreds of pathological narcissists
access to video equipment?
What kind of sick social experiment
are we living in?
And the viewers
are no better than the performers.
Every one of you bloodthirsty voyeurs
makes me sick.
Oh, you people love nothing more
than to watch one of us poor,
helpless egomaniacs
completely lose our minds
live on camera.
Is this what you want, huh?
Is this what-
You wanna total meltdown?
You know, as a creator,
you have to be aware that
you're a circus performer,
and the crowd may in fact
be more entertained
if you fall from the trapeze
and get eaten by the tigers.
Online media today
is full of Lady Florences,
anti-celebrities with anti-fans.
Now, to be clear,
I don't think there's anything inherently wrong
with indulging now and then
in a little bit of light contempt.
Cringing at Davis Aurini
or bad American Idol auditions
seems pretty harmless,
but it can be taken too far.
And there's no better case study
of taking it too far
than the cult following
of one Christine Weston Chandler.
If you don't know what's coming,
you might want to strap in, Gorge,
because this is coconuts.
It's bananas.
It's a full fruit salad.
God, how do I even begin to explain this?
Well, Christine Weston Chandler,
more commonly known on the internet
as Chris-Chan,
is the victim
of what is quite possibly
the longest-running
and most obsessive
internet trolling saga of all time.
She's the lolcow of lols.
Hello, everybody.
This is Christine Chandler
coming to you live from home once again.
Chandler is an autistic trans woman.
And yes, I will be calling her by she or her pronouns,
which I pause to explain
because I don't think I've ever seen anyone
actually take her transition seriously.
Most people seem to regard it as
simply another absurd symptom
of her hilarious mental condition.
In fact, a bunch of trans people
will probably get real salty with me
for making trans people look bad
by including Chris-Chan in our Oats.
Oh, our very prestigious and exclusive club.
Oh, please.
Transsexualism is a deviant sexual identity, sweaty.
This is not the Princeton Alumni Yacht Society.
God, how did trannies get so snobbish?
Look, is Chris-Chan really trans?
I don't know.
And I don't care.
If Chris-Chan wants to be a woman,
I for one support her journey.
But it doesn't matter.
The relevant thing about Chris-Chan
is not Chris-Chan.
It's the fact that for the last 13 years,
nearly every aspect of her life
has been obsessively archived online
by thousands of voyeurs known as Chris-storians.
Chandler first acquired this anti-fandom
several internet centuries ago,
back in 2007,
when 4chan took notice of her comic book series Sonichu,
a childishly drawn hybrid of Sonic and Pikachu.
The comic is set in Quickville, CWC,
being Chris-Chan's initials.
The protagonist is a self-insert
who references Chandler's real-life
quote,
love quest
to find a quote,
boyfriend-free girl,
which apparently involved posting bizarre
attraction signs
around her community college.
For this story to make sense,
you have to keep in mind
that Chandler identified and presented as male
until 2015.
So these trolls saw her as like
the ultimate autistic incel man-child.
Just to give you a feel for this,
here's Christine in 2018
holding up the iconic pre-transition portrait.
Note the Sonichu medallions.
Here's the bedroom she lived in,
and here she is in recent years
giving us a full Bronycon eleganza.
Pegasister snapped.
Basically she's the entire cringetopia subreddit
condensed into a single person.
So 4chan zeroed right in on this shit,
cause of course they did,
and they began tormenting her
by creating pornographic parodies of Sonichu,
posting candid photos of her,
etc.
Chandler reacted to the trolls,
which of course encouraged them more,
and the harassment escalated and escalated.
They hacked her accounts,
or tricked her into giving out passwords,
they posted all her emails online,
they showed up in person and photographed her house,
they called her parents,
posing as friends,
psychiatrists,
journalists,
employers,
in order to extract as much information
about her as possible.
And of course they contacted Chandler herself,
which was very rewarding for trolls,
because she has no filter,
and was very naive and trusting.
So she was very willing to divulge,
or easily manipulated into divulging,
mortifying information about herself.
Sexual, psychological,
scatological,
there's not really any limits or boundaries to this.
For all the information they gathered,
the trolls created a wiki,
called the Quickie,
devoted to the obsessive compiling
of all Chris Chan data.
It includes a detailed diagram of her bedroom,
entire articles about all members of her immediate and extended family,
pages of psychiatric records she was tricked into sending them,
and that's only the beginning.
In their more grandiose moods,
the Chris-torians have speculated
that Chris Chan is the most documented life
in all human history,
comparing their social expair-tainment
to the Truman Show.
It's a level of obsession
that surpasses the wildest excesses of Stan culture.
It's a gaze into the abyss
that does not blink.
Some trolls have also sent taunting letters in packages,
or on one occasion, sex workers,
to the Chandler household.
Two female trolls actually went on real-life dates with Chris Chan,
of course secretly wearing wires to record their conversations.
Others pretended to be her internet girlfriends
so they could solicit and post nudes and masturbation videos.
These things must be awful.
They're archived, don't you understand?
Chris Chan must be documented.
The absolute low point came
when some trolls encouraged a 13-year-old boy
to pose as a 19-year-old girl
and have phone sex with Chris Chan and record it.
In other words,
they groomed a child
to deceive an autistic person
into performing sex acts for their entertainment.
Now, to contemporary Chris-torians,
this sort of sadistic interference
in Christine's life is frowned upon.
Not so much because it's immoral,
so much as because it's considered a bit tacky,
a bit attention-seeking.
No, to the sophisticated Chris-torian,
the real pleasure in all this
is supposed to lie in quietly spectating,
savoring the fine notes of cringe.
Now, I take it I don't even need to comment
on the morality of all this.
The real question to me is why?
Why do thousands of people
have a morbid obsession with Christine Chandler?
And yes, it is an obsession.
Just to give you a sense of a single individual's
personal investment in this,
the YouTuber Gino Samuel,
one of very few Chris-torians
with the audacity to show his face,
has been working for more than two years
to produce an eventual 100-episode documentary series
about the life of Chris Chan.
Gino has completed 36 episodes
so far, and each episode is around 40 minutes long,
meaning he's already produced around 24 hours of video
about the life of what is essentially
a random stranger.
I think this phenomenon deserves its own name.
I'll call it morbid cringe,
defined as an obsessive and addictive
contemptuous fascination
with a particular person or group.
Why does morbid cringe happen?
Well, I've spent some time
poring over Chris-torians' conversations
with each other,
and I've even interrogated a couple of them,
and this is what I've found.
The first thing they'll tell you is that
they just think it's funny and entertaining,
that Christine's strange life and mind
simply appeals to their morbid curiosity.
And I'm sure that's true.
But a lot of things are funny and entertaining
and morbidly interesting.
Why fixate on this particular person?
Well, for a lot of them, it's a reassurance
that there's someone out there
worse than them.
Maybe they're nerdy loners with no social skills,
but at least this defenseless punching bag
called Chris-Chan is here for them
to assert their superiority over.
It's pretty much common knowledge
that a lot of Chris-torians,
including some of the most vocal haters,
are autistic themselves.
And a frequent justification
given for trolling Chris-Chan
is that she's giving autistics a bad name.
In recent years, there's also been
a small contingent of transgender trolls
who are likewise prone to say,
he's not a real transgender like me
and he's making us all look bad.
Oh yeah, cause people who troll Chris-Chan?
You guys look amazing.
It's common for trolls to offer rationalizations like this
about why trolling Chandler is justified,
righteous even.
Because, at the end of the day,
trolls are people too.
And a lot of them actually do have
a guilty conscience about this,
which they suppress by insisting
that Chris-Chan is a horrible person
who deserves to be tormented.
But trolls who protest too much
about the evils of Chris-Chan,
and therefore reveal the excess
of their emotional investment in this,
are known in the community as A-logs.
A-log is the name of a troll
who attracted the eyes of people
who are aware of other trolls
by ranting about Chris-Chan's crimes,
comparing her to Hitler,
and generally betraying a pathological hate obsession.
Among the trolls,
this kind of behavior is considered
an embarrassment to all of them
because they want to feel
like they're just coolly and casually
toying with this person.
You know, just for laughs.
Not a big deal.
Perfectly healthy,
and normal,
and fine.
It's fine.
But A-log gave the lie to that illusion
because it was obvious that his Chris-Chan obsession
wasn't healthy,
or normal,
or fine.
So the other trolls turned on A-log,
and they made him into Chris-Chan 2.0,
and they uncovered his autism,
and his furry porn collection,
and his cringy erotic fanfiction.
So why would someone as similar to Chris-Chan as A-log
obsessively hate on her?
Well, there's two explanations.
One is troll-shielding.
That is, A-log may have performatively despised Chris-Chan
and spearheaded the trolling efforts
in order to protect himself
from being targeted by trolls.
The idea is that you can protect yourself from the mob
by waving your pitchfork the hardest.
Obviously, this did not work.
The other explanation is that,
A-log saw himself reflected in Chris-Chan,
and sort of projected his own shame
and self-contempt onto her.
A-log hated Chris-Chan
because he saw part of himself in her.
And the other trolls hated A-log
because they saw part of themselves in him.
To quote Margaret Pless,
who covered this story for New York Magazine
a few years ago,
I think it might be A-log's all the way down.
People form morbid cringe obsessions with Chris-Chan,
because to them she's a symbol
of something they hate about themselves,
something they're ashamed of.
Maybe it's being on the autism spectrum,
or being a socially awkward recluse.
Maybe it's being unemployed and living with their parents,
or an adulthood fixation on children's cartoons,
or embarrassing sexual proclivities,
or all of the above.
This is how scapegoating works, right?
You repress your uncomfortable feelings
of shame and insecurity and self-loathing.
And you displace them onto someone else,
usually someone you can feel superior to.
Then you blame and persecute the scapegoat,
transforming your painful shame and self-loathing
into pleasant, judgmental self-righteousness.
It's pretty safe to assume
that a large percentage of Christorians and trolls
are some kind of social outcasts,
much like Chris-Chan.
So bonding together over their shared contempt for Chris-Chan
is a way of processing the shame and anxiety
of social rejection and exclusion.
And I think for a lot of people, even normal people,
who aren't part of a bizarre internet stalker community,
contemptuous cringing helps us cope
with our own shame and insecurity.
Anyway, it's time to stop this tedious
empathizing with other people
and find a way to make this all about me.
.
Meow meow.
Would you like to meet my quarantine boyfriend?
Would you like to meet my...
.
boyfriend's boyfriend?
That's right, honey,
I'm giving you fujoshi realness, nya.
He's gonna stay right here as a grim reminder
of the things that you have seen.
Actually, I identify as a trap.
It's very that.
I guess it's not really cringe if I'm trying to be cringe.
Cringe is failed seriousness.
In my last video,
I talked about how ashamed I am
of being a transgender lesbian.
Cringe.
Shame.
At the end of that video,
I talk about how I sense that my shame
is related to the contemptuous cringe I feel
for a lot of other trans lesbians,
particularly those of the heckin' stripey sock,
nya nya, catgirl variety.
But I confess to periodically sinking
into these morbid, guilty binges
of cringing at embarrassing trans lesbians.
I want to return to that thought
and kind of psychoanalyze myself
as a kind of first-person case study
of a morbid cringe obsession.
So, uh, catgirl trans girls are...
Okay, I can't believe I'm about to explain this.
They're trans women, usually attracted to women,
who express their identity online
through cloying, neotenous, otaku memery.
And my conscious reason for cringing at them
is that I see these Japanese cartoon catgirls
as a kind of visual baby talk,
an infantilized and unrealistic representation
of femininity and womanhood
that's designed to titillate nerdy boys.
So when trans women identify with it,
I cringe.
Like, no.
You can't become an anime girl, Lily.
Fuck your dreams.
Now look, I don't want to get sidetracked
with a discussion of whether my opinions
about catgirls are fair or correct.
So don't listen to what I'm saying about catgirls.
Listen to what I'm feeling about catgirls.
Listen to the contempt beneath my words.
Because even if everything I'm saying is true,
catgirls are being cringe online
is a situation so inconsequential
that any amount of emotional energy spent on it
is too much.
So why do I have this cringe fixation?
Well, according to the A-log theory of morbid cringing,
we form obsessive and addictive contempt
for people who have traits in common with us,
people who make us uncomfortable
because we see something of ourselves in them.
So do I have traits in common with the catgirls?
Well, we're both trans women,
we're both attracted to women,
uh, I do like anime, but
I don't like the anime they like, okay?
I like good anime that has, you know,
mature, three-dimensional female characters.
Look, I'm a real transgender, okay?
I'm not like you.
It's also not lost on me that this is like
the seventh time on this channel
I've dressed as a catgirl
to make fun of them.
I have posted cringe.
You should all be laughing at me right now.
Nyah, nyah, nyah, nyah, nyah, nyah, nyah.
So I do think there's some truth to the idea
that I'm A-logging these catgirls.
I also think there's a group representation aspect to this.
Like, I'm afraid that other people will cringe
at a group that includes me, trans lesbians,
because of how these catgirls are acting.
So let's make another distinction between
in-group cringe and out-group cringe.
In-group cringe is when you cringe at someone
who belongs to the same group identity as you.
For example, your family, your romantic partnership,
your ethnicity, or your country.
Particularly if they're embarrassing themselves
in front of outsiders to the group.
Think about how embarrassed a teenager gets
if her mom does something cringey in front of her friends.
Or think about how embarrassed liberal Americans get
when we talk to foreigners about Donald Trump
being our president.
Or think about these phrases.
She makes me embarrassed to be a YouTuber.
They're making trans people look bad.
He's giving autistics a bad name.
When we cringe at someone who belongs to our identity group,
we don't just feel vicarious embarrassment,
we feel embarrassment,
because their disgraceful behavior makes us look bad too.
So in-group cringe is actually a kind of self-cringe,
because you're cringing at your membership
in an embarrassing group.
Nothing has ever triggered this kind of
in-group embarrassment more for me
than a cringe video that went viral last year,
in which a masculine trans woman throws a tantrum
over being misgendered in a GameStop.
You're not getting my fucking money back!
Excuse me sir, there's a young man in here.
Excuse me, it's ma'am.
It is ma'am!
This video is excruciating for me to watch.
Motherfucker, take it outside!
If you want to call me sir again,
I will show you a fucking sir!
Motherfucker!
The paradoxical absurdity of trying to brutishly
intimidate people into seeing you as a woman.
Now Twitter's gonna come for me over this and say,
Natalie hates trans women, hey don't pass!
But passing is really not what this is about.
It's aggressive, intimidating, hyper-masculine behavior
from a trans woman, accompanied by apparently
total delusion about how she's presenting.
Well I'm gonna ask you for the fifth time
to stop calling me a man!
Because quite clearly I am not!
It's really not that clear, Gorge.
And that's what makes this video classic cringe, right?
The incongruity between her thinking that
she's serving women, while
bellowing like a drill sergeant.
By the way, what I'm doing right now,
this is cringe reaction content.
I don't really do that on this channel, but
I'm dipping my toe in just to see how it feels.
And it feels good. Like,
intoxicatingly good.
I can see how you could get addicted to this.
I'm imagining myself right now,
surrounded by cis people,
and I am leading the righteous mob
as we point and laugh
at some delusional, manly dump truck.
I am a real transgender.
A true transgender.
A good transgender.
Father finally approves of me.
Uh, this would be the unconscious, archetypal father.
Jot that down in my progress notes please, Doctor.
Okay, so why does this feel so good?
Well, let me talk you through my feelings.
When I watched that GameStop video,
for the first few seconds,
I do feel vicarious embarrassment for her.
I can even relate, cause in the first couple months
of my transition, there was an occasion
where I was in a lengthy
customer service interaction
where the guy at the desk was
calling me sir the entire time.
And there's something very humiliating
about trying to present female,
like wearing a dress and makeup,
and yet being called sir.
It's a quintessential mismatch between
self-concept and the way other people are seeing you.
And the memory of it is painful to me,
but what I cling to
is that while I may have
looked like a man, at least
I didn't act like a man.
I didn't threaten to take anyone outside
and show them a sir.
In fact, I was too ashamed to even
correct the guy.
So as the GameStop video progresses,
my sympathy runs out fast.
And instead of compassionate cringe,
I feel group embarrassment for trans women,
including myself.
And I feel contempt toward this individual
for making us all look bad.
I also feel a kind of morbid
fascination rooted in fear.
What if I'm as delusional as
that trans woman?
I don't look and sound like that, do I?
I feel like I have to do a sanity check.
I start scrutinizing myself in the mirror,
because of my voice, just to make sure.
And that fear motivates me to distance
myself from that person in the video.
I don't feel compassion for her,
because that would mean putting myself
in her size 16 shoes.
And I don't want to do that,
because I'm horrified and repulsed
by the thought that I'm like her in some way.
So I want to push away.
And contempt is a way of emotionally
distancing myself.
And if I express that contempt by publicly
shaming and condemning her,
then I'm also socially distancing myself.
Oops. Guess it's, uh,
contagious.
I think many people who are stigmatized
or who have been humiliated
long for the experience
of being a normal, surrounded
by fellow normals, judging
and humiliating a freak.
And if you take a look around trans YouTube,
a lot of the biggest creators in the
platform have channels
basically devoted to exactly
this type of cringe reaction
humilitainment. The YouTuber
Calvin Guerra is a trans guy whose best
known for what are essentially cringe
reaction videos, mostly aimed at
people he deems trans-trenders.
That is, people who claim to be
trans, but who aren't real
transgenders like Calvin.
He's especially bothered by girly,
afab, trans and non-binary
teenagers, or by anyone who
blurs the line between lesbian
and transmasculine identities.
Sometimes he'll do a long-form reaction to a
specific person who grinds his gears.
So this person is an asexual,
non-binary,
transgender,
lesbian, who uses he,
they, it, thons
pronouns. According to my calculations,
you are a trans-trender.
In other times, he'll basically
just laugh at cringy trans TikTok
teens.
No, no, I'm
turning off the video. I can't watch
this. He has a couple justifications
for making these videos. One is that he's
actually helping the people he's cringing at,
because if a trender transitions,
then they'll get dysphoria and have to detrend.
But I have to wonder,
does humiliating or laughing at people
really help them figure out whether they're trans
or not? His other justification is that
trans-trenders are giving real trans
people a bad name. They're the reason
people are transphobic. This is why
they hate us. It's because of
the trenders. Wow, I love
that idea of a true scum furry.
Isn't that just, isn't that just
wonderful? A true scum furry!
Uh, but it's not, though.
I mean, transphobia existed
long before there were people you could plausibly
describe as trans-trenders.
So trans-trenders aren't the reason
society hates trans people, Calvin.
They're the reason you hate trans people, right?
Or at least the trans community. And I feel like
what you're doing is you're projecting that feeling onto
society at large, and you're saying,
oh, this is the reason people are transphobic.
And to be fair, I get that it's not
just a projection. Like, back in
2016, the SJW cringe era,
it was cis people mocking
trans people with all these tropes.
Attack helicopter, two genders,
36 genders, special snowflakes.
But now, they're used by trans people
trying to distance themselves,
trying to ghettoize the most laughed at
people in the community under the label of
trans-trenders. And Calvin, there may
be some truth to what you're saying about there being
confused teenagers who think they're trans when
they're not. I mean, I wouldn't know. I'm a
near-dead woman in the twilight of my life, and I don't
hang out with teenagers. But even if it is true,
Calvin, your fixation
on it seems disproportionate to me.
Like, you return to this topic to cringe
again and again and again
and again and again and again. It's like you're
picking at a wound. It feels to me
like a morbid cringe obsession.
And I guess I think I recognize
part of myself in you. This could be
me projecting, of course, but I
wonder if the way you feel about
girly, sparkle-gender AFABs
is similar to the way I feel about
otaku, transbian catgirls.
And it might be worth considering
that I don't cringe at the
sparkle genders the way you do. I mean, I'm
with you on wondering what a hey-they-zeer
gender-flux lesbian demi-boy
is. But unlike you, Calvin,
I just don't have a morbid cringe obsession
with feminine AFAB trans people.
They can identify as however many genders
they want for all I care. I may not always
understand it, but I support
their journey. I guess it doesn't bother
me, because I'm not worried that anyone
will judge me because of how they
behave. I don't feel in-group cringe.
Now it's a different story if I'm reading
a general lesbian subreddit and I
see a comment like,
Pre-transition trans lesbian here.
I wish I had titties. Girl,
dick, nyah-nyah. Get the fuck out of here,
Billy. You're giving real trans
lesbians a bad name. This is why they
hate us. See, now I
have strong feelings. Now
I'm in-group cringing. And intellectually,
I do think my feelings are
correct to some extent.
Like, I don't think a general lesbian
community is the appropriate
forum for a trans woman who's
effectively still living as a man
to take the mic and whine about
wanting titties or rhapsodize
about girl dick. But I'm also
aware that I feel this strongly
about this because of my own
dysphoria. And my own shame.
And honestly, my own
self-loathing. Like, I can't
even talk to cis women on dating
apps because I feel like a fake woman
imposing myself on real women.
That's where my head is at. So
where does this pre-transition
trans lesbian get the
audacity? You know, it makes me feel in-group
cringe about an identity,
trans lesbianism, which for me
is already a pain point of
insecurity and embarrassment
and shame. So Calvin, maybe
and again, I could just be projecting,
but maybe, that's
kind of like how you feel about these trenders.
When you make these videos condemning
them as not really trans, aren't
you essentially exiling them from
the in-group so you no longer feel
the pain of in-group cringe?
Or perhaps, Calvin Guerra,
what you're really trying
to destroy is the trender
within.
And again, I could be
full of shit here. At the end of the day,
this is psychoanalysis of a YouTuber
I haven't met. So feel free
to tell me if I'm full of shit, Calvin.
But still, I guess I invite
you to consider whether
producing trans trender
humilatainment is actually helping anything,
or whether it's really
just an addictive way to
scratch some kind of emotional itch.
Alright, I've said my piece about Calvin.
Who's next?
Oh, how about
Vanessa. We meet again here.
And once again, I'm wearing some
kind of embarrassing anime hairpiece.
Vanessa is a trans woman who
is the second most popular
political trans YouTuber.
At least that's what I wrote in the script when I
had more subscribers than her and was fully
prepared to be a cunt about it, but
since then, she has
in fact surpassed me once again.
Good for her. Vanessa started out as
basically a cringe reaction channel
back when SJW cringe was fashionable.
She cringed at a wide variety of SJWs,
but the most consistent theme was
trans trenders and crazy activists
are giving real trans people a bad name.
They're making us look bad.
This is why people hate us.
So what we can now recognize as a standard
in-group cringe fixation.
But Vanessa focused in particular
on a strident
SJW type trans woman
called Riley Dennis.
And Vanessa made several reaction
videos to her where she made a point
of misgendering Riley and
dismissing her as a fake
transgender who hadn't
transitioned and clearly
had no intention to.
You know, if you went on estrogen,
your sex drive wouldn't be so high and you
wouldn't be guilt tripping people into having sex with you.
Just saying.
But then, Riley made a video
revealing that she'd been on hormone therapy
for a year and was about to
undergo facial feminization surgery.
This prompted Vanessa
to make an apology video where she
not only apologized to Riley
and acknowledged her transition, but she
actually went beyond the script of a
generic oopsie doopsie YouTube video
and opened up about having
experienced herself the cruelty
she directed at Riley.
I'm someone who's had my transition
picked apart online.
There have been Reddit threads and 4chan
threads with hundreds of comments on it
of people trying to prove that I'm not trans
because I haven't done this or that
or, you know, digging up my old pictures
and so the thought that this entire
time I've done that exact
same thing to someone else
and pushed that off on someone else
fucks with me.
And I'm fucking sorry.
Vanessa actually managed
for one fleeting moment
to make a connection between
her own past hurt and trauma
and the pain she'd inflicted on another
person. Which is kind of a once in a lifetime
event on a website
where the performers are remorseless
psychopaths who wouldn't muddy their
shoes to save a drowning child
and the viewers are cold blooded
sadists who consume human misery
like a glutton, gorging him
at a particularly
sumptuous buffet.
You know, this whole thing has really taught me a lesson
that I should really try to stick to
ideas, opinions,
policy.
However, this lesson would not last.
Vanessa kept doing
SJW cringe content
well past the point it had become
passé, making a video with
Big Red in the thumbnail
as recently as 2019.
I admit, I thought she was
fading into irrelevance.
But again, I underestimated Vanessa.
In July 2019,
her channel rocketed to a new
level of success when she released
a video titled
Exposing Jessica Yaniv
Trans Predator.
In this video, Vanessa sounds the alarm
about a trans woman, or rather
she believes, a man posing
as a trans woman, called
Jessica Yaniv.
Who the fuck is Jessica Yaniv?
Well, as far as
I can tell, everything
Vanessa says about Yaniv
is true. Yaniv attempted
to use a Canadian human rights
tribunal to close down several
beauty salons that had refused to wax
her hairy balls after she approached
them about it in an awkward and creepy
way. She has a long history of sending
extremely inappropriate
messages to underage girls.
And, she attempted to host
a topless pool party
for unchaperoned children.
Basically, Yaniv is someone who
appropriates the language of
transgender acceptance and equality
to cloak predatory behavior
toward minors. And my read
on Yaniv, by the way, is not
that she's a cunning manipulator,
but that this is someone who is
mentally not playing
with a full deck. After the success
of her initial video, Vanessa
made a few more videos about Yaniv
rebranding herself as a kind of
transsexual Chris Hansen,
exposing TRANSGENDER
PREDATORS wherever
she could find them. And it
turns out, first, I was honestly
kind of loving this for Vanessa.
At least now she's finally picking on
someone who deserves it. But the more
I think about it, the more
hesitations I have. One,
is that Vanessa framed the Yaniv
story and the lack of attention
given to it by other trans public
figures as an indictment of
trans activists.
Who Vanessa thinks should spend more time
sounding the alarm about
TRANSGENDER
PREDATORS. And I'm willing to
admit, there's probably
a valid point in there somewhere.
Like, some trans people really are
so paranoid about transphobes framing
all of us as dangerous perverts
that they basically look the other
way and refuse to acknowledge
the small but real subset of trans
people who are, in fact,
dangerous perverts. But Blair,
you talk about the Yaniv
situation like it's urgent
breaking news. Like Yaniv should
rightfully be a household name,
but for the stubborn silence of trans
activists. But why?
Why should everyone be focused
on Jessica Yaniv? There's more
than 100,000 sexual assaults
reported to American law enforcement
every year. The literal president of
America is a bit of a sexual
predator himself. Why
fixate on this one particular
Canadian creep? I guess you could
argue that since Yaniv is a
trans-identified predator,
a tip. We as real trans
people have a responsibility
to be the ones who lead the charge to stop
her. Or at least it would be good
optics for us to do that.
And again, I think there's maybe some truth
to that, like initially
the LGBT website Pink News
straightforwardly reported Yaniv's
claims of discrimination, which
is pretty embarrassing and
not great optics, but I don't think
that constantly broadcasting
updates about the trans
gender is really the best
optics for us either. Why did
Vanessa make this video in the first place?
Is it simply because she
cares deeply about the well-being
of children, and she
thought making a video exposing
Jessica Yaniv is the best
way to protect them?
I mean, I'm sure she cares a little
bit about the children, but it's
still a YouTube video, and
you have to ask, is the
primary intention here really
to stop a predator? Or
is it to manufacture
a sleazy entertainment
spectacle? Shortly after her
first Yaniv video was published,
Vanessa hosted a live stream
on her channel titled
Heated Debate with Jessica Yaniv
Trans Predator.
This got 2 million views.
Is this what you do with
someone you've just accused of
pedophilia? You host a live
event debating
the pedophile on your YouTube
channel? What's to debate?
I don't need to be scared in my own house
that I'm gonna get fucking attacked
which is illegal
in Canada, just saying. But
you think that was, like, cute?
Was that a moment for you?
Then of course, you sell t-shirts
featuring the meme that resulted
from your YouTube pedophile
debate. I mean, that makes sense.
If you're gonna catch a predator,
you gotta sell pedophile debate
merch. And of course, you
gotta follow the pedophile's makeup
tutorial, you know,
for the children.
Now, I hate to be overly
critical, but when I look
at this, I don't see
a high-minded activist
working to protect children and
trans people's image. I see
a tabloid entertainer
who's discovered a way to
monetize milking lulz
from a mentally defective
pervert. And I have to say,
Blair, as a connoisseur of trash
myself, I'm very entertained
by all of this. Following
a sexual predator's makeup
tutorial? That's
genius. I wish I'd
thought of that. But just be honest.
This isn't activism.
This isn't justice.
It's a lolcow cult.
It's like one of Mari's transsexuals
took over the show. And I love
that for her. I love that
for her. But Blair,
I can't help but notice
you're still hitting all the
same beats your videos have always
hit. Attention, everyone.
There is a bad
transgender in our midst.
The bad transgender
is not a real transgender like
me. It's very important
that we all gather round
to condemn this bad
transgender who is not a real
transgender. And Blair, I'll give you
this. You are getting better at
choosing your targets. The transvestite
monster is a stock character in
our culture, and Jessica Yaniv
is good casting for the part.
She's a transphobe's boogeyman
come to life, and I certainly
am not shedding any tears for her. But
you'll have to excuse me if I don't take this
seriously as anything more than
a smarter version of the same
in-group cringe humilitainment
you've always made. And by the way,
you may want to check in
on your understudy, Rose of Dawn.
Rose of Dawn is another
conservative trans woman YouTuber
who produces a series called Trans
Stupid. Hi, everyone, and
welcome to another edition of Trans
Stupid, the show where I take a look at the
wonderful world of LGBTQIA++
news because
stupidity is intersectional.
Transgender.
More like trans
retarded. More like trans
gay.
Trans gay.
I love that. I'm literally, I just
realized I'm literally trans gay. Rose's
channel is allegedly about the
excesses of trans ideology
and activism, which in theory
I do think is a perspective
worth including in the conversation.
But in practice,
well, let's just say Rose
has produced a 30-minute documentary
about why Chris Chan is not
a real transgender. There is a
bad transgender in our
midst. The bad transgender
is not a real transgender
like me. I'm getting pretty tired
of this. And here's her transition advice
to trans women just beginning their
journey. You probably have this image in your
head that, you know, you're going to be this really
cute-looking trans
woman. Like, effectively, you're going to be this
seal. Like, look at this seal.
Isn't this seal adorable?
You're so cute. But
the truth is, you're probably not
looking like this seal right now, are you?
You're probably more like this big
bull seal, barging your
way into women's bathrooms
saying, this is a woman's
body. Now,
you might never reach the
cute seal phase. In fact,
very few of us turn out to look like Blair White.
Rose, no.
Do not simp for Vanessa.
It only encourages her. She's also
made no less than 20
videos about Jessica Yaniv.
Which seems like kind of a lot,
Gorge. Would I be wrong to say I'm
getting a little bit of a morbid cringe addiction
vibe? In these videos, Rose
chronicles Yaniv's numerous crimes and
wrongdoings, but she also
cannot resist making it
very clear how disgusted
she is with Yaniv's
appearance. The irony being
that this kind of tweet came from someone who you
could smell just by looking at
a picture of them. I bring this up,
again, not because I have
any interest at all in white knighting
for Yaniv. I do not support
her journey. As far as I'm concerned,
she can eat shit. And maybe
she does. I wouldn't be surprised.
No, my point is that part of the
catharsis that Rose and Vanessa
seem to derive from making
this kind of content
comes from contrasting themselves
as good, presentable,
real trans people with
the hideousness of the wretched
fake trans dump
truck. A classic Vanessa
thumbnail is divided
into two halves. On
one half, Vanessa
looking fish, looking
cunt.
Always with her lip gloss in the livestreams.
And in the other half of the
thumbnail, for contrast,
the tragic dump truck
in a maladjusted wig.
And I'm allowed to say dump truck because before
I transitioned, I was one of Vanessa's
dump trucks. I was one of
her dump trucks.
Look, I happen to
possess a little thing
you probably haven't heard of it, called
inner beauty. That's right, sweetie.
My pancreas?
Unclockable.
Meanwhile, Rose,
who prefers to represent herself
with this cartoon,
okay, straight up
refers to Yaniv as
the tubby troon in the Titanic
Tranner of Canada.
A particular Titanic Tranner of Canada?
Tranner and
troon being pejoratives for
transgender that I associate
with 4chan, where I'm guessing
Rose has spent a lot of time.
As for the emphatic revulsion
toward Yaniv's fatness, well,
I'm guessing that must be another
important part of stopping a predator, right?
It seems almost
taboo to condemn people
for how rough they look, when
I think that that tough love in a
way is needed, because
I look at what I looked like when I
first transitioned, and
Jesus Christ, I wish my friends had said something.
Like, I looked
bad. Like, I was overweight,
I had a poor taste
in clothes. Like, I was
never wearing stupid dresses or anything,
it was mostly t-shirts and jeans.
You're probably more like this big bullseed
barging your way into
women's bathrooms, saying
this is a woman's body.
Now, you might
never reach me. You'd see
me fake, so in fact, very few of us
turn out to look like Claire White. And I want to make
it very clear that when I'm talking about
transition, I don't mean that
you're going to- Rose...
Are you okay? No.
You're not okay. None of us are okay.
No trans woman, remotely
in the public eye, is in any way
okay. And look, I don't want to take
this psychoanalysis too far, because
I don't know, from watching YouTube
videos, what's going on in someone's head.
But I can try to make intelligent inferences,
and I think it's pretty revealing
that this is how Rose
introduces the topic of Jessica
Yaniv. Being, well, one of the
biggest characters in the
whole fucking world at the moment,
which is Jessica Yaniv.
Rose?
Gorge?
Jessica Yaniv is not one of
the biggest characters
in the whole world
at any moment. This is not
a world historical figure.
At the end of the day, this is a more or less
random civilian sex fiend off
the streets of Vancouver, BC.
The only reason anyone has heard of her at all
is that Vanessa decided to go full to catch
a predator and turn this grimy
reprobate into a minor anti-celebrity.
She is not one of the most important
characters in the world. But it sounds
like what she is, Rose, is
one of the most important characters
in your brain. This is distorted thinking.
It's like A-Log comparing
Chris Chan to Hitler. You're so deep
in the morbid cringe obsession that
you've lost perspective. And I'm sure
you have what seem to you like perfectly
logical reasons why you're devoting so much
attention to this. And I know videos
about Yaniv get a lot of views, so I'm
sure that's a factor too. But Rose,
I also know a morbid cringe obsession
when I see one. And I know
that being a visible trans woman on the
internet is more difficult than most
people can imagine. And I know
that pretty much every trans person is
bullied or shamed or humiliated
at some point in our lives. And I know
how good it can feel to
take all the horrible things transphobic
noobs and bullies and TERFs have said about
us, and repeat them
verbatim about some
big, fat, fake,
dangerous, delusional, disgusting
male fetishist. Oh,
it feels good to be the TERF for
once. It feels good to be the
judge rather than the judged.
Because when you point the finger at someone else,
you're also pointing away
from yourself. And it's not
lost on me that in conservative circles,
queer people are often treated like
suspected sex criminals by default.
So there's safety in being the
one who spearheads the think of the children
type moral crusade. And when
you expose a trans predator,
you get that feeling of
safety plus the relief
of having someone in particular
to blame for the shame
and stigma we all feel.
Jessica Yaniv is the reason
people hate us. But that's just not true.
It's a simple answer to a
complicated problem. It's scapegoating.
When I look at the Yaniv
obsession on trans YouTube,
I see a community trying
to cope with stigma and
hoping that destroying a scapegoat
will bring relief. It's basically
a blood sacrifice.
It's not rational. It feels
good for a moment,
but it's an addiction. It won't ever
erase the stigma and the shame.
And Yaniv is simply the latest
and most deserving in a
long line of bad
transgenders who aren't real transgenders
and are giving us a bad name
and are the reason people hate us and
want us to be condemned and destroyed.
But when Yaniv is finally gone,
when you get her sent to prison or whatever your
goal is, you're just gonna find a new
scapegoat to take her place.
And the shame cycle continues.
The humiliation and bullying we've experienced
is internalized as shame.
When we project that shame onto
scapegoats and onto each other,
it becomes cringing and contempt.
And we voice that contempt
by shaming other people,
which starts a new cycle.
So you can keep finding new scapegoats,
new punching bags, new shame dumps,
new lolcows, and you can end up like
one of the people who's been archiving
Chris Chan for 13 years.
But that will never really heal us.
God, how do I get out of this video?
I'm trying to have a serious conversation
dressed as some sort of catgirl degenerate.
Cringe. Shame.
I'm ashamed. Don't look at me.
You know,
I love wearing florals in front of flowers.
Thank you, yes.
I suppose it is groundbreaking.
Alright children, let's review our notes
on cringe. The word cringe really describes
two different emotions,
either embarrassment or contempt.
You can feel either one for yourself
or for someone else. When you're embarrassed
for someone else, we call that vicarious
embarrassment. And that can mean cringing
with someone who is embarrassed themselves,
which I've argued is excluded
in the internet usage of the word cringe.
Or it can mean embarrassment for someone
who isn't embarrassed themselves,
in which case we say we're cringing at them.
Now if someone who's part of your
in-group is embarrassing themselves,
by proxy, embarrassing the in-group
that includes you, you feel
in-group cringe, which can involve
both vicarious embarrassment
and a kind of self-cringe.
And on the contempt side, contempt
for someone who shares traits in common with
you, particularly if they're traits you have
contempt for in yourself, can
develop into morbid cringe,
which is that obsession with a lol cow,
that addiction to contemptuous
gazing at a dark mirror in which
you see reflected everything you hate about
yourself or about your in-group.
Now I want to end this video by reflecting
on whether cringe is good or bad,
healthy or harmful.
And I do think that in some situations,
cringe is good.
Embarrassment serves a social purpose.
It helps us interact smoothly with each other
by telling us what not to do.
And empathizing with other people's embarrassing
stories can be cathartic.
It can make you feel closer to other people,
more alike, less alone.
I also think a moderate amount of self-cringe
is very healthy. It shows you're
self-aware, and you care at least
a little bit what other people think.
You know, I've met people who never cringe
at themselves, and let's just say
they're not my kind of people.
They're narcissists who think super highly
of themselves, regardless of how they're
actually coming across. But I think partly
out of fear of ending up like one of those
people, I've overcompensated.
And I cringe too much.
Both at myself, and at other people.
It's a habit that's kind of
making me hate myself, and it's making
me unfairly contemptuous towards
others. And when I take a look around the
internet, like I've done in this video,
I find that I'm not
alone in this situation. And it's
not cute. So, how do we
cringe less? Well, the cliche solution
is self-love, which our culture
places a lot of value on.
Self-love and self-esteem.
You know, I don't care what haters
and losers say. I'm a bad bitch.
I look like a supermodel.
I'm a genius.
We're encouraged to hype ourselves up in this way.
But it doesn't work, because it's not
realistic. You don't look like a supermodel.
And you're not a genius.
And when you realize that, you fall from one
extreme to the other of what Chris Fleming calls
the self-esteem tower of terror.
You go from self-love to self-hate.
But self-hate is also
a distortion. Recently I was listening to
a David Foster Wallace interview.
Yeah, I know. Cringe. And he attacked
me mercilessly and unprovoked.
There's a lot of narcissism and self-hatred.
How
dare you notice that? I'm in this
photo and I don't like it.
But it's true! Time spent
cringing at yourself is still
time spent obsessing over yourself.
And it's hard not to, because
humans are animals, so our
perspective is egocentric by nature.
But we can still learn to appreciate
that the world is bigger
than us. I mean, I've heard rumors.
In that book we started with, Cringeworthy,
Melissa Doll advocates not
self-love or self-hate, but what
she calls self-indifference.
She says,
Self-indifference is the relief
of realizing that you are simply
not that big a deal.
So yeah, I was pretty
cringey in the past, and
I'm still pretty cringey now, but
you know what? Everyone else
is pretty cringey too. And the world's
probably gonna burn down in 50 years anyway,
so I don't know if I would call this
good news, but if it's
any consolation, uh,
nothing matters.
Nothing matters.
Thank you for watching.
Thank you.