So, April 27, 2017 was the greatest day in the history of twitter.com.net.gov.
I realize that to you children, Twitter is an app, but to us MILFs, it remains a website.
You have to dial in.
Hello operator, connect me to hell.
This was the day that Fyre Festival, a luxury music event hosted by Ja Rule and some charlatan,
was scheduled to begin on a private island in the Bahamas.
There was a lot of hype, Kendall Jenner and Bella Hadid endorsed the festival on Instagram,
there was a promo video full of supermodels, tickets were selling for thousands of dollars.
One Twitter thread summarized the marketing as exclusivity, conspicuous consumption, and
many, many promises of excellent selfies for your already insufferable Instagram.
So when the day arrived and the advertised best in food, art, music, and adventure turned
out to be two slices of pallid American cheese languishing over sliced bread in an atmosphere
that can only be described as muddy third world shantytown, I mean, if you weren't
on Twitter that day, I don't think you can even imagine.
The revelry.
Just learned about Fyre Festival, aka Ja Rule's concentration camp for Instagram models
and rich white kids.
Yuppie Hunger Games hosted by Ja Rule.
Finish your food, there's starving millennial influencers in Fyre Festival.
Instagram entitled rich kids, meet Lord of the Flies.
Let them eat salad.
It was a shuddering climax of pent-up class rage.
You know, maybe millennials couldn't get Bernie Sanders.
But at least those sandwiches were garbage.
Jamila Jameel is an English actress who's just extremely pretty.
Imagine looking like this.
Imagine being perfect.
Why are you doing this to me, Jamila?
Why are you doing this to women?
One day on Instagram, an ordinary peasant told the queen, Jamila, your skin is so perfect,
uwu.
And Jamila replied,
My skin is currently perfect.
My skin is currently clear because
A. Privileged people have more access to good quality nutrition and also our lives are significantly
less stressful than those with less privilege.
I also get to sleep more because of this.
All of these things keep my hormones in balance and I'm able to address food intolerances
easily.
B. I believe that trans rights are human rights.
C. I exfoliate twice a week.
Oh boy.
Jamila, they're gonna cut your head off, Gorge.
I'll protect you, queen.
Could she be any more annoying?
Someone wandered on Twitter to 77,000 likes.
This trend of fake self-awareness legit makes me want to rip my hair out.
Now look, to be fair, everything Jamila said is true.
Being privileged does make it easier to spend time and money on cosmetics.
But Jamila's acknowledging this, this recitation of all the complex socioeconomic factors that
account for why she's prettier than you, doesn't take any of the sting out of inequality.
I'm not saying she's not pretty.
I'm not saying she's not beautiful.
I'm just saying she's got a lot of quality.
Does it?
And that's kind of at odds with what activists used to say, which is that you should check
your privilege.
A suggestion which the privileged seem to have taken to heart, since the rich and famous
now go around delivering these orations on how fortunate they are compared to the rabble.
And this of course turns out to be far more annoying than when they acted oblivious to
it.
I don't have any beauty secrets.
I guess I just drink lots of water.
Take me, mother.
A similar scandal occurred when Kim Kardashian tweeted about her birthday party at the height
of the coronavirus pandemic.
Forty and feeling so humbled and blessed.
There is not a single day that I take for granted, especially during these times when
we are all reminded of the things that truly matter.
After two weeks of multiple health screens and asking everyone to quarantine, I surprised
my closest inner circle with a trip to a private island where we could pretend things were
normal for just a brief moment in time.
I realized that I was not alone.
I realized that for most people, this is something that is so far out of reach right
now.
So in moments like these, I'm humbly reminded of how privileged my life is.
Hashtag this is 40.
Tag me, bitch.
So like Jamila, Kim is attempting some kind of privilege checking maneuver.
And once again, it has not gone well.
You are the Marie Antoinette of the 21st century bragging about being humble and letting us
eat cake.
Millions of Americans sick and suffering.
Standing for hours in food lines and being evicted as you flaunt your wealth and privilege.
Your tweet made ten times worse by hashtag tone deaf, humbled and blessed line, hashtag
gross.
Happy birthday.
Mmm.
I hope somebody got you an alphabet book as a gift so you can read them motherfuckin'.
So the response on Twitter resembles moral outrage, but what people were upset about
was not that she had the party.
I mean, wouldn't you escape to a private island if you got that MILF money?
The problem was more that she tweeted about it, and that the tweet was maybe, just maybe,
a little bit yikesy.
But if having the party wasn't wrong, then why was tweeting about it wrong?
This isn't a good look.
We say bad optics.
Not relatable.
Relatable.
Relatability is not a moral category.
This is public relations, it's not ethics, and it definitely isn't socialism.
Like, I'm pretty sure Karl Marx is a socialist.
I'm pretty sure Karl Marx never said,
The problem with the bourgeoisie is they are not relatable.
They can't read the room and it isn't a good look.
This should have stayed in the drafts.
Hashtag tone deaf.
Isn't the issue that, when Kim tweeted this, most people were trapped in quarantine?
We didn't get to have birthday parties.
Some people couldn't even travel to visit their dying relatives.
So watching Kim get to travel and celebrate her birthday like normal was…
painful.
Pain at the good fortune of others is how Aristotle defined envy.
And I think it's interesting that whenever social media erupts in outrage over luxury
music festivals, or Kim K's birthday party, or Jameela Jamil's privileged pores, no
one ever uses the word envy.
It's like we're averting our eyes, avoiding confrontation with this dark aspect of our
own psychology.
So in this video, I want to take a long, hard look at envy.
What is it?
Where does it come from?
And seriously, what is Jameela Jamil's skincare routine?
Drop it in the comments, bestie!
Okay, so what is envy?
Pain at the good fortune of others is not a bad start, but there's more to it than that.
Envy is a syndrome, a complex of poisonous thoughts and feelings about people who have
what we want, but cannot get.
It's not simply wanting what another person has.
That's greed, which is a much more wholesome sin.
Because simply wanting what someone has can inspire us, it can fuel our own ambition,
it can even motivate us to improve ourselves.
And sometimes people call that envy, but it's not really envy.
It's emulation, or admiration.
At worst, it's what the Bible calls coveting.
It covets.
Envy is something darker, it's not just wanting what someone has, it's begrudging
them what they have.
You might even hate the person.
You might even hate the person you envy, and want them to lose what they have, to be
humiliated and destroyed, even if their downfall doesn't benefit you in any way.
Like Satan, who is willing to lose heaven just to spite God, according to the poet John
Milfton.
It's gonna be 90 minutes of MILF jokes, kids, so strap in.
So envy is malicious, it's a force of destruction.
For an example of the distinction between envy and emulation, think about incels, involuntary
celibates.
Men who can't get girlfriends and are bitter about it online.
It was incels who contributed to our culture the concept of chads, that is beautiful, wealthy,
masculine men.
For incels, taking the red pill means buying into an ideology which says that women only
want to date chads, or else they want to marry beta cucks just to take their beta bucks.
Gas keep, gate boss, girl light.
So if you're an incel, you can either go to the gym and try to become a chad, that's a
bad emulation, the aspiration to attain what another person has, or, and this is the more
popular option, you can take the black pill, which means believing that chadhood is genetically
determined at birth, there is no hope, no woman will ever want you, and therefore happiness
is impossible, you may as well lie down and rot.
This mindset of resentment has inspired so many mass murders, there's an entire Wikipedia
timeline dedicated to tracking them.
And the essential motivation for this violence is...
The black pill.
Inã¾ã‚Š's day, one indication of it all, is, envy.
The incels failed ambition.
And sense of incurable, predestined inferiority turns venomous.
The logic behind the violence is, if I can't get a girlfriend, if I can't get what I want,
then no one can.
In the words of a murderer.
The day of retribution, is my attempt to destroy everything I cannot have."
But most incels aren't murderers, most of the time envy is most harmful to the person
who envies.
The philosopher Max Scheler called it a self-poisoning of the mind.
There's a Christian saying that envy is the only sin that gives no pleasure.
Because the other sins are fun, right?
Greed, gluttony, lust.
That's what I call a good time.
But envy is misery.
Though I wouldn't go so far as to say it gives no pleasure.
Fire Festival is an art installation where mediocre people realize what their lives would
be like without rich parents.
Parents, yes.
Rich refugee crisis.
We're living in a moment of growing inequality and resentment.
Look around you.
We've got the guillotine memes.
We've got edgy teens tweeting eat the rich.
And none of this is new.
The slogan eat the rich actually originates with the philosopher of the French Revolution,
Jacques Gabor, who supposedly said,
When the people have no more to eat, they will eat the rich.
And fair enough.
It's a good source.
It's a protein.
But take it from me, kids.
Cannibalism is one of those tricky things.
It's hard to do just once.
You develop a taste for it.
It's like they say at NA meetings.
Once you've wore, you just want more.
Also, who counts as the rich?
Am I the rich?
I certainly hope so, because I want you to eat me.
Stop it.
See this is why I quit academia.
If I was a professor, I'd have to behave myself.
And I don't want to behave myself.
I want to be bad.
Do you want to be bad?
Do you want to be bad with me?
Let's be bad.
So you might think that envy is simply the
The rich.
simply the product of inequality, and that societies that have more inequality have more
envy. I used to assume that too, but the more I think about it, the more I realize that might not
be true. Envy is a basic part of human nature. It exists in all societies and all economic systems,
and it begins anytime two or more people start comparing themselves.
Part 2. The Desire for Mommy's Milk
According to Sigmund Freud, or as I call him, Daddy, the first stage of human development is
the oral stage, in which the primary concern is oral gratification, which is of course provided
by mommy milkies. Am I doing too much? I'll tone it down, just a little bit.
So look, I get that a lot of people are skeptical about Freud, and it's true,
he was a bit of a crackpot coke fiend who had some zany ideas. Like penis envy. Maybe there's
truth to that, but I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't
know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. I don't know. Hmm.
Transgender men who experienced that. But I don't think it's a basic
factor for the female condition. As for castration anxiety, is that a dare?
Because I take that personally. I'm giving it very serious consideration, doctor,
but I feel like even when Freud is wrong he's often at least onto something. Like,
with the oedipus complex, it's not that you literally desire your mother right that would
be weird, it's more that you desire an archetype. Mother. Right? Mommy. You guys get it. Gen Z
tiktok lesbians get it they're the ones who got me started on this milf shit i'm a reverse socrates
i've been corrupted by the young my innocent and delicate nature has been defiled so freud says
that in the first two years of life libido is primarily focused on mommy's milk and it's also
in this stage that envy first emerges so i was the oldest child in my family and i was less than two
years old when my brother was born so i don't remember this because i was one year old but my
family tells me that when my brother was born i was just insanely jealous oh and i guess now is a
good time to discuss the difference between jealousy and envy scholars agree that there is a
difference and usually and usually they describe the difference in one of two ways the first is
that jealousy is defensive it's a kind of protectiveness over what is rightfully yours
whereas envy is offensive it's resentment over what someone else has that you lack and the second
difference is that
envy is between two people the envier and the envied whereas jealousy typically involves three
people as in romantic jealousy where you have the subject the romantic object and then the rival and
the subject is jealous of the rival because they're protective of their relationship with the romantic
object and that's also the dynamic of sibling rivalry just substituting the romantic object
for mommy of course in ordinary english people are always going to say jealousy when they really mean
envy probably because jealousy has less negative connotations
and i think it's pointless to try to fight that like i wouldn't go around correcting people but
just keep in mind that there is a difference so sibling rivalry is that envy or jealousy well i
think it's both because initially you're defensive of your privileged only child relationship with
your parents but a new baby often gets more attention at least in your paranoid toddler brain
and you might be envious of that and in romantic jealousy you may also envy the rival if she has
qualities that you wish you had
you know young kids are little egotists who are very sensitive to when another child might be
getting preferential treatment one of the favorite phrases of tiny babies is it's not fair it's not
fair tell me about it bambino and i've got bad news life is not getting any more fair than this
according to the bible one of the first events in human history is the story of cain
i don't know why
i said it in spanish i guess i just thought it would sound cool was i wrong
it just sounds so much better than cain king and abel cain and abel god tells cain and abel
each to make a sacrifice and then god prefers abel's you know because god loves meat then
in an act of malicious envy toward abel in spite towards god the father
kain kills his younger brother in my earliest memories of my brother i already loved him
and i don't remember the envy so i guess i wasn't a cain cain
so i must have somehow worked through this without resorting to murder
freud says that the older sibling's envy of the younger leads to a recognition of impotence because
at first you selfishly want to be the special most loved child but you see that your parents love
your sibling just as much as you and you're powerless to do anything about it so your ambition
to superiority fails and so you have no choice but to repress your ambition to superiority as well as
your envy and the result of that repression is what we could call herd instinct solidarity this
feeling of identifying with a group the equal siblings and as you get older the herd instinct
evolves into feelings about justice duty community and equality but freud thought these feelings
retain a vestige of repressed envy if i can't be the favorite if i can't have special privileges
then no one can and from these observations freud made the generalization social justice means that
we deny ourselves many things so that others may have to do without them as well okay so we don't
want other people to have anything we can't have so we enviously insist on equality
as a defense against the greater prosperity of others now i don't think i completely agree with
that like i think freud is definitely onto something here but don't some of our community
feelings also come from a place of genuine care for other people i cared for someone once
wrong well we'll come back to that later let's put a pin in me for now a pin in it for now in order to
make it work for you
freud i mean let's put a pin in freud
in a 1966 book titled envy a theory of social behavior the sociologist helmut shook argued
that rather than being that is a very german name helmut shook it's putting me in a german mood
sweetie hello myna liban hoyta gifts i know yes video i just get worse at german every year shook
argued that rather than being the result of social or economic inequality envy is a universal across
all human societies including very egalitarian ones for example in tribal and village cultures
around the world there's often a concept of black magic or witchcraft which are thought to be used
by envious people to bewitch the ones they envy you're probably familiar with the concept of the
evil eye which originates in ancient greece or maybe even earlier than that cultures all over
the world today understand the evil eye as a kind of curse cast by the malignant gaze of an enemy's
envious person now you might be thinking that sounds superstitious but i actually think the
concept of the evil eye reveals a more sophisticated awareness of envy and of the social danger that it
poses you've probably seen these amulets around there's an emoji for them now which are supposed
to protect against the evil eye it's called a nazar which comes from the arabic word for sight
or surveillance similar to the origin of the english word envy which is the latin invidia
which just means to look at so there's an agreement across the
cultures that envy is related to sight the malevolent gaze the evil eye and these amulets
show that a lot of people are afraid of being envied and want to protect themselves i was just
watching this turkish youtube channel with an episode on the evil eye and the host explains
that for muslims it's customary to say or god has willed it when admiring a person or object
you know to avoid unintentionally cursing them i love that it's like no envy like no homo but no
love the top comment on that video says you want to protect yourself from the evil green eye monster
well don't tell others about your ideas goals or wishes don't be flaunting your accomplishments on
social media or posting pictures of your children that's how you avoid being jinxed see this is where
kim kardashian went wrong with her birthday post clearly no one in the kardashian cinematic universe
has ever heard of the evil eye wait i thought these people were armenians why haven't they heard
a thief oh
okay never mind every piece of media they've ever produced is about flaunting an enviable lifestyle
this is a particularly american thing most americans have no concept of the fear of envy
like there's advertisements here that literally promise if you buy this exclusive
luxury vibrator you'll be the envy of all your friends as if it's a good thing to be envied oh
but it is not if people envy you they gossip about you right they seethe over your success
and celebrate your misfortunes being envied is basically the opposite of being loved so why would
anyone want to be envied well it's a contradiction of human nature on the one hand we need to be
loved but then there's this other drive in us this like homeric striving for fame and glory and
riches which is kind of in conflict with our need to be loved in a past gilded age there were stories
like citizen kane and sunset boulevard which warned what a sad and lonely life would be like in the
past gilded age there were stories like citizen kane and sunset boulevard which warned what a sad and
lonely thing success can become.
In ancient democratic Athens, there was a practice called ostracismos, which is the
origin of the English word ostracism.
Ostracism was a procedure where the Athenians would assemble, and each person would write
the name of a person they wanted to ostracize on a pottery shard called an ostracon.
And whoever got the most votes would simply be banished from the city for ten years, no
questions asked.
I love the ancient world, things were so direct.
Often this was used to remove someone who was becoming too prominent or too arrogant
or just annoying.
According to Plutarch, I'm just going to read this from Wikipedia, in one anecdote
about Aristides, known as Aristides the Just, who was ostracized in 482, an illiterate citizen
not recognizing him came up to ask him to write the name Aristides on his ostracon.
When Aristides asked why, the man replied,
It was because he was sick of hearing him being called the Just.
It's good!
It's so good!
See, this is why the idea of cancel culture is absurd.
This has been going on since the dawn of civilization.
People in most cultures, not all, but most cultures understand that being envied is a
massive social liability, so it's best not to draw too much attention to yourself.
According to a Tamil saying, the tree that bears fruit will be stoned.
This is sometimes called Tall Poppy Syndrome.
Tall Poppy Syndrome.
Tallest poppies in the garden will be cut.
Shook argues that the fear of envy is a major inhibiting force in many societies.
In Haiti, G.E. Simpson found that a peasant will seek to disguise his true economic position
by purchasing several smaller fields rather than one larger piece of land.
For the same reason, he will not wear good clothes.
He does this intentionally to protect himself against the envious black magic of his neighbors.
Now this kind of thing is not unheard of in America, like I've known people from seriously
wealthy families.
They dress like gutter punks, like they're trying to pass as poor.
But in general, Americans don't openly acknowledge fear of envy, in the way many other cultures
do.
And I don't think that's an accident.
We're a nation of show-offs, and so the taboo against discussing envy is related to
our whole national ethos of shoving our wealth in everyone's face.
But though the fear of envy isn't widely talked about or admitted here, it's definitely
still there, only repressed.
Confined to the realm of dreams and art.
The fear of envy isn't widely talked about or admitted here, it's definitely still
there, only repressed.
In the movie Black Swan, Nina is a perfection-obsessed ballerina who achieves her dream of getting
the lead role in Swan Lake, after which her life and mind are totally unraveled by fear
of envy.
Black magic, black swan.
At first we see how Nina's success comes at the very real cost of being envied.
By her ex-ballerina mother, by the other girls in the company, and by the former lead ballerina
she's replaced.
Did you suck his c**k?
Not all of us have to.
I love Winona Ryder so much.
I love Natalie Portman so much.
I love Mila Kunis so much.
I just like women.
Where's my shock wand?
Stop it.
Stop stanning.
But reasonable fear of envy becomes paranoia, as Nina begins hallucinating black swan doppelgangers
and is seduced by bisexual demon Mila Kunis, who's trying to steal her role.
You gotta watch out for those bisexual demons.
They'll getcha.
Did you hear that?
I don't.
Stop.
You could argue that Nina is actually suffering a kind of self-envy, where she envies the
disinhibited, sexually liberated, corrupted part of herself that's capable of adult eroticism
and also of dancing the black swan.
So she imagines that part of herself as an envious rival who's trying to replace her.
It's like her mind is split between two impulses.
There's her dominant White Swan Impulse, which we could call the Squidward personality, perfectionistic
and orderly, but reserved, priggish, stiff.
And then there's her repressed Black Swan Impulse, which we could call the SpongeBob
personality, intuitive, chaotic, ecstatic.
In SpongeBob SquarePants, the character Squidward is fundamentally a figure of envy, stemming
from failed ambition.
Hello, you've reached the house of unrecognized talent.
Squidward aspires to artistic achievement, but remains a mediocrity, partly because of
his overly dry, doctrinaire attitude towards art.
SpongeBob is Squidward's social equal, they're literally neighbors, and they both work the
same fast food service job for the same exploitative capitalist.
But SpongeBob is a Mozartian intuitive genius, who's able to transform the most mundane
activities, glowing bubbles, flippin' bubbles, into the world of art.
From flipping burgers, into a kind of aesthetic rapture.
Squidward intensely envies SpongeBob's uninhibited joy and intuitive creativity, but he can't
admit that envy to himself.
So he convinces himself that what he's really feeling is contempt, snobbish disdain for
SpongeBob's childish behavior.
What the people want is culture, not dancing bubbles.
Though deep down, Squidward really wants what SpongeBob has.
It's beautiful!
Uh, I mean, uh.
Which we see when he can't help himself from blowing bubbles, or when he trades away
all of his possessions for the chewing gum wrapper that in SpongeBob's hands was a
source of infinite entertainment.
A lot of people my age who watched SpongeBob as a kid rewatch it now, and are horrified
to discover that they identify with Squidward, whereas as children, they identified with
SpongeBob.
Well, you either die as SpongeBob, or you live long enough to see yourself become the
Squidward.
Future!
And there's a lot more to it.
And there's a pain in becoming Squidward, which is usually explained as the disappointing
drudgery of adult life, or simply loss of childhood.
I would argue that envy of childhood is the distinctive Squidwardian emotion.
Squidwardian?
Are we saying that word?
Are we really saying that word out loud?
To an audience of millions?
Okay!
It's basically the same dynamic as Salieri's envy of Mozart in Amadeus.
Oh my god, the evil eye killed Mozart!
Oh my god!
It's the evil eye!
You gotta watch out for that one, kids!
If a mysterious stranger shows up on your doorstep at midnight asking you to compose
a requiem math for your own father, just say no!
So in SpongeMadeus Mozart pants, we have a diligent-tho-stuffy wannabe envying the effortless
playfulness of the spontaneous genius.
Ah!
So Squidward's envy of SpongeBob is, well, it's Apollo's envy of Dionysus.
Look, if we were to view SpongeBob SquarePants through the philosophy of Friedrich Nietzsche,
stay with me ladies, I have an angle here,
we could say that Squidward represents what Nietzsche called the Apollonian impulse,
while SpongeBob represents the Dionysian.
Nietzsche thought there were two conflicting artistic drives in the human personality.
The Apollonian, named after the Greek god Apollo, is the drive towards self-control,
order, logic, morality.
And the Dionysian, named after Dionysus, is the drive toward intoxication, frenzy, passion,
intuition.
Both SpongeBob and Amadeus present these two drives in conflict,
with the Apollonian envying the Dionysian.
Of course, this is a misrepresentation of how art is actually created,
because Nietzsche's whole point is that you need a balance
of the two drives.
In reality, you cannot have a pure Dionysian artist like SpongeBob,
because creating good art requires at least some level of discipline in ordering.
See? It is all in the technique.
Otherwise, you're just some drunk idiot with a guitar.
Get off the stage!
So Black Swan is, in a way, actually more realistic.
In order to give the perfect performance,
Mina has to unify her fragmented personality and dance both swans,
resolving the envious rivalry between her
and the two artistic impulses.
It was perfect.
Another movie about fear of envious ballerina doppelgangers
Can you guess it?
is Jordan Peele's 2019 horror film Us,
which dramatizes the repressed economic guilt and fear of the American middle class.
We meet the Wilsons, a moderately affluent family with a vacation house
and a boat, along with the Tylers, a slightly better-off white family,
whom the Wilsons envy.
You saw their new car, right?
You had to do it.
You just had to get that thing to fuck with me, too.
One night, the Wilsons' vacation home is invaded by a family of their own monstrous doppelgangers.
Red, the only doppelganger who can speak,
explains that her family is metaphysically tethered to the Wilsons,
living wretched and destitute versions of their lives
in a liminal backroom's office.
Underworld.
It's super-fucking-liminal.
I'm on Ambien at an AA meeting.
Not again.
Once upon a time, there was a girl, and the girl had a shadow.
The two were connected, tethered together.
When the girl ate, her food was given to her warm and tasty.
But when the shadow was hungry, she had to eat rabbit, raw and bloody.
We later find out that all over the US,
oh, US spells us,
hey, that's the title of the movie.
Ohhhh.
The tethered have risen up to kill their privileged doppelgangers
and to link arms across the country
in a dark parody of the real-world 1986 homelessness fundraiser
Hands Across America.
So my reading of Us is that it's an expression of middle-class guilt about privilege
and fear of envy.
It's not a movie about the working class.
If it was a movie about the working class,
then the working class would be able to speak humanly.
And would not be scary monsters who make animal sounds
and stagger around like zombies.
This is a movie about the anxious middle class's nightmare of the working class.
Us represents in a self-aware way what other home invasion movies represent unconsciously.
The fear of the envious poor.
Of revolution.
Of slave revolt.
Tell me you did not just reference Home Alone.
But Us diverges from other home invasion movies
by not just being fearful about the underclass,
but also guilty.
The idea of the tethered underclass
represents life as a zero-sum game
where every moment of your happiness
is bought with someone else's suffering.
It's an incredibly guilty fantasy.
An internalization of the black magic logic
of people who blame their own misfortunes
on the people they envy.
As Shook puts it,
my neighbor's harvest
can only have turned out better than mine.
And it's not just me.
My neighbor's harvest
can only have turned out better than mine.
Because he has somehow succeeded in reducing mine by black magic.
So the fear of envy
and the guilt of success
are repressed in American culture.
But they still find expression in movies.
Jordan Peele is kind of like the Charles Dickens
of the 21st century.
Us actually reminds me of A Christmas Carol.
A story about the guilt of the rich
if ever there was one.
You know, Scrooge is visited by ghosts
who show him how wretched and sad
the lives of his employees are
and how he'll die alone
and hated by everyone
and his funeral is only attended by businessmen
on the condition that lunch is provided.
Dickens was truly the master
of scaring the rich straight.
So maybe fear of envy
can serve a softly regulatory function
by motivating charity
and generosity in the rich.
But in general, I'm suspicious of envy
as a motivation for politics.
Because remember,
the basic logic of envy is
if I can't have it,
I can't.
Which is a purely negative, destructive
style of thinking.
It's taking privileges away
not for the material benefit of the underprivileged
but merely for the psychological satisfaction
of the envious person.
And that's even worse
when you consider that envy is subjective.
It doesn't necessarily target
objective power and privilege.
So envy in politics
is not by any means
relegated to the left.
Conservative politics is brimming with envy.
In the debate about forgiving student loan debt,
you often hear people say
I had to pay my student loans
so they should too.
Debt forgiveness is not fear.
The logic here is
since I didn't get my student debt forgiven,
no one should.
It's intergenerational envy.
Which is a pretty common thing.
Usually older generations
envying the young.
Kids these days have it so easy.
When I was young, we ate nails for breakfast
and sent text messages
to the phone.
The feeling is basically
it's not fair that kids these days
don't have to suffer like I suffered.
Or think about the concept
of a welfare queen
which openly reeks of envy and white resentment.
Or the way conservatives talk about immigration.
It's all this envious suspicion
about illegal immigrants
sneaking in
and getting government handouts
without having to pay taxes.
I had to work hard for my money
so why should these people get a free ride?
What is an illegal immigrant
is actually like,
except in the imagination
of people who envy them.
Envy is felt more intensely
by prideful people.
So it's especially sharp
when it targets people
who are supposed to be beneath you.
The Jewish radical feminist
Andrea Dworkin
made what I think
is a pretty compelling argument
that both antisemitism
and misogyny
are the main protagonists
of Tolstoy's story
The Kreutzer Sonata
who resents that women and Jews
find a kind of paradoxical power
in their own oppression.
Just like the Jews
as they pay us back for their oppression
by financial domination
so it is with women.
Ah, you want us to be traitors only?
Alright.
As traitors we will dominate you,
say the Jews.
Ah, you want us to be merely objects of sensuality?
This dominance of men by women
is experienced by the men
as real. Emotionally real.
Sexually real. Psychologically real.
It emerges as the reason
for the wrath of the misogynist.
The woman appears to control sex.
The man needs it.
This causes his rage
at her perceived power over him.
Women control access
to what men want
which gives women a kind of indirect power
that some men envy.
They envy the sexual power
of women.
It doesn't matter to the misogynist
that, especially at the time
Tolstoy was writing,
women objectively have less power
in society than men.
He envies women because they have
what he desires.
Likewise, it didn't matter
to Weimar anti-Semites
that Jewish people were a marginalized minority.
Anti-Semitism is often rooted
in an envious obsession
with the disproportionate influence
and affluence of Jewish people.
There are no differences between men
which feed envy,
but subjective perception,
the optics of envy.
Magic mirror
on the wall,
who's the cuntest of them all?
Thou art
cunt, my queen.
But hold,
a lovely maid
I see.
Oh yes,
What?
In a way,
I'm kind of just in the beginning
of this whole transition,
you know, like a young little girl
going through all these things,
having a sleepover with the girls.
What do we do on a sleepover?
Do we have like pillow fights
and all that stuff?
Alas,
she is more cunt than thee.
My pussy's stunting on the gram
The classic 1937 Disney movie
Snow White and the Wicked Milf
is the story of a quote
vain and wicked queen
who obsessively envies the beauty
of her own stepdaughter.
Are you sure this one's for children?
Every day the milf queen asks the mirror
who's the fairest one of all
and the mirror responds that the queen is the fairest
till one day it says the stepdaughter
Snow White is the fairest
which sends the queen into an envious fury
resulting in a series of bizarre murder attempts.
So first of all,
why don't we talk plot holes, ding?
Are we really supposed to believe
that this is more beautiful
than this?
Uh, ding!
Isn't Snow White like 12 years old?
What's going on, Walt?
Why don't you take a seat?
Maybe she's not 12, I don't know.
It's hard to tell because she's constantly
surrounded by manlets.
But she's just so boring.
And the queen is such a baddie.
Step on my throat, mother.
This is a horny video.
I can feel the pulse back in my veins.
So despite the injustice done
to its lead milf,
Snow White does illustrate some interesting things
about envy.
Once again, we have black magic and witchcraft
as an expression of envy.
We have the age difference,
intergenerational envy,
the envy of youth.
It kind of reminds me of those millennial women
who hit 30 and suddenly feel a need
to rage against Gen Z.
Pretty counterproductive since
if you're worried about seeming old,
it's probably not helping your case gorge.
You might wonder if there's also jealousy
involved with the evil queen.
Like, is she worried that the king is gonna fall in love
with his own daughter?
Well, I don't think so.
Because we never even see the king.
The queen doesn't mention him.
It's not about the king.
So there's no romantic jealousy involved.
It's just one woman envying another woman
over beauty for its own sake.
We stan a Bechdel test passing
movie about women hating each other.
Gatekeep? Gas Girl?
Gas Keep? Light Boss?
In fact, in the original Brothers Grimm version,
the queen first tries killing Snow White
with beauty accessories,
poisoning a comb and lacing her to death
with a corset.
I wish I could die that way.
What's really striking is the pure
kamikaze malignity of it all.
This queen, who we know
is obsessed with her look,
is willing to transform herself with witchcraft
into an ugly old hag
just to give Snow White
the poisoned apple.
Disguising herself as an old hag
parallels Satan disguising himself as a serpent.
I mean, you could actually argue
that the queen is simply a persona of Satan.
It's paradise lost all over again.
Which also happens to be
the title of my memoir.
The queen is incredibly petty,
because even according to the, again,
wrong and tasteless mirror,
she's still the second most beautiful woman
in the world.
How could someone so close to the top of the hierarchy
still be consumed by envy?
Well,
basically, because that's how envy works.
It's petty,
it's subjective,
and it's indifferent to the magnitude of the inequality
or to the absolute
position on the overall hierarchy.
So you can be the second best in the world
and still be
obsessively envious of the one
person who may barely even be above you.
In fact, there's studies showing
that Olympic silver medalists
are actually less satisfied with their prize
than bronze medalists.
Probably because the bronze medalist is just happy
to be on the podium at all,
while the silver medalist is so close to first,
they can't help but wonder
what if?
Humans form our sense of identity and self-worth
not by comparing ourselves to any absolute
standard, but by comparing ourselves
to each other. And we're more likely
to compare ourselves to the people who are around
us than we are to people who are far away.
We could call this
the proximity effect of envy.
We're more likely to envy people who are
close to us, or similar to us.
Especially people we're in competition with.
That's why social media
is such a nightmare. It's an incubator
of envy, because it puts everyone
next to everyone else.
So we're all being compared, all in competition.
And it can destroy your
self-esteem, because you're comparing
your actual life
to these idealized images.
And it also turns public figures into
lightning rods for envy,
because of the numeric visibility
of popularity and success.
It's a perverse consequence
of the proximity effect that
envy within an oppressed class
is often more venomous and obsessive
than envy for the oppressor.
So for example, in Snow White
and Black Swan,
you have women envying other women.
Because women are often in
competition with each other.
And I know it's kind of a misogynistic trope.
In media, there's constant portrayals of
vain and envious women.
Jealous bitches fighting
over men, over youth,
over beauty.
It's like drag queen femininity.
It becomes her femininity.
On guard!
Bitch!
So yeah, it's kind of a misogynistic trope.
But...
How do I put this delicately?
Sometimes reality is misogynistic.
Like when my eyelash won't stay glued on.
The patriarchy's machinations
are clearly to blame.
In her 1976 essay, Trashing
The Dark Side of Sisterhood,
feminist Jo Freeman wrote about her ostracism
from within the women's movement.
I've been watching for years
and I'm starting to say as the movement
consciously destroys anyone within it
who stands out in any way.
And she quotes a speech by fellow feminist
Anselma del Olio.
And who do they attack?
Achievement or accomplishment of any kind
would seem to be the worst crime.
Do anything that every other woman
secretly or otherwise feels she could do
just as well, and you're in for it.
You are immediately labeled a thrill-seeking
opportunist, a ruthless mercenary
out to make her fame and fortune
in the bodies of selfless sisters
who have buried their abilities
and sacrificed their ambitions
for the greater glory of feminism.
Freeman speculates.
The primary reason there have been
so few great women blank
is not merely that greatness
has been undeveloped
or unrecognized, but that women
exhibiting potential for achievement
are punished by both women and men.
The fear of success
is quite rational when one knows
that the consequence of achievement
is hostility and not praise.
So at no point in this essay
does Jo Freeman use the word envy.
But as usual, envy is right
below the surface, causing
all the trouble.
So Freeman is describing
how people from marginalized groups
whose ambition raises them above
the typical limits set by marginalization
are often ostracized
from their own communities.
But she has no causal explanation
for why this happens.
I have an explanation. The explanation is envy.
Women are more likely to envy other women.
Trans women are more likely
to envy other trans women.
Oh god, am I really gonna go there?
If we did this topic justice,
this video would be nine centuries long.
Angar!
Bitch!
A lot of people assume that trans women
envy cis women. And there is some truth to that.
There definitely was a time in my life
when I used to envy cis women
for being cis women.
But now I kind of just don't even allow myself
to have the thought,
to be a cis woman.
So in a way, because becoming a cis woman
is impossible, it's unobtainable,
I actually envy cis women less.
So trans women are more likely
to envy other trans women.
Because of the proximity effect
and because another trans woman
represents an actual possibility
of what I, a trans woman,
could become.
She's a standard to which I could
plausibly compare myself.
Here's a post someone made on my own fan subreddit.
Am I the only one who finds it hard
to watch trans creators?
Before I realized I was a trans woman,
I fucking loved people like ContraPoints,
Nick Spears, and other trans creators.
But ever since I realized I was trans,
I just get this angry, resentful feeling
in the pit of my stomach whenever I get recommended
any of these videos.
I seriously loved ContraPoints,
but whenever I try to watch any of her videos,
I just want to scream.
I have this feeling toward passing trans people in general.
I feel such hatred for them, and I don't know why.
Am I just a toxic person?
Well, sweetie, you're not a toxic person.
At least not any worse than anyone else.
It's just that human nature
is a toxic person.
And that angry, resentful feeling
in the pit of your stomach
that makes you want to scream
and feel such a hatred has a name.
And the name is Envy.
I actually admire the person who wrote this post
because they're doing the best that any of us
can do, really,
which is noticing the feeling
without endorsing the feeling.
I wish that more people could feel things
without rushing to a rational,
even if they don't want to.
It isn't rationality itself,
often simply the attempt to make our feelings contagious.
Sometimes people have no self-awareness
about it at all.
For example, there's a certain kind of
boomer transsexual who complains that
when I transitioned,
I had to go through rigorous medical gatekeeping,
but kids these days just waltz on in
and walk out with hormones.
It's intergenerational envy,
trans addition.
It was hard for me, so it should be hard for everyone.
Like the student debt-dippy.
If I can't have it, no one can.
And look, I do have sympathy
and admiration for older trans people.
Like, being trans in 2021
is already the maximum
level of adversity that I can handle.
I cannot imagine how hard
it was to do this in the 80s.
However, the pain of envy
is not a valid argument.
Envy is not sacred rage.
And the malignant demands of envious people
should be ignored.
God, this community.
The constant competition.
The cringing.
It makes it really hard to get along with other trans people.
Oh, speaking of which.
Gay tangent, everybody. Gay tangent.
Envy presents kind of a unique
problem to same-sex attracted people.
Because of the increased risk
of envying the very people
you're attracted to.
I wanna the ones I envy.
You know, it's the classic
do I want you or do I want to be you
problem. I've heard feminine queer
women say they could never date another
femme because they're worried
they would just end up envying her.
So dating masculine women solves that
problem. Because having separate roles,
separate aesthetics, separate
categories helps to avert
proximity envy between
partners. Unfortunately,
I am not that smart.
Basically, I am attracted
to femininity. But I also want to
embody a kind of feminine archetype
myself. I'm not masculine
and I don't wanna be. You know, I used to think
I'd only wanna date another trans woman
because of the mutual understanding
but I've kind of realized that at this point
it may actually be more psychologically healthy
for me to open up to dating cis women.
I used to not wanna do that because I was
afraid it would make me feel like a man. But at this point
honestly, just
be a man. Whatever.
It's fine.
As a drag queen once said,
I'm more of a man than you'll ever be. I'm more of a woman
than you'll ever have. Yes, glad.
Can we get the tequila out of the frame please?
I think at a distance
it's okay to indulge the attraction
emulation ambiguity. But if
you wanna actually have a relationship with someone,
you have to make up your mind
that you desire this woman
and you do not wanna be her.
Because think about it from the other perspective.
What could be less attractive
than someone who literally wants
to be you? Teacher,
make her stop copying
me. Like as much as I joke every
episode about how Buffalo Bill
is an iconic trans legend,
you don't wanna date that bitch.
Imagine trying to date Eve
from All About Eve. Pass.
Hard pass.
So if you're a queer woman, or a queer anything honestly,
and you find yourself envying your
partner, my advice is
stop overthinking a good situation.
An enviable woman wanted to be with
you. So sit back,
relax, and enjoy
the clout. I get it though.
It's complicated.
We're all supposed to proudly affirm what we
truly desire, but how do you know
what you truly desire? Do I want
mommy? Or do I wanna
be the mommy?
Yes. Just yes.
Anyway,
let's go back to talking about Sigmund Freud.
The mother half took over completely.
Do I look okay? Is my head on
straight? So,
we keep running into this avoidance
of the word envy.
And people especially cannot seem
to notice when they themselves are
feeling envious. Like that person who
was puzzled over the angry, resentful
feeling in the pit of their stomach without
being able to name what they were feeling.
There's two reasons why people are usually in
denial about their own envy. One is
guilt, and the other is shame.
Shame. Shame
because admitting to yourself that you
envy someone implies
that you feel inferior to them,
which is shameful. It wounds
the ego. And guilt
because envy is malicious.
If you envy someone, you may feel angry
and miserable about their success
and good fortune, and you may wish
to see them ruined or brought down.
That's cruel and antisocial.
It goes against most ideas
of morality, and it's a thought that's
usually not socially acceptable
to admit. So envy is shameful,
guilty,
and socially unacceptable. And we
deal with that by suppressing it
from our awareness. But it is still
there, and in order to maintain
the denial, we have to convince ourselves
that this angry, resentful
feeling in the pit of our stomach
is actually something else.
Think about how in Spongebob,
Squidward shows contempt for
Spongebob's childishness
for blowing bubbles, for having fun at
work, when in fact,
Squidward envies Spongebob's
uninhibited joy and intuitive
creativity. But he can't allow
himself to have the thought that he
envies Spongebob, because that would
mean recognizing the intolerably
shameful truth that he
feels inferior to Spongebob.
So what he does instead is
convince himself that what he really is
is a refined sophisticate
scoffing at this childish
fool.
We could call this envy to
contempt sublimation.
Sublimation is a psychoanalytic
term, which means that you transform
an ego-wounding feeling
or socially unacceptable longing
into something more
ego-flattering or socially acceptable.
So the classic example used by Freud
is the transformation of sexual
urges of erotic
energy into creative
expression. It's like the founder of the
NoFap movement, Lady Gaga,
once said,
I have this weird thing that if I sleep with someone,
they're gonna take my creativity from me through my
So according to Freud,
the vast majority of erotic longings
can never be fulfilled.
Tell me about it, Sigmund. Ugh.
Misery.
There's a positive side to this, supposedly,
which is that you can sublimate your
erotic longings into a more
socially acceptable productivity.
So, you know, instead of slicking the bean,
maybe you write novels
about thirsty vampires, or
for that matter, philosophical treatises
about the will to power.
Oh, we'll get to you. Freud thought that
civilization itself is built at the cost
of our instincts, most of which
we have to sacrifice in order to
live in a society. So like erotic
impulses, I think envy can
be sublimated, which is what's happening
when it becomes contempt.
Another example is the blog
McMansion Hell, which makes fun of the
tasteless architecture of suburban
ostentatious trash.
I would argue that part of the fun of this blog
is the pleasure and relief
of looking down
at the rich.
Because looking enviously up at the rich
is painful. It makes you feel
inferior. And a way to
alleviate that pain is to sublimate
envy, and pretend
that you're an aristocratic
esthete, scoffing at the vulgar
taste of the Ereveste.
These flying buttresses are an
extremely poor taste.
Another example is shit-talking
plastic surgery. I once heard a
trans woman say, at least I don't look
like a botched sex doll.
The subtext is, there's a certain kind of
trans woman influencer who lives in LA
and has a lot of cosmetic surgery
to achieve a doll-like aesthetic.
But it costs a lot of money to look
like this. And a lot of trans women can't
afford surgeries that they want.
And one way to cope with frustrated
desire is to convince yourself
that the thing that's out of reach
is not worth having anyway.
See also the discourse on Twitter
about how passing is transphobic.
There's an ancient Greek fable where
a fox wants some grapes, but he can't
reach the vine. So he walks away bitterly
and says, well the grapes are
transphobic anyway. The cisgender
version of this is maybe the not like
other girls meme. Which is classic
envy to contempt sublimation.
The trope is usually that other
girls are popular and slutty.
They have fake tans and fake nails.
They like partying and makeup
and stupid music for idiots.
But I'm quirky and real.
I listen to Pink Floyd
and read books and eat lots
of pizza late at night.
Alone and sad.
There's usually a subtext of anxiety
about inferiority. The other girls
being more socially accepted,
feminine, and put together.
A lot of times the other girls
don't even exist, right? They're a media
construct of idealized womanhood.
Like where are these other girls
who've never eaten pizza and enjoy
wearing makeup at 9am on a Saturday morning?
Are they between the sofa cushions?
Did you put them in with the other laundry?
Are the other girls in the room with us
right now? So the feeling of inferiority
toward the other girls is
reframed as a kind of contemptuous
hipster superiority. Which is
really just an ego defensive persona
of resentment. Like Janice
in Mean Girls. She's not even really a lesbian.
She's Lebanese.
Regina got confused.
And then she dances with a boy at the end.
And is readmitted into girlhood.
Thank you for that Tina Fey, that's very helpful.
Great.
Another way we can reframe feelings of
envious inferiority is by
transforming them into moral
superiority. Moral superiority
often being the refuge
of people with nothing better
to feel superior about. We don't have to
feel guilty or ashamed of envy
if we convince ourselves that we're
actually experiencing
is justified, legitimate
hatred. So for example,
think of the morality around sexuality.
Part 69
Sluts. Yeah, what are you gonna do
about it? Cancel me?
On guard!
Bitch! Why does everyone hate
sluts so much? Sluts never did nothing
wrong to nobody. Open sexual
promiscuity is in a way analogous
to opulence. You're conspicuously
enjoying something that other
people want, but may not be able
to get. Many cultures have
norms about modesty. For example,
expecting women to cover their hair
in public. This is usually explained
as prophylaxis against male
lust, but I wonder if it also
serves to prevent a more
generalized envy, which female
beauty has a way of attracting.
Men often slut shame
because they want to control female sexuality.
And by female sexuality,
I do mean male sexuality.
Because often what they're really struggling
to control is their own
desire. But slut shaming is also
done pretty viciously by
women to each other. And that's a
complicated thing. It's more than just
envy. Sometimes it comes from a sense that
a woman who's having casual sex
with a lot of men is compromising
the collective sex withholding
power of the group. Almost like
she's crossing a picket line. But there's
also sometimes a resentment
that a woman who's showing skin
is using her body to get
unearned attention.
And that smells like envy to me.
I don't use my body to get attention.
So no one should.
The repressed feeling is
maybe I'm a little jealous that she's
getting all this attention by posting
thirst traps. But you don't think that.
You think, I
am above this. Because I
am chaste. I
have class. I
am a feminist. I would also
suggest accusing her of pandering to the
male gaze. That's, of course, the
feminist way of calling someone a
lowdown hobag skank.
So again we have envy to contempt
sublimation. And often the contempt
is moral. Virtuous.
The psychological
need to convince ourselves
that envy is morality
can become so strong
that we actually start inventing things
to be outraged about. Take
for instance the tendency to imagine
that the wealthy and powerful are
enjoying wild satanic
orgies and indulging all the
forbidden salacious pleasures
that we ourselves are denied.
Like QAnon, these conspiracy
theorists who want us to imagine
Hillary Clinton reclining
in a garden of earthly delights
sampling the pleasures of
ephibes.
Live, laugh, love
that for her. Envy is very
imaginative when it comes to the
hedonistic extravagance of the envied.
Let's talk about Marie Antoinette,
the queen of France who was guillotined
by the revolution. If you know
one thing about Marie Antoinette,
it's probably that when she heard about a family
famine where the people had no bread,
she infamously responded,
let them eat cake.
What an evil bitch.
How could she say that? Well,
she didn't.
She never said it.
It's a lie. The phrase
let them eat cake, originally
let them eat brioche, first appeared
in Rousseau's Confessions, written in
1765 when Marie
Antoinette was nine years old.
Rousseau attributed the line to
a great princess.
It's probably no one ever said this.
It's kind of like how the most famous photo
of Paris Hilton is the one where
she's wearing a stop being poor
t-shirt. What an evil
bitch. How could she wear that?
Well, she didn't.
It's photoshopped.
The actual shirt said stop being
desperate. Envy likes to
fabricate the diabolical
crimes of its enemies. I assume
to compliment the hedonistic extravagance.
I mean, what is a Disney villain
if not an opulent homosexual
seen through the eyes of the envious?
I'm gonna try lowering
the ISO because it's so f***ing bright in here
now. Okay, well it's a
much lower ISO. What if I get another
white over here? That's what this channel's really about.
One biological female's quest
to create a harmonious color story.
In the years leading up to and
during the French Revolution,
Marie Antoinette was constantly defamed
in these sleazy tabloids
called libelle.
It's the same root as the English word libel.
The often pornographic libelle
depicted the queen as a bisexual
demon who was constantly having
drunken orgies and sexually manipulating
everyone around her. All of which
is very interesting, but
none of which is true.
The historian Robert Darnton called it
an avalanche of defamation
that has no parallel in the
history of vilification. This
woman took the blame,
the moral blame, for the
structural failings of a broken
economic system. And by the time
she was brought before the revolutionary tribe
in 1793,
the actual person Marie Antoinette
had long ago been overshadowed
by the libellous caricature of her.
Now there was maybe one
good reason for executing the former
queen, which is that the legitimacy
of your new republic is a
little more secure when you don't have
living monarchs hanging around.
Someone better tell the English.
But the problem with that reasoning
is it has nothing to do with whether
or not the queen deserved
to die. And beheading a recently
widowed mother of two in front of
a jeering crowd for political expediency
might weigh a little
heavy on the conscience.
So the revolution had to convince themselves
that the queen deserved it.
Which was pretty easy after decades
of, again, false and
defamatory gossip. In her biography
of Marie Antoinette, Antonia
Frazier describes how
the prison guards separated Marie
from her eight-year-old son, who they
plied with alcohol and groomed
into accusing his own mother
of incestuous abuse.
To justify killing Marie
Antoinette, they had to destroy
the idea of this woman
as a mother. So she was convicted
of what may as well have been
crimes against ethics in games journalism
and sent to the guillotine
where her last words were
sorry to the executioner for
stepping on his foot.
Uh, women stop
apologizing challenge. This is what a
girl boss winning looks like.
So Marie Antoinette literally
did nothing wrong.
Hey, how are you?
An innocent milf was killed
that day and I, for one,
won't stand for it.
So look, we have a
psychological incentive
to believe that people whom
we envy are immoral monsters.
Because then, we get to label our
hatred and violence toward them justice.
Cruelty generally
cannot conceptualize itself
as cruelty. And part of the
reason for that is that calling
cruelty what it is
takes the fun out of it.
It reminds me of the second best day
in the history of Twitter.
October 1st, 2020.
The day that Trump got COVID.
And I'm gonna be honest, I have never
felt more schadenfreude
in my entire life.
Well, well, well.
If it isn't the leopards eating people's faces
party having their faces eaten by
leopards.
Last time I ate cake.
Like Dan Savage said,
it felt like Ronald Reagan got AIDS.
The next day, I tweeted,
These last 24 hours have been the first time
I've genuinely enjoyed Twitter in years.
Because this website is good for one thing only,
reveling in the cruelest of human impulses.
And someone responded to that
saying,
Oh my god, could you even be
a bigger killjoy?
But why was I being a killjoy?
The tweet was about how much I was enjoying it.
Well, for most people, I guess not
me, but for normal people,
for other girls, cruelty is only
pleasurable as long as they can convince
themselves it's something other than
cruelty. Justice served.
So again, reason,
rationality, are often the attempt
to publicly communicate,
to evangelize our
private feelings. And morality,
ethics, and justice
are often put forward
as the respectable public
face of private
envy, vindictiveness,
and hatred. But is this a
corruption of morality?
Or have we stumbled onto something
darker? What if morality
itself is simply the
expression of some kind of
sadomasochistic urge?
It's too early for this.
I mean, it's literally 7am
where I'm filming. I don't know how this keeps
happening to me. My head gets cut off one afternoon,
puts me in a philosophical mood.
The next morning,
I've stayed up all night and I'm still talking about
the philosophes.
Meow meow.
Hello again, kittens.
Let's talk about justice, uwu.
I look like a Supreme Court justice.
So nya? So to meow your?
It would actually be fierce if I wasn't,
you know, if I wasn't being nyadily.
Look, I've been seeing a lot
of comments lately along the lines of
Natalie used to do serious
academic arguments. Now she
only cares about makeup.
Alright, you little shits. You want
book learning? I'm gonna learn you so
hard. I'm gonna learn you so hard you're gonna
have a god damn
headache in the morning. Friedrich
Nietzsche. Friedrich
Wilhelm Nietzsche. Do you mind if I call you Fred?
Friedrich was a German philosopher
who had a lot to say about
envy and morality. But before
we get into that, I want to say a little bit about his
life, because it's just very
funny. Nietzsche's famous for his concept
of the Ubermensch, but Friedrich
sweet,
beautiful little Friedrich,
he was not what most people think of as an Ubermensch.
Friedrich was a chronically
ill, chronically in pain,
nearly blind incel
who probably slept with a prostitute
once and got syphilis and
died. Life is
funny. Sad, but funny.
In the introduction to Beyond
Good and Evil, the editor says
though he prided himself on being
comfortable with women, he does not seem to have been
very successful in establishing emotionally
satisfying relationships with them,
which is hardly surprising.
I love when the introduction to a book is just a
brutal roast of the author.
Who wrote this? Rolf Peter Horstmann.
You're killing it, Rolf. You're a savage.
I adore. Friedrich's books
sold a dismal number of copies
in his lifetime. What emerges
is a picture of a totally isolated,
highly neurotic man who had
to try hard to avoid thinking of
himself as a complete failure.
Aww. He was also doing huge doses of
opium, relatable, and writing himself
prescriptions for sleeping pills using
the name Dr. Nietzsche.
Dr. Nietzsche? Pretty sure I got a Xanax
prescription from that guy once.
Behind a Dairy Queen.
Nietzsche was also a failed musician and
was in love with the composer Richard Wagner's
wife.
The Virgin Nietzsche contra the
Chad Wagner. You beta cuck.
Why did I do that?
Can we all agree that Catgirl Nietzsche
is by far the most cursed thing I've ever done?
I just want to mom this guy, honestly.
I don't even care that he's a misogynist.
His misogyny is simply
too sad to be offended by. You know, I think
it's interesting that a person this
pathetic can also be a genius
whose name will never die. He's someone
who had a lot of reason to be envious
and self-pitying, but his philosophy
couldn't be more against that.
And as a person of pathetic experience
myself, that is unironically kind
of inspiring to me. So let's
go in. In his book on the
genealogy of morality, Frederick
wants to explain the origin
of the concepts of good and evil.
Under what conditions did man invent
the value judgments good and evil, and
what value do they themselves have?
Have they to now obstructed or
promoted human flourishing? Hang on, my food's
here. That's right, you're getting a mukbang,
sweetie. Did you think I was gonna sit at this
giant table and not be eating something?
This video's been going on more than an hour, so I assume
you guys are drunk by now, and we're just kind of
hanging out at this point. You guys can't even
see. Well, here. I've got
a bunch of sushi, and it's my mission to eat
all of this while summarizing the entire life
and work of Friedrich Nietzsche.
Trisha Paytas, Nikocado, consider
this a challenge. So Frederick argues
that good and bad, not
good and evil, that's different, we'll get to that,
but good and bad were originally
the self-affirming values
of people with power.
So to be good meant to be powerful,
strong, beautiful, healthy.
And to be bad meant to be
weak, sick,
common, ugly.
I'm gonna eat one like a cat.
And Frederick supports this speculation
with etymology. So in a lot
of languages, the word that means morally
good or spiritually noble
originally meant noble in the sense
of aristocratic, the propertied
class. Like in Buddhism,
the Arya Satyani, that's
Sanskrit for noble truths.
Arya means noble.
And Arya is used to mean spiritually
noble, but earlier it meant
the aristocracy, the rich.
And originally, it was just the name that a culture
in northern India gave themselves,
the Aryans. I'm really
working not to get soy sauce on this list.
This was later misunderstood by Europeans
who wrongly thought
that Aryan was a race.
Oops.
Goddammit.
Goddammit, kids. Can we not?
Frederick traces the origin of the
German word gut, or the English
good, to the name of the Goths.
No, not those Goths.
The Scandinavian people who invaded Europe.
Frederick calls them the blonde
beasts of prey. I like to
stalk my prey in the small hours
of the night.
The German word schlecht, which means
bad, is related to schlicht, which
means plain, simple, originally
common, low, not
aristocratic, not noble.
So good and bad
were originally the values of warrior
aristocrats who were like Homeric
heroes celebrating themselves.
And Frederick calls their value
system master morality.
This glorification of combat,
feasting, athleticism,
sexual conquest,
beauty. These things
were called good. And their
opposites, weakness, impotence,
ugliness, were called bad.
The ancient nobles worshipped
noble gods who acted like them
and shared their values. I mean, if I created
a personal goddess, I think we all know
what animal that would be. Me and the ancient
Egyptians on the same page. So for
example, Roman warriors could
worship Mars, the god of war.
And it was like they were worshipping themselves.
They were dumb jocks, worshipping
dumb jock gods. Well, good for them.
But what about the people who got shoved
into lockers? Well,
Frederick's example, and this is gonna
create some misunderstandings later,
but his example is
the Jews who were colonized
by the Romans in Judea.
And it's certainly not that the Jews didn't try
to revolt. Oh, they did.
Multiple times.
But for several centuries, the Romans were
just too powerful. No one could stop
them. So the question is, what
happens psychologically to people
who are oppressed and who lack the
power to overthrow the oppressor?
Well, in that case,
frustrated vindictiveness builds over
time to become this deep
bitterness which Nietzsche gave the French
name, Résentiment.
Resentment in English.
I don't speak French. I just enjoy
making vaguely French noises.
I don't like the English, but I like the French even less.
Because they're always dressed so well, and they speak a sexier language
than me. Stop it! This is your final
warning, comprendez-vous? Good wine, though.
I'll give them that. So there's a German word,
Neid, which means envy.
So why is Frederick using this
French term, Résentiment?
What's going on, Frederick? Why are you speaking
French? Are you nervous?
You trying to impress me? Nietzsche must
have said Résentiment because he thought
it was something different than envy.
I think the difference is resentment,
and I'm just gonna use the English word so I don't sound like an
asshole. Resentment is born
not just of wanting what someone
has, but of a permanent frustration
of the desire for resentment.
Revenge. It's born of weakness,
inability to get revenge.
Now revenge itself
implies weakness, at least a
temporary weakness. We say revenge
is best served cold,
but actually, revenge is only
served cold.
If it's served hot, if someone slaps
you and you slap them back immediately,
that's retaliation, not revenge.
You brought
this on yourself. Revenge is only
a possibility when you can't
retaliate immediately. So you become
vindictive. You start plotting and
scheming. But if you're too weak,
too impotent to have any
hope of revenge, then you become
resentful. So Nietzsche's argument is
that a person who's too weak to get material
revenge can instead
get psychological revenge
by creating a new morality.
In Frederick's words,
the beginning of the slave's revolt
in morality occurs when
Résentiment itself turns creative
and gives birth to values.
This is a little high concept for a mukbang,
isn't it? What are you doing, Frederick?
So while master morality says that good
is power, riches, health, and
strength, and bad is the
opposite, slave morality,
the morality of resentment, says
blessed are the poor, the
meek, the sick, the powerless.
This is the good
of slave morality, and its opposite
is not the bad, but a new concept,
the evil. And what
is evil? Well, everything
that master morality says is good.
Power. Wealth.
Conquest. Sexual
satisfaction.
He's talking about
Christianity here, he's not talking about
Judaism. But Frederick thinks of
Christianity as the spiritual revenge
of the Jews against the Romans,
an inversion of the empire's
values. But he also thinks
that slave morality is fundamentally
dishonest. It's like the fox
and the grapes. Not being
able to take revenge is called
not wanting to take revenge.
It might even be called
forgiveness. Slave morality
says that weakness is
righteous. Submission to people you
hate is called obedience.
Having to wait is
called patience.
Inability to satisfy sexual desire
is called chastity,
purity, and so on. And while
master morality is born of saying
yes to yourself, as a powerful,
noble beast
of prey, slave morality
is born of saying no
to the master and everything he has
that you can't. I like to have
my belly rubbed. Scratch my
back above my tail, please.
I'm gonna put the rest of the fish away because it's getting warm
and I'm full. This has not been a successful
mukbang. It turns out that it's actually very difficult
to do a mukbang while
talking. I should have thought this through a little harder.
So slave morality is born of a repressed
desire for revenge, but that desire
for revenge never completely disappears.
It's there, for example, in the Christian
idea of the Last Judgment.
No need to take revenge
against the wicked, my sheep. God
will do that for us. And in the meantime,
being weak
is good, actually.
I find this book thrilling
to read, honestly. And I'm not
easily thrilled. Especially not
by philosophers. I think this book in particular
gets me because, especially
if you were raised Christian, this is
so the opposite of everything
you were ever taught to believe that it almost feels
like, dirty.
Should I be reading this? Is this allowed?
Because even if you're not religious,
most of us still agree with a lot of
Christian morality. Like, yeah, Jesus
was a good guy. Blessed
are the meek. Sure. But then
Frederick comes along and he's like,
hmm, morality is just a cope
for frustrated vindictiveness.
And you're like, I need to lie down.
Where's my smelling salts?
But wait, there's more.
This gets even darker. Nietzsche
thinks that over the last two millennia of European
history, slave morality has
triumphed. Saint Paul made
Christianity marketable, the
Emperor Constantine converted,
and by the Middle Ages, even
kings and aristocrats were kneeling down
not to powerful warrior gods
made in their own image, but to
a god that was weak.
Suffering. Victimized.
Oppressed.
Mmm. So by the 19th
century, slave morality had become
the only morality.
And it's not just Christianity, either.
The secular version of these values
became socialism, anarchism.
About freethinkers and
atheists, Nietzsche has this
to say.
Okay, the poison.
What is the poison?
Well, Frederick thinks that resentment
poisons the mind,
and turns humans against our own
natural instincts. Not just against
aggression, but against sexuality,
against ambition,
against power, against life
itself. And there's two possible
outcomes of this. One is
that resentment becomes a political
movement. The conspiracy of those
who suffer. The tyranny of
the herd. The revolution
that eats itself. Only we
are good and just, is what they say.
As though health, success, strength,
pride, and the feeling of power
were in themselves depravities
for which penance, bitter penance
will one day be exacted. Among them
we find plenty of vengeance seekers
disguised as judges
with the word justice continually in their mouth
like poisonous spittle.
So you get the mentality of a hyper-moralistic
resentment mob. Which I'm sure
we're all familiar with. The other outcome
is that this moralism turns
inward and attacks the individual
conscience, producing
asceticism, self-denial,
guilt. Because slave morality
condemns not only the external
beasts of prey who are oppressing us
but also the beast
of prey within. Our own
animal instincts. What Christianity
calls sin.
So Frederick thinks that modern humans
have become sick.
We hate ourselves. We hate our
own nature. We hate
life itself. I mean
is he wrong? You see a girl
boss winning. I only
see the will to power.
Frederick thinks of modern men as
once proud wildcats who
become domesticated house pets
at the cost of everything
great in the human spirit.
That's very valid
Frederick.
That's super hecking
valid. So look I've been
pretty positive about Nietzsche so far
but I do have a couple critiques I want to say.
One is that Frederick
associating slave morality with
the Jews is very irresponsible.
Even though he didn't intend to be
anti-semitic and even though he was outspoken
against anti-semitism in his own time
when you keep referring to the Christian
values you're critiquing as
Jewish hatred and Jewish revenge
some people might get
the wrong idea. And some people did
Frederick. Like your dumbass sister
Elizabeth Nietzsche who became a literal
alternative
ethno-identitarian. God damn it
Liz. Kind of goth goals though.
Yes that kind of goth. You're
right this time. My other critique is that
it doesn't seem to have occurred to Frederick
that genuinely caring about other people
is an option. Like not because
caring about other people is repressing your
true selfish nature, but just because
caring about other people is
part of your nature. And isn't it?
Isn't caring about other people
also in our nature? I do think
most of what Nietzsche says about resentment
accurately describes a
very real thing. But it's not
the only thing. There is genuine
care and love in this world
I've been told. I've heard rumors.
And I'm even gonna go so far as to say
hashtag not all Christians. Christ
I'm defending the Christians. What does this channel
come to? There are Christians
maybe not most, but still some
for whom love and forgiveness
are genuine experiences
and not just some kind of
twisted impotent
passive aggressive vengeance.
Where I agree with Nietzsche and with Freud
is I do think a lot of the
emotional foundation of justice
and morality is
retribution, envy
or some combination of the two.
But maybe it doesn't have to be that way.
There's a famous Martin Luther King
quote responding to Nietzsche
What is needed is a realization
that power
without love is reckless
and abusive and that love without power
is sentimental and anemic.
Power at its best
is love
implementing the demands of justice
and justice at its
best is love correcting
everything that stands
against love.
So Reverend King concedes to Nietzsche
that to simply call power
evil is a sickness
anemic. But there still needs
to be some kind of emotional or spiritual
force that keeps humanity
from tearing itself apart. And maybe
something like this Christian idea
of love for humanity is the missing
piece. Because without something like that
I just see retribution
and envy snowballing
into human self destruction.
And I hate that for us. It's not very
sliving of us. Do you guys know about sliving?
Do you even subscribe to Paris Hilton's
YouTube channel? She doesn't have as many subscribers
as I do but you know. I try to support
smaller creators.
Sliving is basically slaying and living
your best life into one word. It's the new
that's hot. Maybe I'll do a video about
love when I'm in a better mood.
So for now, well
let's put it this way. God is
dead and we have killed
him, yeah?
It's living.
So let us give him
all we see.
Okay. I'm moisturized. I'm primed.
I've proven my academic credentials.
Now it's time to do my makeup.
That's right children, I'm going full
Bailey Sarian. I'm going full
suspish. So I guess I should
say something about the political implications
of all this since, uh, I guess
this channel's about politics. Sometimes
I have to read my own Wikipedia article
to remember what I'm doing with my life.
But this morality of resentment,
of impotence, and permanently
frustrated revenge, judges
that power
is evil. I don't use foundation, I just
use concealer. I know that's like not
how you're supposed to do makeup, but I don't need to be good
at makeup, okay? I have a million subscribers on
YouTube. I don't need to be good.
There was a New York Times article about young
women's attitudes toward political ambition
and one of the women who was interviewed said
as a white woman, I know
I have unearned privilege. So
am I really the best person to be in leadership?
Uh, yes.
Yes you are. Because we need leaders
like you who are capable of
questioning the legitimacy of their own
authority. Otherwise, we're
just going to be stuck with another blonde beast of
prey. And of course it's good to be
aware of your privilege, especially
as a leader, but let's not be so
self-effacing that we efface
ourselves off the face of the earth.
This is the self-sabotage of
resentment values. If you think
power is evil, then you've given
up on the ambition to acquire any
power, which virtually guarantees
your political irrelevance, since
like MLK said, you have to at least
have some power to implement
the demands of justice. Remember
what incels call taking the black
pill, this conviction that the reason
you don't have a girlfriend is just that you're
genetically undesirable. There's
nothing you can do to change it, and
I guess women are just too shallow
to be attracted to all the amazing hatred
and spite that festers in your heart.
For a lot of black-pilled incels,
it seems like there's only one thing left in
life that they enjoy, which is
simply the pleasure of complaining.
Of moaning in pain.
It reminds me of a comment from
Dostoevsky's second most
horrible protagonist.
Even in toothache there is enjoyment.
In that case, of course, people are not spiteful in silence
but moan. But they are not candid
moans, they are malignant moans.
And the malignancy is the whole point.
The moan is a protest
against the meaninglessness of pain.
And part of the satisfaction of
moaning is inflicting your
pain on other people.
This kind of malignant moaning,
it's kind of the opposite of music.
Because a lot of music, like blues,
is benevolent moaning
that transforms pain into pleasure.
I mean, that's what blues is all about.
My woman don't love me no more, but I know her
sister will. You know, optimism.
I think a lot of incel discourse
is really just malignant moaning.
Right, it's not an attempt to diagnose
or solve any problem.
It's just a contagious expression of misery.
A moan of pain that
masquerades as a political agenda.
Sexual Marxism, they call it.
The redistribution of sex.
State-mandated GFs.
That's very valid.
Of course, they don't actually expect any of this
to happen. That's not
the point. So incels are kind of
a universal punching bag online.
It's very easy to point and laugh
at them. But what's harder is to look
in the mirror and notice how these
exact same tendencies
are rampant in our own communities.
So the incel black pill is just one
instance of what I call an ideology
of resentment. A discourse
that outwardly appears like moral
or political critique, but which on examination
is mainly just a resentful
moan. The goal of resentment
politics is not to improve
conditions. In fact, the
resentful person is full of contempt
for any morally compromised
sellouts who are
attempting to enact plausible reforms.
They don't want victory.
They don't want power. They want to endlessly
critique power.
Because for them, critique is
an important psychological defense
against feeling
impotent. Shaler described
it this way.
What am I going to do with my eyes?
I think a pink kind of
look. We've been doing a lot of pink looks.
I love that hay fever look.
As a general rule, the more radical
a political community claims to be,
the more likely it is
to be a community of resentment.
Self-styled radicals will tell you,
superficial surface reforms do not
interest us. The problem must
be critiqued at its root.
And then the root turns out to be this universal
all-encompassing evil, right?
Society itself.
The system. The machine.
A resentment ideologue always
imagines himself to be engaged in a
kind of satanic revolt
against an omnipotent,
omnipresent enemy. Okay,
I need to do makeup for a second.
It's harder than it looks to be a makeup vlogger.
It's hard to talk while doing this. And nothing short of
total revolution counts as any sort of
victory whatsoever. We have to dismantle
the entire system.
Burn it all down.
I guess it's pedestrian to point out that this is
the revolutionary utopian equivalent
of Christians awaiting the last judgment.
Our kingdom is coming, comrades!
Often the appeal of utopian
ideology is similar to religion.
It's not about healthcare,
higher wages,
relief from police violence.
Those are actual goals that could be
demanded, worked for, and achieved.
Utopian ideology instead
promises relief from some
general malaise.
Alienation.
And so ironically, it can have the same
opiate effect that Marx ascribes
to religion. But release from
the general anguish of human existence
is not a political goal.
There's been many revolutions in the last
few centuries, and so far
zero utopias.
Resentment, envy,
and hunger, for that matter,
are not satiated by the downfall
of the old regime. When the people
have no bread, they eat the rich.
And when the rich
are gone, they eat
each other. And because of the proximity
effect, envy may actually
increase after the revolution.
You may actually be more envious of a
favored comrade, a
successful citoyen, oui,
a kulak, than you ever were of the
aristocrats. So envy turns
paranoid and imaginative
in revolutionary moments.
It gets sublimated into morality,
and the accusations
start flying. That citizen
is conspiring against the revolution.
That peasant is hoarding grain.
So the guillotine starts slicing
thousands of heads off, the gulags
fill up, or an authoritarian
strongman takes over just to
announce another revolution
two decades later. The things people will do
to stay relevant, honestly.
And for what? What long-term
egalitarian utopia results?
Socialism with Chinese characteristics?
So look, I do understand
that sometimes you just have to
do a revolution. And if I'd been there in
1789, I'm sure
I'd be storming the Bastille myself.
But I just wish we could stop being so doe-eyed about it.
Revolution is a bloody nightmare that
happens because society is collapsing
and people are desperate. At worst,
revolution is nothing more than a
violent day of retribution. And at
best, it lays the groundwork for future
incremental progress. But it will never
usher in utopia, nor is it the
antidote to a vague sense of unease, which
I'm sorry to report, is
simply the resting state of an unsedated
human mind. Now I'm not
saying, as some conservatives do,
that all leftist or all
egalitarian politics is born of
envy. No. This is a
specific subtype. There are
plenty of reasons, other than
envy or fear of envy, to oppose
an economic distribution where
some people have billions of dollars
while other people are dying because they can't afford
insulin. Objectively, that is
not an efficient use of resources to
promote human well-being. And personally,
I just don't want to live in a country
where people are dying because they
can't afford medicine. And I'm willing to pay
however many taxes it takes
for that not to happen. So while I'm
putting down straw-man versions of my
argument, I'm also not
saying, oh, let's just stop being
envious. No. That's
impossible. I think envy is like libido.
It's a basic force of human
nature that's more or less
unstoppable. But with the right leadership,
I think that envy can
potentially be sublimated
or redirected into something
more constructive. Because raw
envy is a very bad
basis for egalitarian politics.
It often targets the wrong people,
like millionaires instead of billionaires.
And eventually, it turns the revolution against
itself. And you get the circular firing
squad. The self-cannibalism.
The problem I see on the left today
is that without any genuine political
outlet, resentment mostly manifests
as morality. Morality
itself being a way to
vent envious aggression and vindictiveness.
On the left, we claim to be so
impersonal, right? We're all about structural
analysis. The material
conditions. Systems of
power. Intersectional identity
hierarchies. But if you look at what people
actually spend their time doing here,
it's all this obsessive moral
policing. I wonder if because
leftists can't seem to win on any
major political stage, we feel
disempowered. And so this moral
fanaticism is a
psychological substitute. Like with Marie
Antoinette, it's easier to blame
people than systems. Also,
structural analysis is
very boring, and destroying people
with gossip is extremely entertaining.
This obsessive
moral policing also gets
turned inward and becomes leftist
guilt. You know, this useless
internalized scolding.
I think I'm done with my makeup. What do we
think? Leave a comment. I'm always hesitant
to do anything about skincare, since last time
I did skincare, I was critiqued by Hyram.
So I am gonna spray my face a couple
times with this Tatcha skin
mist, if that's okay with Hyram.
It feels good to finally address this
feud. Clear the air.
I look a lot better with makeup.
I don't want to say that I don't have natural beauty,
it's just that it's very much enhanced by
painting a different face on top of
my face. But hey, at least this way
I've kind of earned it, you know?
Because it's my skill. So there's a podcast
called Guilty Feminist that's been
running for years. And I haven't listened in a
while, but in the early episodes, they'd bring
on these women who would confess their
feminist sins. You know,
hi, my name is Amber,
I'm a feminist, but
I enjoy being choked
in bed. It's
hard being a woman. Not only are you being
choked, you also feel guilty
about it. The same moral hand-wringing
happens with body positivity.
When you make loving your body into
a moral imperative, not
only are you still going to hate your body,
but now you're also going to feel guilty
about hating your body because it makes you a
bad feminist. So there was one problem,
and now there's two problems.
Thanks, morality. That's very
helpful. Now I want to take a moment to
acknowledge that a lot of conservatives
have made some version of the
argument I'm making in this video.
For example, Jordan Peterson
and Camille Paglia have argued
that academic postmodernists
are motivated by resentment. The argument
is that deconstructionist
literary theory is a kind of envious
vengeance against the beauty
and virtuosity of canonical
great art. And yeah, there's probably
some truth to that. A lot of academics
are field artists, but I was even more
manqué than that. I've noticed that
working-class, non-academic socialists
do tend to be more
productive and more self-advancing,
involved in unionizing or organizing.
Whereas, it's usually people who
went to college. I went to
college!
Presumably because they had middle
class ambitions at some point,
but whose middle-class ambitions have
failed. Who become the great
critiquers of capital. I mean, I can tell you
from experience that when I was eating
Chef Boyardee over my master's degree,
that's when I was most likely to say things like
According to Antonio Gramsci,
in the logic of late-stage capitalism,
the culturally hegemonic neoliberal
ideology manufactures the consent
of the civilian.
Uh, so point taken. But some conservatives
take this argument way too
far and try to argue that the entire
left is nothing but a coalition
of resentment. Like there's a video on YouTube
of the philosophy professor Steven
Hicks doing a version of the
post-modernism is resentment argument,
and in the comments section there's a bunch of people
saying, this describes Black
Lives Matter, Antifa, and
the Democrats. Does
it though? I mean, any political movement
is gonna have people in it who suffer
from resentment poisoning. But Black Lives
Matter, at its core,
is about the right not to be murdered
by police. The slogan,
Black Lives Matter, is an affirmation
of the value of Black life.
So, that seems like something even
Nietzsche would approve of. Huey Newton,
the co-founder of the Black Panther Party,
was inspired by Nietzsche to
create the slogan, All Power to the People.
When we coined the expression
All Power to the People, we had in mind
emphasizing the word power, for
we recognize that the will to power is
the basic drive of man. But it is
incorrect to seek power over people.
We have been subjugated to the dehumanizing
power of exploitation and
racism for hundreds of years, and
the Black community has its will to power
also. What we seek, however,
is not power over people, but the
power of control of our own destiny.
That, to me, is a
role model for how to do identity politics
without centering resentment.
It's instead an affirmation of
self-determination and self-respect.
Like Nietzsche would say, it's saying
yes to yourself. Whereas, if your
whole political project is defined in the
negative, then you're allowing yourself
to be defined by your enemies. I find
feminism is prone to this, where even
and in fact especially the most radical
feminists cannot seem to escape
this resentful consciousness of being
the second sex and defining themselves
against men.
Earlier I mentioned Andrea Dworkin in a
positive way. She's the most radical of
radical feminists, and my first
impulse is actually to defend her
because she's very widely hated
and most of the people who hate her
hate a caricature. Like in that Steven
Hicks video, Hicks summarizes
Dworkin as,
literally in the preface to her most
famous book, Dworkin says,
If one's sexual experience
has always and without exception
been based on dominance,
how could one understand that this
book does not say that all
men are rapists or that all intercourse
is rape? Listen Hicks,
I get that you're a full professor and I'm
just a makeup vlogger, but my gut
feeling on this one is, before
criticizing a book, maybe
read the book. Just a thought.
Get it together prof. You're being owned
online by a makeup vlogger. I mean
there's no shame in that, it happens to me all the time.
That being said, I do think that Hicks
is coincidentally correct
that Dworkin is a theorist
of resentment. What Dworkin does
say in this book is arguably
even more bleak than what is falsely
attributed to her. The book is called
Intercourse. She wrote a book called Intercourse.
Imagine writing a book called Intercourse.
I can actually easily imagine that, never mind.
So this is an argument about the
meaning of sex. Penetration
to be specific. Dworkin
argues that penetration expresses
domination, invasion,
occupation, possession, contempt,
degradation. So it's
against the Freudian male
castration anxiety interpretation
where it's, you know, fear of
being devoured by the woman.
Imagine being afraid of that. Imagine
being afraid of that. I'm gonna get a
facelift someday, and I'm
gonna look like this.
I'm perfect.
I certainly don't agree,
with everything she says, but isn't
Dworkin closer to the truth here? Closer than
Freud, anyway. You know, think about what men
typically say to women during
the act. Do they say,
Help, I'm being devoured.
Never heard that one. Have you?
No, usually it's more along the lines of
You like that, don't you?
You little... Etc. And of course
you can eroticize being subjugated
and degraded, and enjoy it.
And I think Dworkin would argue that most women
do eroticize subjugation because
they're taught to. But enjoying it
she'd have to say, doesn't
change the meaning of what's happening.
So I think Dworkin says some things that are
very true, and some things that are off the fucking rails.
Where she loses me is where she
starts getting blackpilled, and this book,
this is the feminist blackpill.
It is 250 pages of
hopeless misery and rage. She
says, Male-dominant gender
hierarchy seems immune to
reform. This may be because
intercourse itself is immune
to reform. Uh, okay, so
women will never be free, and
until men stop putting the P in the V.
We can dream, Andrea.
We can dream! Like
most ideology of resentment, this book
is totally dismissive of any
plausible reforms that might
actually improve the situation of women.
Instead, preferring to wallow in the
endless violence, filth, and
objection of it all. I also think it's
symptomatic that Dworkin identifies as a
lesbian, but in that second wave
political way. Quoting from
the foreword, to Dworkin, it was a
badge of rebellion against the patriarch
hierarchy. In 30 plus years of knowing
her, I've never heard of a single romance
with a woman not one. This is not
surprising to me from the author of a
250 page book about sex
that not once pauses to even
imagine the possibility of
intimacy between women. Because it's not a
lesbianism that's about saying yes to
women. It's a lesbianism that's about
saying no to men. You know, people
think that lesbians are the biggest man haters,
but I don't think that's true. I think
lesbians just don't think
about men that much. The only men I
think about are Fred Nietzsche and
Oedipus the King.
It's straight women who are usually the real
man haters, because they're stuck with this.
And love is closer to hatred
than neutrality. So what does Andrea Dworkin
actually want? What would she say
yes to, if she said yes to anything?
Sometimes women have trouble saying what they want,
because no one ever told them they could.
Romance. That's what Joan
Didion said is the real desire of the women's
movement. Joan Didion, of course, being
not like other girls. Dworkin offers occasional
glimpses of a positive desire.
Despite all efforts to socialize
women to one intercourse, women still
want a more diffuse and tender sensuality
that involves the whole body in a
polymorphous tenderness. That does sound
nice. I'm so lonely.
I think it's a bit bold to speak
for all women, though. Like, there are
definitely women out there who, uh,
they don't make love. Anastasia,
they f***
hard. I'm really sleepy, and
this bed right behind me just looks
so nice. Get in here right now.
What if I just go to sleep?
And then wake up, and then just record
the rest of the video when I wake up. I don't want to do it
now. I'll get Pikachu. That'll make this easier.
Isn't it better for me to have a friend?
Pikachu is the most adorable Pokemon.
Why? Because he's the yellowest.
Name one thing more yellow than Pikachu.
You can't name anything. You can't think of anything.
So if diffuse and tender sensuality
is what you want, then just
say that. Is that what you want, Pikachu?
I bet it is.
And Dworkin did get married.
To a gay man. So I
guess she found what she wanted.
Lucky.
Envying
Andrea Dworkin. Is that really what we've
sunk to around here? You know, I've been noticing
the poison creeping
into my mind lately. I know this isn't
very original, but I had
a bad year. You know, I fell in love with my
best friend like a gay idiot,
got my heart comprehensively
broken, and then COVID hit
and gave me a year of solitude
to spiral deeper
into a hell of my own making.
You know, I stopped saying yes to life.
And I started saying yes to chasing
the dragon. By which I mean
playing Spyro the Dragon. One of the
greatest appropriate for all ages
video games of all time.
Look at him gooooooo
I'm taking the hair clips out. I catch
myself having bitter spinster thoughts.
It's because I'm trans.
It's because I'm gay. That's
why I'll die alone. Yeah, that's the reason
I'm alone. Definitely not because I don't
leave the house. See, I am not immune
to incel-tier
brain poisoning. And you really can't
use political theorizing as
an excuse not to fix your
life. Society did
this to me. A transphobic
society made me hate myself.
Well,
yeah, that's true.
But at a certain point, you have
to take responsibility for your own
mind, and decide to stop being
an accomplice in your own annihilation.
Since we keep referencing Paradise Lost,
the mind is its own place, and in
itself can make a heaven of hell a hell of
heaven. Yeah, squad. So I asked
myself, what kind of mind
do I want to be? Do I want to obsess
over what I lack? Concede
society's judgment of my inferiority?
Become a self-hating, self-pitying,
envious, resentful little
nothing? Or, do I want
to get off the goddamn
floor, stop chasing the dragon,
and say yes to life?
The answer, of course, is that
I long to return to the sweet womb
of my dark mother. But we're not gonna do
that, because there's plenty of time to numb
the pain after you die. The sweet
embrace of death is the darkest mother of all.
Also, nothing is
less attractive than an
envious, resentful,
self-pitying person. It's beyond
a personality flaw. It's
a personality deformity
that can ruin whatever chance at happiness
you have. So, in the short
time that you're alive, you have to
discover that which is noble
in yourself, and say yes to it.
You know, don't say no to getting older.
Say yes to being a MILF.
Yes. Yes.
What I'm really trying to say here is
Spongebob Squarepants is the
ubermensch. Spongebob says
yes to life, and so should we.
Yes to ourselves. Yes to
art. Yes to sensuality.
Yes to the world. Yes.
Yes.
We.
Is this really how we're ending the video?
I guess.
Okay, bye!
Oh, so what
if my fantasies make no sense? You wanna
talk about things that don't make sense?
Heterosexuality. Let's put that under the microscope,
hmm? You want me to believe
that a straight woman who knows
the difference between magenta and mauve
is gonna date a straight man
who thinks it's gay to wash his underwear,
and that's just gonna work out fine.
You think it's safe to raise a child in that
environment? I don't think so.
Not on my watch.
See, I think straight men should date each other.
They can sit on the couch all day playing Xbox
and then each other. And then straight women
can pair off, decoupage
some shit, and eat each other out.
Isn't that better? Isn't that more
rational? I wish I could wiggle these cat ears.
Like, I wish I had anatomical
control over them. Hello?
Yes, Dr. Spiegel?
Yes, it's me again.
I have a suggestion. What do we even have here?
We've got tuna, salmon,
some squid,
mackerel, shrimp,
some, I think it's yellowtail,
clam,
some rolls. I've never been as much into rolls.
I'm a cat, you know, I like fish.
You start adding too much avocado and rice into things.
It's an affront to my
feline nature.
Yes, I'm sure.
To make sure it's not too much,
get the phone ready,
you find a place where
you can actually
eat them.
Give you some
Thank you for watching!
Doctor, I think if a breeze comes into the window, I could die.