Hi boys, it's me again.
Just your average girl.
Look, I may be a biological female, but I do hope that just for this video we're able
to converse as men.
I want you to think back to 2016, which I know in internet years is like halfway between
now and the decline of Rome.
Do you like history boys?
How did Rome fall again?
Was it the gays?
Tell me all about it.
Back in 2016, the big internet culture war was between feminists on one side, and men's
rights activists on the other.
Whatever happened to that?
These days it's as dead a meme as, I don't know, Harambe.
I did want to do the fedora though.
Every YouTuber who's ever covered the men's rights movement has done the fedora, and I
wanted to put my own little twist on it.
My wardrobe notes for this video say, MRA femme fatale and fedora but make it fashion.
School shooter realness.
I feel like I'm also serving a little…
Oh.
Red-pilled Carmen Sandiego.
In this video, I want to ask, in all seriousness, what are we going to do about men?
Because no offense, but as a group, you guys kind of seem like you're not doing okay.
Could a group of people who are purchasing uncooked alpha yogurt possibly be subsisting
in a state of psychological balance?
Fellas, are regular bowel movements gay?
I guess yeah, kind of.
You don't see a whole lot of psyllium hustling.
I'm not sure.
I don't think I'm going to be a big fan of the trans-heterosexual medicine cabinets.
I'm losing my target audience here.
Listen, my dudes, let's just say, I'm kind of worried about you guys.
And I'm not saying I'm any better.
To be clear, I'm not okay either.
There's like 15 jars of urine in my refrigerator right now.
Yeah, that's right, women pee too, okay?
Get over it.
I'm so sorry if this offends your male notions of feminine delicacy, but I, for one, will
not be shamed by your patriarchal bullshit.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
You boys, you're very rational, aren't you?
Ugh, I suppose I was too.
I admit that these days, rationality, it's something I struggle with,
both as a biological female and as a Pisces moon.
But when I decided I wanted to make a video for men,
Contra Pines, for men,
I started brushing up on my reasoning skills because I want to be so fucking rational for you.
So to prepare for this video, I read Newton's Principia Mathematica,
Wittgenstein's Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus,
and of course, the philosophical classic The Rational Male by Royal Caliente.
So my mind is well lubricated and I am ready for what I have no doubt will be a penetrating,
intellectual… interchange.
Look, I want to play by your rules, okay?
So there will be no emotions in this video.
I will present my arguments in strict, logical form,
relying only on facts, reason, evidence, and deductive proof.
So let's get to it.
Actually, you know what, fuck that, let's listen to house music and do sex shrugs.
I'm pandering to the male gaze.
Oh, and the male's traits.
God, I love attention.
Hey, gorge.
Okay, I'm ready.
Let's crack open a cold one, boys.
My hands are too pretty to open the can.
I need a man to do it for me.
Help!
Fuck it.
Okay, that's super fucking pretty.
Hey, gorge.
Are there any women?
Women still watching this video?
I'm really sorry about all this, unless you're into that sort of thing.
In which case, how very dare.
I'm a good Presbyterian.
And by Presbyterian, I do mean pansexual.
Hey, how are y'all?
Look, the video's about men, so I'm trying to be attractive to men.
Am I doing this right?
Is this what men like?
Traps.
Straps.
It is a risky look for a girl like me.
When you do a lingerie look, you know you're going to wind up somewhere
on the frankenfurter violet tchotchke didevantese spectrum?
Oh, but you don't know where exactly.
And that is a dangerous game, ladies.
I have to say, though, I actually am feeling pretty fucking empowered right now.
But, um, that could be because of the drugs.
Look, gentlemen, let's be rational.
And we're fooling around, okay?
Part one.
Oh, wait.
Rational.
Axiom one.
America's next top victim.
I think there is some truth to the idea that we live in a victimhood culture.
And I'm not just talking...
about campus SJWs with their microaggressions.
No, bitch.
This goes all the way to the top.
We have white people complaining about reverse racism.
We have the literal 1% complaining about ANTI-RAGE PREJUDICE.
That must be super fucking hard for you.
We have the heterosexual agenda organizing straight pride parades.
You know, flaunting their sexuality in the faces of children who are trying to raise a family,
and protesting in the street like a bunch of .
And so, of course, because there was women's rights, there has to be men's rights too.
I've been hearing about men's rights for my whole adult life,
and I've always been very skeptical.
Because in my experience, online men's rights activism in practice always looks like this.
Women try to do a good thing to solve a real problem,
and then a man shows up to say,
Well, what about men?
Men also get harassed.
Why aren't you talking about men?
And is this man actually involved in activism to stop harassment against men?
Of course he's fucking not.
He doesn't give a shit.
He's a troll.
His contribution to the conversation begins and ends with what about men?
What about them, honey?
For this video, I decided to actually do some research for once.
And the first thing I did was read the foundational text of the modern men's rights movement,
which is the Myth of Male Power by Warren Farrell.
Actually, I listened to the audiobook because, let's be honest, reading is hard.
But as I was listening, I admit I thought it made more sense than I was expecting it to.
Basically, Farrell says that second-wave feminists rightly fought against the traditional gender role
that confined women to domestic servitude.
But he argues that the feminist idea that men have all the power in society is actually an illusion,
because the traditional gender role for men is just as oppressive.
He introduces the idea of male disposability,
basically the idea that society values female lives more than male lives,
which are seen as expendable in the service of protecting and providing for women and children.
And he points to statistics,
showing that men make up the majority of military casualties,
workplace fatalities, murder victims, suicides, and so on.
So we're supposed to conclude that even though at first it looks like men have more power than women,
in fact, the queens have a certain kind of privilege
in being protected and provided for by the expendable male worker bees.
And I guess that kind of makes sense.
I feel like I can at least empathize with the point of view.
What I'm saying is, I took the red pill,
and I rubbed it on my clitoris,
and I rubbed it on my chest,
and I rubbed it on my chest, and I rubbed it on my chest,
but some initial objections come to mind.
Like, haven't men been almost all of the kings, presidents, and CEOs for millennia?
Didn't men make up all these rules in the first place?
I don't know, boys.
Still seems kind of patriarchal to me.
But maybe you'll say that it's only at the top of society that men have more power than women.
Maybe the average man is also oppressed by the system that feminists call patriarchy.
If that's what you're saying,
I think I basically agree with that.
See, what you have to understand about me is I am such a fucking Libra.
Whenever there's a conflict, my gut reaction is to be like,
well, maybe everybody's right, and maybe there's good points on both sides,
and we should all just listen to each other and rub each other's cluuuuts.
But no, my Scorpio rising persona will not allow that.
Oh, there will be a champion.
There will be blood.
So, judges.
How do we decide which gender is American?
And who's America's next top victim?
I mean, it's not like you can just change genders and see how the other half lives.
Or can you?
Proposition two.
Diary of an X-man.
Dear diary, with every false smile I conceal that on the inside I'm drowning in darkness.
Mom, get out of my room.
You're ruining my life.
Look, I have never, ever talked about this on my channel before.
It's like a super fucking vulnerable moment for me.
But I was born a boy.
Well, was I ever really a boy?
It's hard to say.
Dear diary,
Growing up, I always knew that I was different from other kids, especially other boys.
And it took me so long to pinpoint what it was.
But there was this moment.
I must have been, what, seven, eight years old?
And I was playing in my parents' room all by myself.
And I saw this pair of my mom's shoes lying on the floor.
And I don't know what it was.
It was like this magnetism that drew me to them.
And I put my little feet in them and walked in front of the mirror.
And I didn't really have the words yet to describe how I felt.
But basically, in that moment, I sensed that God had made a mistake.
And I was destined to be, to be a Crosstresser.
That is super fucking coconuts.
Anyway, then in my 20s, my life completely changed.
My life completely fell apart and I became a woman.
Hey, how are you?
I became one of the dolls.
My plastic surgeon is an artist.
Look, boys, the point I'm trying to make here is I used to live your lifestyle.
I know what people like you get up to.
And I think it's disgusting.
I gotta say, though, since I transitioned, my life has been super fucking great.
Like, way better.
Now, of course, a lot of that is not because women have it better than men, but because...
Hey, gorge, I am literally transgendered.
So before I transitioned, I was like, oh my god.
I was dying inside, you know?
I was in the wrong body.
And now, it's like I finally have the body I was meant to die inside of.
But it's not just that.
I do think that, in some ways, since I started presenting as a woman,
people actually do treat me better.
I mean, they take my opinions less seriously, sure.
But that's probably for the best.
Now, before using my personal experience as any kind of evidence,
I guess I should say a couple caveats.
Caveat one is that most pre-transition trans women are gay.
They're not like other boys.
And most of us, we're not living the business-class male experience by any means.
You know, it's a lot of drunk melancholics,
tormented sissies, secretive transvestites,
poets, you know, that sort of thing.
Caveat two is that my trans experience is not THE trans experience.
And I do have a lot of other privileges that made things go super fucking well for me.
Hey, how are yo?
Don't you just love it when someone checks their privilege in a way that's actually...
It's actually just bragging.
You know, it's super important for me to acknowledge that I've been so successful
and I've come so far in part because I'm white and I'm skinny and I'm young
and I'm blonde and I'm rich and I pass and I'm educated and I'm popular
and my plastic surgeon is an artist and my boyfriend is really rich and hot
and I come from a pure Aryan bloodline.
And part of what makes me so enlightened and so compassionate
is that I'm able to recognize these privileges that I have
that just might not be available to people who are less fortunate.
From the bottom of my mother-fucking-at-my-father-fucking-heart
that must be super fucking hard for you, I can't even imagine.
What I was saying is there are ways that people treat me better now
that I'm presenting as a woman.
You know, people smile at me more.
I feel more taken care of.
Men do things for me.
Now, a lot of women don't like men doing things for them,
you know, holding doors, helping with luggage,
because they feel that it's infantilizing or condescending.
But not me.
I love it.
Both because I love attention and because I'm a recumbent queen
who's too much of a delicate flower to lift a finger.
I do this thing on airplanes where when it's time for me
to put my carry-on luggage in the overhead bin,
I pretend that my bag is too heavy for me to lift
and then some man will usually get up and do it for me
even though I'm taller than most men.
It makes me happy.
Another good thing about becoming a woman is
I integrated into female social groups
and I found that they provide a kind of
communal support and overt affection
that male social groups generally just don't.
I find that female social style suits me better than the male one
which tends to be more atomized, more individualist
where affection is always concealed behind this semi-jokey front of competition.
Like, think about the way boys talk to each other when they play video games.
A third improvement for me has to do with the way
men and women are treated in public space.
When you present female in public
you're more likely to be treated as a spectacle to be caught up in, so to speak, when you're screened as a zombie.
When you present a female in public, you're more likely to be treated as a spectacle, to be caught up in, and more often than not, an idol in front of a mirror.
spectacle to be commented upon. People, usually men, will just blurt out their opinions about
you. Sometimes complimentary, sometimes insulting, sometimes just fucking weird. Whereas, when
you present male in public, you're more likely to be treated either as invisible or as dangerous.
Now, feminists have traditionally interpreted these differences as men asserting dominance
over women in public space, and they've criticized catcalling as being objectifying, degrading,
and misogynistic. And it certainly can be all of those things. There's different kinds of
catcalling, and I have different feelings about them. If I'm walking with another woman, and a
man says, ladies, you look beautiful tonight. I don't know. I like that. I think that's nice.
It makes me feel seen. It makes me feel admired. It boosts my confidence. Whereas, if I'm walking
alone, and a drunk starts following me down the street, singing, have you seen a polythene Pam?
She's so good looking, what she looks like.
A man.
That, I am less enthusiastic about. I mean, not that that's ever happened.
I'm completely fucking unclockable, hey, how are you?
No one knows what it's like to be a sad tran.
I definitely get where feminists are coming from, because street harassment sucks. I'm a lot more
afraid walking alone at night than I used to be, and there's a lot more places I just won't go by
myself. But on the other hand, I do now enjoy being able to walk down the street at night,
without other people acting afraid of me. I think a lot of feminists have failed to imagine the ways
that being treated as invisible or dangerous can also kind of suck. In my video on incels,
I talked about male invisibility on dating apps, and how getting no attention at all can actually
be emotionally worse than getting a lot of shitty attention. And when it comes to being treated as
dangerous, when I was living as a man, sometimes if I was walking at night, a woman on the same
block as me would change sides of the street. And I totally get why. Men do scary shit sometimes,
and it's better to be safe. But it's still stung a little bit to be treated as dangerous by default.
I think it can actually be harmful, which becomes clearer if we add race into the equation. There's
ways that white women's fear can actually be dangerous, in particular to black men.
I had an experience with this recently when I was filming my video The Apocalypse,
and I had rented a room in a hotel casino. Around midnight,
I was carrying some camera equipment up to my room, and I got into the elevator with a group
of people from the casino floor. A couple floors up, everyone got out of the elevator except for me,
and a single black man. Well, I mean, he was alone. I don't know if he was single. That's
not part of the story. And as soon as the door closed, he started literally whistling Row,
Row, Row Your Boat, the official melody of performative innocence. And I realized,
oh shit, he's afraid that I'm afraid. And I found that just excruciating. I was like,
oh god, how do other white women behave in elevators? Do they, like, clutch their purses?
Ugh, that's so foggy embarrassing. Nothing like that had ever happened to me when I was living
as a man. It's not a thing between black men and white men. It's a thing between black men
and white women. And so that dynamic was there, not just because I'm white and he's black, but
because I'm a woman and he's a man. And I thought of that incident again when I was listening to
it. And Farrell says, men's greatest weakness is their facade of strength, and women's greatest
strength is their facade of weakness. I think there is some truth to the idea that women's
perceived vulnerability can make them powerful, and men's perceived power can make them vulnerable.
Now I hope you're taking all this with a grain of salt, because these are just some little
observations I've made based on a handful of anecdotes. And as rational males, it's important
that we consider the facts, the stats, and the figures. Did you know?
Did you know that 46% of men are at least 2.8 times different than 73% of women? Look it up.
I haven't. I guess my super fucking Libra opinion is that there's upsides and downsides to male and
female experience. I don't actually think there's a single definite answer to the vague and useless
question, which gender has it worse? I consider myself a feminist because I support reproductive
rights and I oppose workplace misogyny, and I generally agree with a lot of the activism that
happens under the heading of feminism. But I also think a lot of men are just
having a super fucking difficult time right now, and that must be super fucking hard for them,
eh? How are you? And I don't think feminists have an obligation to care about male angst,
but I care about you boys. God, I'm such a cool girl, I think the entire mid-Atlantic
region is about to freeze over. No, I'm just a super fucking empathetic Pisces moon,
and I really try to understand other people's pain, because I just find it really, really funny.
I'm also really, really sobering up here. The drugs have worn off, and I'm suddenly feeling
very naked. Like, it's just now occurring to me that this is a highly inappropriate outfit for
this occasion. So, I'm gonna go put on a robe, and I'll meet you back for the next section.
Postulate 3. The Man Question.
Hi boys.
Et cetera, et cetera.
Hey, how are you?
For the last three years on this channel, I have been your Virgil, leading you through gender hell.
Pick-up artists, gender dysphoria, incels, radical feminists, non-binary genders,
men's rights activists. It seems like everybody's having gender trouble, so what do we make of that?
Well, Gorg, a very, very rational male philosopher named Hegel once said that the unfolding of
history is a
basically rational process, Gorg. That means that at any time in history, society is based
on certain principles, like, um, all men are created equal as long as they're super fucking
rich and white. And there's always contradictions within those principles, which creates tension
and eventually leads to a rupture, like a revolution, where society has to be reorganized
according to new principles. At least, I think he was saying something like that. It's pretty
hard to make anything out through the fog of his unreadable, hyper-abstract man-jabbing.
God, I can't stand that shit. Or any of the other music-hating vol-cells of the male philosophical
tradition. My point is, I think our society has reached a place where gender as we know
it just isn't working anymore. Now, no one seems to agree why it isn't working or how
to fix it, but we do all agree that it's broken. We have mainstream feminists saying we need
to continue advancing the rights of women. We have conservatives saying we need to restore
the gender roles of the 1950s. We have an increasing number of people not identifying
as men or women. We have TERFs saying we need to restore the gender roles of women. We have
transphobic TERFs who think that the transgenders are the single greatest threat to civilization,
hey, how are you? And we have men's rights activists saying we need a male equivalent
to feminism to liberate men from their oppressive gender role. Now, I want to focus on that
last one, because in principle, I agree. I've spent a lot of the last three years covering
the manosphere. I know, such a feminine topic, love that for me. And from all the time I've
tortured myself wading through these communities of incels, pick-up artists, men's rights slacktivists,
intellectual dark web fanboys, and anti-feminism activists, I've come to the conclusion that
I'm not the only one who thinks that the transgenders are the single greatest threat to civilization,
hey, how are you? And we have men's rights activists saying we need a male equivalent to feminism to liberate
men from their oppressive gender role. Now, I've spent a lot of the last three years On
the same planet world, somewhere in our own lives, some of those healthy species have
nothing to do with us or anything else, and all of our vakas and 1000s of racisms have
nothing to do with that mother24 and the others, but happens to be a lie to me. Yeah,
morph forests, freaking you guys and shit, bullshit. Yeah. But to at least identify who
long, crossedació this great opportunity of our funky moments because,
it all starts from up here, says Mike. And you lie to me, you mean七
And just to clarify, I'm not trying to take away your video games and pornography,
but I am not telling you what to do with your penis, you can rub one out once in a while
for this video for all I care–let's just move on.
ok?
Don't pull a GamerKeed on me, okay?
I live in fear.
Look, I like to believe that until the red pillars
inject their poison, most of these boys are not bad people.
I think all of this originates in a genuine crisis
of male identity, and I think it's happened
in something like the way men's rights activists describe.
The sacrificial role of men as warriors
is no longer widely glorified or necessary.
The traditional protector-provider role of men
is being replaced by a more equal
and undefined gender dynamic.
And college professors and activists are telling men
that most of our culture's aspirational representations
of manhood are toxic and bad.
But without an attractive replacement vision
of aspirational manhood, average young men
can only envision their future as what?
The beta, the cock, the new male.
And in a post-left-toop internet,
we're so used to laughing at this vocabulary.
And to be fair, it is very funny.
But we forget,
especially us grills, that for a lot of men,
these words actually do tap into a deep existential angst.
And a lot of leftists go,
well, how can men be so angsty?
Especially white men, they're so privileged.
But existential angst is often a disease of privilege.
If you're actually being oppressed, you have a struggle,
you have something to fight for, and therefore, a purpose.
But for a lot of men, their lack of purpose
puts them in search of a struggle.
And that, along with the loneliness
and the lack of a positive identity,
is what makes men vulnerable to recruitment
by the manosphere groups and by the alt-right.
And even worse, it seems to be a motivating factor
for the small but growing number of young men
who decide to pick up a gun
and open fire in a shopping center.
There were two mass shootings during the weekend
I was writing this video, resulting in 31 deaths.
Both shooters were young white men,
and one of them posted about the shooting
on an alt-right image board.
Now, I don't pretend to fully understand
the motives of mass shooters, but I don't think it's true.
I don't think it's true.
I don't think it's a coincidence
that basically all of them are men.
One possible interpretation of the mass shooting epidemic
is that these killers are trying to resurrect
some horrible parody of ancient masculine glory,
and therefore, to be seen and recognized as men
by unleashing Homeric violence in a fucking Walmart.
And of course, there's also the racism
of the alt-right killers,
and the wounded sexual entitlement of the incel killers.
But that racism and that sexual entitlement are learned,
and men in the throes of a masculinity crisis
are more receptive to learning it.
So, you can try to take down their forums,
and ban their accounts, and de-platform their events,
but as long as this male identity crisis goes on,
I don't see any end to these problems.
Theorem four, what do?
There is this media narrative that has emerged
around me and around this channel.
And by the way, the fact that there's any kind
of media narrative about this channel
is super fucking coconuts.
Because let's be real, Gorge,
I just wanted to pour milk on my face
and talk about the mouthfeel.
But there's this media narrative that my role
in the discourse is de-radicalizing young alt-right men.
And it's true that if you read
the leftist YouTube fan subreddits,
I used to be alt-right posts are so common
they're considered cliche.
And some of them cite me as an influence
in changing their politics, which I love for them,
and I'm super fucking happy about it, but it's also,
um, a lot of responsibility.
They're my boys, and I worry about my boys.
Because in reality, it's not like they go
from far right extremists to complacent centrists.
No, most of them go far left.
A lot of them become communists or anarchists.
So I watch them go from far to my right
to significantly to my left.
It's not really de-radicalizing so much as re-radicalizing.
And I think it's definitely an improvement,
but I still worry it's not gonna be enough.
I worry about my boys because I don't think
that the left yet has a final solution to the man question.
Oh no, that was worded poorly.
You know, there's kind of two options the left has
for disillusioned men.
The first is the Marxist promise of economic revolution.
We say, well, actually, yes, you are oppressed,
but you're oppressed because of your class, not your gender.
So just join the revolution.
It's gonna be super fucking crazy.
We're gonna overthrow the bourgeoisie, meow, meow.
Smash, no voting.
And then things will be better for you.
Now, I think that has a couple limitations.
One is that I look at the far left
and I see a bunch of people who spend all their time
accusing each other of abusing moderator privileges
in closed Facebook groups.
And I'm concerned that might not succeed
at ending capitalism, meow, meow.
Like definitely vote for Bernie Sanders
or Elizabeth Warren or whoever.
But if you're investing all of your hopes
in a capital R revolution, I worry that can be
become like waiting for Godot or waiting for the rapture.
So we do need political change,
but I feel like I'm failing my boys
if I'm somehow giving them the idea
that revolution is their only hope.
Cause here's the other thing,
even if we did succeed ending capitalism,
there would still be gender.
And my boys would still need some model
of what it is to lead a good life as a man.
Now the other option the left has for disillusioned men
is the feminist tranquilizer.
We say, look, talk about how it's not about how you live.
This is the feminist tranquilizer.
Toxic masculinity is the reason you don't have room to express your feelings and it's the reason
you feel lonely and inadequate. So while feminism tells women you hate your body and you're
constantly doubting yourself because society did this to you and needs to change, we kind of just
tell men you're lonely and suicidal because you're toxic. Stop it. We tell them they're broken without
really telling them how to fix themselves. I think what we need is a new positive ideal of manhood
which I don't think is something that women can create for men even if they wanted to. And honestly
the best way for that to happen may actually be some kind of men's movement. But on the left the
whole idea of a men's movement is basically taboo because the men's movement we all know is basically
just a backlash to feminism and at worst it's just straight up misogyny. And look boys, I understand
that being lectured about man spreading for most of 2015 was super fucking hard for you and you're
still mad about it but posting endless
outrage porn about false rape accusations and paternity fraud isn't actually going to make life
any better for you. Because yes, those things are horrible when they happen but they're not systemic
issues that affect most men. I think what would actually improve life for most men is a positive
ideal of 21st century manhood but that's not something I can give to you because in case you
hadn't noticed I'm literally a fucking woman. I can't mom you through this one boys, you're on
your own.
You don't have to help each other. So find each other in the comments section, meet up on reddit, make friends, clean your room, leave the house, fuck each other, I don't know, it's worth a try.
And failing that, you could always throw in the towel and become a woman. Worked for me.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye.
Like and subscribe.
And subscribe.
Bye bye.
Bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye bye be brave.
Bye.
for their labor and women are useful for their wombs well i'm a woman without a womb so i guess
i'm useless but i'm beautifully useless oh i'm a work of art the problem with our society is we've
turned men into women it's disgusting as an ally to men it's not my place to speak for them or speak
over them but i just want to use my platform to uplift some male voices who might not have as
many subscribers as me okay i'm not hypergamous i don't need a rich husband if i make what share
i don't need a rich man i am a rich man it's not even really much of an insult being called
a delusional man many great books have been written by delusional men so bad i'm bad i'm
really bad
okay