All right, children. It's a new decade. It's time to face the facts. How do I put this
delicately? Your humble hostess is a total les. Shame. You're probably worried this
is a coming out video, and I'm sorry to tell you that it is, but oh, it's so much worse
than just that. You know, one, coming out may be regarded as a misfortune. Two, looks
like carelessness. And three, well, at that point, you're just doing it for attention.
And I do love attention. I want to be very clear about that, but I also happen to be
gay. Some gay people love attention. It's been known to happen. So there comes a time
in a woman's life when you have to take a step back, look yourself in the mirror, and
admit, this is some high-key, lesbicious behavior. And I'm going to talk you through how I got
to that point. So, story time, I fell in love with my best friend. Story time, telling my
boyfriend I'm a lesbian. Story time, my parents walked in on my Taco Bell mukbang. Exposed,
graphic, the tea is piping hot. For a long time on this channel, the official story has
been that I'm bi. I'm a super fucking bi. But I haven't dated.
I haven't dated women since I transitioned. And for a while there, I got pretty deep into
the straight lifestyle. This really started in 2018. By that summer, I had privately convinced
myself that I was a fully heterosexual woman. And we're going to circle back to how I reached
that conclusion. But I'm starting in the middle of things. I'm like an epic poet.
Hail Muse. Hey, how are you, gorge? So at the beginning of 2018, I became close friends,
I'd even say best friends, with a woman whom
I'll call Joanne. Light of my life. Can we get some melodramatic music, please? Yeah,
here we go. You're going to want to pour yourself a glass of something nice. I want you to fully
enjoy my pain. So my friendship with Joanne got very intense, very fast. It was that kind
of friendship where you develop your own private language of references and in-jokes, and you
drive everyone around you crazy with your unintelligible banter. We'd call each other
pretty much every day, and we'd talk for hours. And I don't think I've ever called her and
not been laughing or smiling in the first 20 seconds, which is very unusual for me, because
I am a weird, and I don't get along that well with that many people. One reason we got so emotionally
close is we're both trans. And there's a kind of intuitive understanding and a sense of humor that
I can share with another trans woman that I can't really have with anyone else. Oh, and by the way,
Joanne also happens to be just angelically beautiful, which I did notice every time I looked at her.
And from the beginning of this relationship,
it wasn't sexual, but it wasn't exactly platonic either. We'd get drunk and make out. We'd sleep in
the same bed and cuddle. Straight girls do that, right? Gal pals. I remember one of the first times
I hung out with Joanne, we got our nails done together. And that night, we were bar hopping,
and she took my pretty hand and her pretty hand, and we walked down the street together holding
hands. This is garbage, and I want to die. I hope you all know that I'm in agony. Later,
we were at a bar table with friends.
And every time one of us needed a drink, we'd run off to the bar, and she'd secretly kiss me.
Ah, it's still one of the most magical gay things that's ever happened to me.
Joanne had a boyfriend at the time, but he didn't care. A lot of men think girls kissing is hot,
but they don't take it seriously. They don't think it could ever mean anything or
lead to a real relationship. Gal pals. Just kill me. Take me out behind the shed,
put me down humanely, and just buy a new YouTuber before the kids get home, and they won't know,
I guess. So this very intimate friendship went on for about a year without me acknowledging to
Joanne or to myself that I was falling in love. So not only was I in denial about being in love
with her, but at the same time, I had basically convinced myself that I only wanted to date men.
So how could I possibly think that? Well, the short answer is shame. Why is no one talking
about the shame? I was so ashamed of my attraction to women. There were days I thought the shame was
going to crush me to death. Oh, I wanted to be straight so bad, and let no one say I didn't make
a strong attempt. There should honestly be a statue of me sucking dick in a town square with
the inscription, here knelt Natalie Wynn, attempted heterosexual. I'm a bronze star lesbian. Well,
if we're really being honest, I don't think I get a star. Oh, I was desperate to be straight.
I tried prayer. I tried electric shocks. All the classics. All the hits. You know, the idea is,
if you shock yourself every time you think about women, you start to associate the two in your
head. So now I'm a lesbian and I enjoy electric shocks. This is supposed to hurt, but I just feel
like I'm on a road trip with Cate Blanchett. So at some point, the shame was just too much for me,
and it literally broke my brain. I no longer wanted to be straight. I simply deluded myself
into thinking I was straight. Maybe a little bi. A little bi. By that time, I started dating men,
and I got into a serious long-term relationship,
with a man. And at first, I explained away my feelings for Joanne, by telling myself,
female friendships are just really intense. That's probably why I feel so strongly. And
everyone thinks women are beautiful, so it's only natural I notice that. And, you know,
spend a lot of time thinking about it. So this nonsense went on until the beginning
of last year, and then two things happened. First, Joanne started dating a cis lesbian.
Second, Joanne started dating a cis lesbian. Third, Joanne started dating a cis lesbian.
Fuck my drag, right? I think before that, I always knew she was bi, but
some combination of self-interested denial and biphobia allowed me to write off my initial
crush on her as, I just have a thing for my straight best friend. Like, who doesn't?
But that's a very self-serving narrative, because it quarantines your feelings inside
the safety of unattainable fantasy, and it wards off the pain of potential rejection.
Because that way, it's not really me she's rejecting, it's just,
she's just not that into women. But once she started dating women,
I couldn't tell myself that anymore. And the jealousy hit me so hard, I couldn't ignore it.
Second, around that same time, Joanne decided to visit me for a few weeks.
It was a long-distance friendship. And about halfway through that visit,
I cracked. One morning, I woke up next to her, and I looked at her pretty fucking face,
and I had the thought, I want to wake up next to you every day of my life.
And that is a pretty alarming thought for a petite heterosexual bio girl to have about her gal pal.
Oh, never in my life have I fallen so deeply in love with someone. Like, what the fuck is this?
What am I feeling? I was experiencing an intensity of emotion that has no right to exist outside of
19th century Italian opera. So I confessed my feelings to Joanne, and love confession gone wrong,
devastating.
...
Nurse! My pain is at a 10, I need more pills!
Needless to say, my heart was shattered, I cried a sea of tears, blah blah blah,
I'm sure we all know how that goes.
And here's the thing, if we'd taken a three-month friendship break right then and there,
I might have recovered. But we couldn't keep away from each other. She wasn't in love with me, but
she must have been in something with me, because the truth is, we were never just gal pals.
And I was beyond reason. Like, I probably would have started one of those
... lesbian couple joint Instagram accounts, that's how tragic this got. Those are great, by the way.
Pay no attention to bitter queens.
So for the rest of 2019, Joanne and I kept talking, kept visiting each other, and I just repeated this
heartbreak again and again and again. Now if she had reciprocated my feelings, I probably would have
come out as gay last year, because the heat of a romantic relationship has a way of evaporating
shame. But rejection and heartbreak are shameful in themselves, and only made the situation worse.
So I spent most of 2019 going in and out of bed with Joanne, and I was like, what the fuck is going on?
I was like, what the fuck is going on? I was like, what the fuck is going on? I was like, what the fuck is going on?
So I spent most of 2019 going in and out of denial, until finally, last October, I got super
fucking cancelled on Twitter as discussed in my last video. Link in the description! Subscribe!
And at the same time, Joanne realized that she was going to have to be the one to enforce a
friendship break, otherwise I was never going to get over her. So there was this combination of
things, being politically cancelled by Twitter, being romantically cancelled by Joanne, and also
losing her as my closest friend, which sent me into this catatonic,
rock-bottom,
kind of depression. And of course depression is a terrible thing, but I think it can also serve a
purpose. Because depression brings your life to a standstill, and in the quiet of that standstill,
you sometimes feel outside yourself. And with that, comes a new perspective.
So last December, when I was lying around drinking White Claw all day and
binge-watching Orange is the Bluest L Word, I actually didn't feel so much shame anymore.
And that gave me a new kind of clarity. I looked back on the last couple years,
and saw that I'd been avoiding the obvious. So that's what it took for me to finally face the
fact that I am a, uh… I am a gay, not clickbait.
I'm sorry.
No, no.
You're not.
Adam's a great guy and all, but I want Lilith.
Shame.
This floral fantasy is a little less Mother of Mankind
and a little more Coachella 2015.
Well that's my Eden.
Candy flipping. I love it.
Okay, let's circle back and talk about how a wholesome homo like me
wound up in the clutches of the straight agenda.
It starts with denial, and there's two sides to gay denial.
First, there was a period where I repressed or explained away my attraction to women.
Female friendships are just really intense.
Straight girls have girl crushes too.
And second, I experienced and acted on what I genuinely thought
was sexual and romantic attraction to men.
And to be honest, I'm still kind of struggling to make sense of all this.
Maybe I'm not quite ready to make this video,
but I'm afraid that if I don't, the shame will overpower me again
and I'll slide back into denial.
So, while I'm still here,
still thinking semi-clearly,
let me talk you through the struggle.
Because, like most queer people,
I find nothing more fascinating than an in-depth analysis of my own personality.
She's a Libra.
So in 2017, I started taking feminizing hormones.
And most people are aware of the more obvious effects of that,
like, it makes you grow breasts.
At least, in theory.
I just added progesterone, we'll see if that does anything.
But the lesser known thing is it has some pretty major effects on your mood and your sexuality.
The first few months I was on hormones,
I didn't know if I was now asexual
because the libido I had known before was just gone.
But I'm very much not asexual.
It just took me a while to adjust to an endocrinologically female sex drive.
One of the differences for me is
it's not as obvious now whomst I'm attracted to.
Just looking at an attractive person,
well, let's put it this way,
it sparks my interest,
but it doesn't light my fire.
It's not the instant inferno that is testosterone-fueled lust.
It's a slow burn that has to be built up.
Some people call this demisexual,
which is a term I'm ambivalent about,
but I think the concept it describes applies to me.
Like, I form little crushes on people based on watching their YouTube videos or whatever,
but I don't feel intense sexual attraction to anyone
until I've gotten close to them as a friend.
So I have a hard time getting too excited about casual dating, you know?
Can't I just find a new best friend,
fall insanely in love with her, and then get gay married?
I know that's not how it works.
I have to play the field.
I also think it's a reason I don't really like porn that much.
Because sex without context is just mechanics to me.
It's boring.
The buildup of desire, that's the interesting part,
and the struggle between desire and shame.
I shouldn't, but I want to.
That's how you build a plotline, kids.
I'm also guessing this kind of slow burn sexuality
is more common in women than men.
And I wonder if that's a reason why gay men
tend to know they're gay at an earlier age than gay women.
When you have teenage boy testosterone levels,
it's harder to be agnostic or mistaken about who you're attracted to.
Whereas, there's a lot of gay women who don't realize they're gay
until they're in their 30s or even later.
And thank God for them!
They make me feel less bad about my wasted youth.
So it's hard for me to use visual sexual interest
as a guide to my sexuality.
Because I do feel aesthetic attraction towards beautiful people of any gender,
and that can be pretty intense in its own right.
I guess the difference for me is
looking at a beautiful woman
is more emotionally captivating to me
than looking at a beautiful man.
Which can be moving in its own way,
but it's more like the way I'm moved by,
I don't know,
the Parthenon.
You know, it's sturdy,
symmetrical,
has impressive columns.
That's not to say it's totally asexual.
I mean, I'd fuck the Parthenon.
I'd fuck it so hard.
I admit I do have some kind of erotic fascination with masculinity,
and maybe that stems from my pre-transition sense
of having failed at masculinity,
so I'm mesmerized by the real thing.
There's something about the contrast
between me and a masculine man
that's sexually intriguing to me.
Like I've sometimes pleasantly gasped
at the feeling of hairy, muscly arms
enfolding my smooth, fragile body.
Or maybe it's more Freudian,
the masculine man as Daddy,
the archetypal father,
the symbolic power of the phallus.
Penetration is the ultimate expression of desire and possession.
There's a lot of sexual connotations to manhood,
and I think that's why I can look at a sexy man
and create plausible fantasies in my head
where I'd absolutely enjoy letting him do things to me.
And I can find things I like about male bodies,
like they're very warm.
I love it when you get under the covers with a man
and he warms you up.
But that's when the lesbian voice comes into my head
and she says,
but are you attracted to men?
Or do you just like being warm?
My attraction to women is very different.
I look at a beautiful woman and it's just like,
oh no, you're gorgeous, you're beautiful.
This is going to destroy me.
You know, it can actually be painful
how beautiful a woman is.
I've never once been in pain over male beauty,
but around Joanne,
once I was open about my feelings and things got bad,
there'd be moments I'd have to just look away from her
and be like, don't even enter my line of sight right now.
You're too beautiful, I can't stand it.
There's a kind of sick masochism
in wanting someone who doesn't want you back.
It's insatiable, like an addiction.
And on the flip side,
there's an intense erotic thrill in being desired.
I think that's what got me interested in men
in the first place.
It's that they're interested in me.
And that's pretty interesting.
I've felt desired by men
in a way I've never truly felt desired by women.
You know, a man will glower at you
with that agitation,
agitated, carnivorous desperation.
Fuck me up, King.
God, that's hot.
Gets me every time.
But notice how excitement at the attention,
the flattery of being desired,
is not the same thing as attraction to men.
You know, there's a difference between I want you
and I like that you want me.
But for a long time, I confused one for the other.
And one reason I was able to do that
is that the normative sexual role for women
is to be pursued, possessed, desired,
seduced, dominated by men.
It's all very passive.
And in most of the sexual encounters I've had with men,
I've taken a very submissive role.
Sometimes I just submit to the glower
and let them do things to me.
And I do think that the thrill of being desired
is a valid thing to want.
I like that feeling myself,
and I do genuinely enjoy taking on
a more submissive role sometimes.
But you have to go about it thoughtfully.
Because if you don't,
sexual submission can be a way to avoid
confronting what your desires actually are.
It's freedom from freedom.
And if you're ashamed of your sexual orientation,
and ashamed of your transsexual body,
and ashamed of having any sexual feelings at all
because of stigma about trans women being fetishists,
then relinquishing responsibility for your own desires
by letting someone else take control
can be the only way
you can enjoy sex at all.
And for a while,
it was almost the only way I could enjoy it.
And I was able to convince myself that was normal
because the sexual situation of a lot of cis straight women
isn't really that much more liberated.
Like I read Fifty Shades of Grey years ago
and totally identified with the fantasy.
And later,
I thought that was evidence
I had normative female desires.
Never mind that I was identifying
with the midlife crisis fantasies
of a repressed English housewife,
longing to be brutalized by a capitalist tyrant.
I mean, not to shame women
who genuinely do enjoy a healthier version of that fantasy,
I think a lot of women
pointlessly suffer under a kind of feminist guilt about that.
But what makes me different is that for me,
submission to a man
was simply the only way I could enjoy sex without shame.
And that's a lot of what I did for a couple years,
even though my real sexual attraction is to women.
Whereas, even in the most patriarchal situation,
straight women are,
ultimately attracted to men,
and sexually aroused by male bodies.
Or are they?
Gay men certainly are,
and gay women are just rhapsodic about women.
But a lot of straight women are just kind of,
meh,
about male bodies and men in general.
Which,
what is that about?
I just,
do not understand straight women.
I don't think I ever will,
and that's okay.
I'm just gonna accept my bewilderment
and move on with my lesbian life.
Now,
what I've been giving you so far
is a retrospective analysis,
an autopsy of my romantic failings of the last two years.
But you have to understand
that when I was living through this,
I experienced it very differently,
because I didn't have these insights.
So I wasn't thinking,
oh, I'm not really attracted to men,
but I enjoy the thrill of being desired by them,
so I'm gonna pursue that
to distract myself from how ashamed I am
of my attraction to women.
No.
Subconsciously,
I put my attraction to women on mute.
At least,
Joanne ruined my life.
And I genuinely thought I was attracted to men,
which was a lot more than just a frivolous sexual fantasy.
I had a serious long-term boyfriend
for a year and a half,
who I had very genuine feelings for.
Plot twist,
story time.
So,
my ex-boyfriend,
let's call him
Chad.
Oh, and he was a Chad.
Like,
full Giga-Chad fantasy.
You know, he was very masculine,
taller than me,
objectively attractive,
very charming.
Straight women used to tell me all the time
they were jealous of me for being with him,
and obviously I loved that.
To me,
Chad represented
almost an ideal of manhood,
a sort of archetypal romantic lead
who swept me off my feet
and fulfilled my sick fantasies
of being a heterosexual woman.
Now, you probably think I'm gonna say
that he was just an abstract fantasy to me,
but that once it came to actually dating,
I realized I didn't like it.
But honestly,
it's more complicated than that.
Like, at the beginning,
I was the one who pursued him,
and I still think of him as the one
genuine boy crush of my life.
When we started dating,
it was really exciting.
I'd never had a boyfriend before,
and he'd never been with a trans woman before,
and we had this, like,
adorably heterosexual energy together,
like, holding hands in the park.
It was cute!
This would be a better lesbian story
if Chad was a Cad.
But he wasn't.
He was great.
He took very good care of me.
He was never ashamed to be seen,
or of his friends and family
knowing he was dating me,
which, if you're a trans woman,
that's a huge deal.
He was a lot less ashamed of me
than I am of myself.
And when I was with him,
I wasn't ashamed.
And that meant a lot.
So I really wanted this to work.
Like, if I was gonna be with a man,
he was the one.
And for a year or so,
I thought it was working.
I enjoyed the time we spent together.
I missed him when he was gone.
I told him I loved him,
and I meant it.
But what happened is,
by the end of the first year,
the initial excitement had died down.
And while Chad was ready
to keep escalating the relationship,
I was realizing that
something was very seriously,
emotionally wrong on my end.
There was something missing.
And when I realized
I was in love with Joanne,
I was like,
there's that missing feeling.
And I started to understand
what my problem was.
Then, last fall,
I posted to Instagram
an aloof picture of me
with the caption,
do I actually like men?
Or do I just like attention?
And I didn't mean anything serious by that.
I was just joking around.
You know, you can post something like that,
and a bunch of straight women will respond like,
yeah, fuck men.
What is their damage?
Well, they're stuck dating men.
That's their damage.
But a few people left comments saying,
oh, are you making a video about comphet?
You should make a video about comphet.
And I was like,
what the fuck is comphet?
So I Googled it,
and I learned that comphet is short
for compulsory heterosexuality.
Basically, it's the idea
that heterosexuality is socially required of women.
And it's so bound up with the conventional idea
of what it even means to be a woman
that gay women often mistakenly believe
for years that they're attracted to men.
And this Google search led me to a Reddit post
called the Am I a Lesbian Master Doc?
And I'm reading through this post like,
oh no, this sounds terribly familiar.
Quote,
compulsory heterosexuality is the voice in my head
that says I must really be het
even when I'm in love with a woman.
Quote,
you have every reason to be happy
in your relationship with a man,
but you just aren't.
Everything is going really well,
but something is missing
and you can't figure out what.
So next thing you know,
I'm doing tequila shots at 3 a.m.
and taking Am I a Lesbian internet quizzes
that were clearly designed for 13 year olds.
And I'm fully a 31 year old transsexual
taking this quiz like,
it's true, Samantha was right,
I am a total les.
All the cis gay people watching this video
probably want to kill me right now
because y'all figured this shit out in high school
and I'm sitting here in my 30s like,
it's just, I just, I just can't, I just.
Well, can I be a melodramatic baby gay
for 30 minutes of my lifetime, please?
Is it all right with you, the gays?
So to be honest,
I still experience comphet thoughts and fantasies.
Like for a long time,
I've had what seemed to be romantic fantasies
about marrying a man.
But after a lot of introspection,
I've realized that this is not really a fantasy
of private happiness and fulfillment.
It's a fantasy of a social prestige and acceptance.
Like, can you imagine if I got married
to a tall, handsome man
at an opulent wedding
with lots of photographers posting to Instagram?
Ah, I'd be queen of the trannies.
I'd be super heckin' valid, uwu.
But I don't actually want to be married.
I want to get married.
I want to have a wedding.
Basically, I want to wear a wedding dress.
I want attention, okay?
Please, pay, pay attention to me.
So I can totally deconstruct the fantasy,
but it's still really hard for me to let it go.
I cling to the reassuring conformity of heterosexuality
because there's a level
of gender instability and deviancy
that's inherent to homosexuality.
And until recently,
I wasn't secure enough in my gender to handle that.
Lesbianism is a very advanced form of womanhood,
and I think I needed to go through
the more one-on-one straight girl experience
before attempting anything as difficult as that.
I still have a hard time imagining
a happy future for myself
as a woman partnered to a woman.
And I think that's partly because
good lesbian representation in media
is so sparse.
The best we have is a Showtime melodrama
from 15 years ago,
which I do like,
and I like the new one too.
But after that,
the runner-up is,
I mean,
maybe not the lesbian representation we need.
It's a YouTube show about two drag queens
whomst we ship.
Well, I don't ship them,
because I have a fully lesbian
parasocial internet crush
on Katya Zamolochkova.
Don't laugh at me.
She's smart.
She's funny.
She's beautiful.
That's everything I'm looking for in a woman.
Sure, some haters and losers
will probably try to convince me
that Katya is in fact a homosexual man
posing as a woman,
but you know what?
This is a super fucking vulnerable moment in my life,
and I don't need this right now.
I need to be touched by a real woman.
I'm losing my goddamn mind.
It's so deeply embedded in our culture
that marrying a man
is the end goal of womanhood.
And it's not just Disney movies,
like, it's the Bible,
it's Greek mythology,
American fairy tales,
Victorian novels.
The whole weight of cultural history
is telling you
that what it means to succeed as a woman
is to marry a man.
And if you're already super dysphoric
and insecure about your gender,
then to reject that possibility?
Ah, it hurts.
It hurts so bad.
But whenever I think about
having a long-term partner,
you know, not the wedding day,
but the 1000th morning waking up together,
I can only imagine her being a woman.
My brain wants a good man
to take care of me.
But my heart wants a high-maintenance diva
to ruin my life.
And once I knew that for sure,
I thought it would be wrong to stay with Chad.
And this man was like my hinge.
He was holding me together.
But last December,
I broke up with him
because I'm a lesbian,
which at least is a good reason.
I'm having a hard time, you guys.
Leave your pity in the comments.
And I'm starting to regret eating this fruit, too.
I feel like shit.
I think it's the loss of my immortal soul
weighing on me.
I could really use a couple Advil
and a vodka tonic.
I think I might throw some clothes on, too.
Where's that snake?
I already miss my heterosexual nails.
I know these are too long to be gay,
but baby steps, okay?
This is hard for me.
Getting my acrylics removed?
Traumatizing.
I feel like I'm detransitioning.
One of these days,
I will do the lesbian manicure
with acrylics on eight fingers.
I just have to find the courage
to walk into a salon and say,
Hi, I'm a homosexual, please.
I want two short nails
so I can fuck pussy.
Shame.
Let's talk about the shame.
Before I was transgendered,
I really only dated women,
though two of those women
later turned out to be trans,
so I guess we had some way
of finding each other.
An attraction to women
was never really a problem for me
before the transgendering
because I was raised
in an alternative lifestyle
where men are supposed
to be attracted to women.
Crazy, I know.
Not that I'm a newcomer to shame,
because, oh, sweaty?
I was doing plenty of things
that men are not supposed to do.
Before I transitioned,
my shame was centered around
my being, at the time,
a gender nonconforming man,
which, in my early YouTube videos,
I dealt with by caricaturing myself
and basically leaning in
to the public humiliation.
One of my classic techniques.
But now, my shame is centered around
my failure to be a socially acceptable woman.
And the most glaring aspects
of that failure are
my male past,
my sexual orientation,
and the severed human heads
in my refrigerator.
Yeah, killing all those people
was not my most feminine moment,
but I was having a bad skin day.
What was I supposed to do?
So there's two problems
that kind of multiply together.
One, I'm ashamed of being trans.
Two, I'm ashamed of being a lesbian.
And whatever one times two is,
I'm really ashamed
of being a trans lesbian.
Ugh.
And it's difficult and risky
for me to admit these feelings,
because visible queer people
are supposed to perform pride.
Why is no one talking about the shame?
Because we are ashamed of the shame.
But we shouldn't be.
The shame is a natural result of shaming.
I grew up in a media era
when trans women were usually represented
as vomit-inducing monstrosities
who deserve the violence
they bring upon themselves by existing.
And I started my transition
in the first year of the Trump administration
when there's been constant vilification
of trans people in the press.
Invading women's bathrooms,
forcing our insanity on children,
destroying Western civilization
with our authoritarian pronouns.
It's hard to express just
the daily humiliation
of being a trans woman under these conditions.
And then there's the little jabs people throw at you,
like my laser technician recently told me,
you must be very courageous to transition
because that is not socially acceptable.
And then she went back to blasting laser beams
into my asshole.
And then there's the internet,
where, you know,
I used to spend most of my life
before the sadness took over.
And I'm sure we all know
that people on the internet
are a wretched, wretched horde
of bigoted attack helicopters.
The whole point of this channel
is I try to talk sense to these people.
I talk to the TERFs and the conservatives
and I try to empathize with their point of view
and provide a rational response.
But a side effect of all that research
is I've acquired a burgeoning vocabulary
of self-loathing.
It's seeped into my brain
and become a part of me.
And this lifelong buildup of shame
has become a wound
at the heart of my existence.
And all I can really do about it is
compensate by wearing fancy clothes.
I may be trash,
but I am a genius.
I am majestic trash.
I am resplendent trash.
I am couture trash.
And I just bought
a mid-century gold-trimmed
Venetian blown glass decanter,
which helps me forget
the shame and self-loathing
that plagues my every moment.
Now, I'm guessing
that a lot of people will be confused
about why I'm so ashamed of being gay
when I've already come out as trans,
which seems like a bigger deal.
To paraphrase what some people have told me,
you're already a transgendered
and a freak's a freak,
so who cares what kind of freak?
Well, first of all,
I would like to propose
a sociological theory.
Tiffany's Law.
All freaks
have a deep psychological need
to feel superior
to a different type of freak.
And trans lesbians
are pretty close to the bottom
of that packing order.
Who's even left for me
to feel superior to?
The goddamn Belgians?
Fuck this waffle.
Second,
coming out as trans
wasn't as hard for me
because I did it incrementally
over like eight years.
At first,
I was like,
well,
I'm just a man
who wears makeup sometimes.
Then I was like,
actually,
it's not just clothes and makeup.
I'm actually pretty gender nonconforming
in a lot of ways.
And then I realized
I'm not a man at all
and I identified as nonbinary.
Then I started taking hormones.
In two months on HRT,
I woke up one day and said,
it's fine.
I am literally a woman.
So by the time
I actually came out
as a trans woman,
that was actually a step up
in terms of social acceptability
from where I was before.
When I was a genderqueer genderfuck,
I felt like
I didn't fit in anywhere.
Whereas
when I started transitioning
to female,
even though at first
I had a lot of the same problems,
there was at least
a goal in mind,
some possible future
where I could lead
a normal-ish life as a woman.
So the moment
I started identifying
as a woman
was the moment
the compet voice
entered my head.
Sure,
I've never been very attracted
to men before,
but maybe I'm attracted
to them now.
I'm a woman, right?
I've always been
a little bi-curious
and there was that time
I kissed a boy
when I was drunk.
Let's choose some boys
to be attracted to
and get started on this.
Of course,
I wasn't as self-aware
as that.
My way of explaining it
to myself was,
I guess,
hormones just magically
changed my sexual orientation
to the socially acceptable one.
That's super friggin crazy.
Shut up,
you goddamn lesbo.
God,
there's so much pressure
on trans women
to be extremely
gender conforming,
and even more so
if you're a representative
of the community.
You feel like
you have to be
a Stepford wife
or else cis people
are gonna throw us all
in camps.
And early in my transition,
I kind of worshipped
straight trans women.
Like,
I looked up to them
and I wanted to be
just like them.
Now back then,
there were a handful
of trans lesbians
on YouTube
trying to make the case
to the masses
that being a trans lesbian
is a legitimate thing.
But in 2017,
sweaty,
the masses
were not having it.
I watched those women
get eaten alive.
And as a result
of my witnessing that
at a super fucking
vulnerable moment for me,
I internalized the message
that a trans lesbian
is just
not an okay
thing to be
if you want to be tolerated
or respected
by anybody other than
a handful of communists.
So I began my transition
with essentially
no role model
of a widely respected
and admired
trans lesbian.
And it doesn't help
that most forms
of transphobia
are harsher
on gay trans women
than they are
on straight trans women.
Like take this trope
that trans women
are men
who transition
to creep on women
in bathrooms.
In response to that,
it feels really good
to be able to say
I'm not even attracted
to this petite
heterosexual bio girl.
I'm surely not
some kind of
six foot monster
who likes women.
Shame.
It does make me feel
like a monster sometimes,
like a mutant
that has no place
in society.
And this shame
has actually made it
more difficult
for me to accept
that I'm a gay woman
than it was for me
to come out as trans
in the first place.
It's like I made
a kind of subconscious
bargain
where I traded
my sexual orientation
for my gender identity.
So I finally transitioned
only to spend
a different kind
of denial.
And that denial
got pretty deep
and pretty dark.
This is painful
and incriminating
to admit,
but not all of my shame
came from external bigotry.
Some of it came
from my own judgment
and disgust
toward things
I saw trans lesbians
doing.
Like this anime
cat girl shit
which clearly
gets under my skin
and not just because
these people
have been harassing me
for three years.
Like you see it
all over trans Twitter
and Reddit,
this queasy combination
of the hypersexual
and the infantile.
I'm a heckin'
cat girl lesbian
cum slut.
Meow meow,
girl dick,
nya nya.
Here's the 97th picture
of my own legs
and thigh-high
stripey socks uwu.
What is that about?
Is this how women act?
Cis people are gonna
see this.
They're not gonna
let us into women's spaces
if we act like that.
Now I'm not proud
of having these
judgmental feelings,
but I confess
to periodically
sinking into
these morbid
guilty binges
of cringing
at embarrassing
trans lesbians
and if I was
a different type
of YouTuber
I could've turned
this into content.
At my worst
I would sit there
telling another
trans person
why are trans lesbians
so cringey
they're making things
harder for the rest
of us girls.
And that's
the real darkness
isn't it?
Not even having
the decency
to openly
despise yourself
like an honest American.
No,
just sitting there
in absurd denial
of who you are
as a person
disparaging
your own repressed
identity to anyone
I'm ashamed
I sunk that low
but all you can do
is try to get better
and I'm trying
to get better
I've broken free
of the denial
and now I have
to break free
of the shame
because shame
is literally
ruining my life.
I told Joanne
I was working
on a video
about shame
and she said
I might want
to mention
that one of the reasons
she didn't want
to be with me
is she'd be ashamed
to date another
trans woman.
She said she feels
like relationships
are a freakish behavior
on the outskirts
of society
with no attempt
to integrate.
These are very painful
words to hear
from the woman
you're in love with
but I understand
why she feels
that way.
Joanne gets validation
from dating cis men
or cis women
but I
can't be the hinge
that connects her
to mainstream society
and it's maddening
to me that she feels
that way
because I would have
chosen her
over every cis woman
in the world
but I'm just another
worthless freak
without the authority
of my love
doesn't count.
Shame.
It poisons
the soul.
You know who you love
just like what gender
you are
is such a basic
part of your humanity
and shame
about that
cuts to the core
of your being.
It's not
I'm ashamed
of what I did
it's not
I'm ashamed
of how I feel
it's I'm ashamed
of who and what
I am
and living
in that state of mind
is garbage
it's basically
hell.
Even after I realized
my sexuality
shoving that shit
back down
never coming out
I have all these
fears about it
I'm worried
people will take my gender
less seriously
I'm worried
cis women
or straight women
I'm friends with
will get weird about it
I'm worried
I'll die a lonely
useless lesbian
in which case
I should have just
married a man
cause at least then
there'd be someone
to kill the spiders
and fix the fucking sink
I'm worried
I'll lose my straight male
audience on YouTube
although
I mean
love you boys
I'll be fine
without you
and in any case
when has a woman's
being a lesbian
ever stopped a man
from taking a swing at it
I actually thought about
marrying a man anyway
just sacrificing
my sexual orientation
to regain
that safe
comfortable
shameless
feeling
I used to have
when walking down the street
holding Chad's hand
feeling like I'd succeeded
as a woman
but if I don't deal
with this now
and work towards
accepting myself
then I'm just gonna be
in the same situation
in 10 years
when I'm 41 years old
and married to a man
with the same feelings
so it's time for this
to stop
because literally
the only good thing
about being gay
is doing gay shit
and as long as I'm ashamed
of my sexuality
no one's gonna wanna
do gay shit with me
as I like to say
if you can't love yourself
how in the hell
are you gonna prop up
your narcissistic delusions
look I'm trying
to stay positive
maybe everyone hates
trans lesbians now
but just you wait
we all know
how trends work
in 10 years
being a trans lesbian
will be the coolest
hippest
chicest
thing imaginable
and all the people
who love it now
will forget
they ever said a word
that's right
even the straight trans girls
will be making out
with each other
just for the clout
like we can be lesbians
too
we are edgy
oh
it's gonna be
Madonna and Britney
at the 2003 VMAs
all over again
mark my words
and among cis lesbians
oh
it will actually be
a sign of prestige
to have a trap waifu
I can dream right
once you've tasted
one forbidden fruit
why stop there
because they'll be
fine
oh my god
you've got a bomb
nggak
nothing can stop
me
gotta go
you only do
what you gotta do
or else
I'll fall
and if it's
really speed
like where are you
now
then drive
you home
since I'm
dead
sorry
I'll make it
so we're
not friends
yeah
right
sorry
something seems
weird
будем
you sure
Thank you.