Thank you for watching.
I'll see you in the next one.
It's probably the most effective approach eventually,
but the problem is that it's hard
and I don't like things that are hard.
Because when you do things that are hard,
you have to feel bad now so that you can feel good later.
And I don't want to feel good later.
I want to feel good now.
And if you want to feel good now,
well, you have a couple options.
The first is, of course, to do drugs.
And I've tried that.
I spent most of my 20s on the threshold of alcoholism,
but it turns out that's not a cute look for me.
It's not my vibe.
So what I do now when I feel the darkness coming
is what any respectable woman would do.
I take a Xanax and lie on the floor for a couple hours.
Is it a pee under my mattress, your majesty?
Or is it another Xanax I left under the throat rug?
Now, the problem with doing drugs
is that when the drugs wear off, you feel bad again.
In fact, you probably feel worse.
So where do we go from here?
Well, how about music?
When you feel bad, you want to listen to sad music
because sad music makes you cry.
And crying feels good.
It's like an orgasm for sad people.
And why settle for less than the official meme song of sadness?
The Sound of Silence by Simon and Garfunkel.
You know, I'm pretty sure there's another Xanax
under this throat rug.
Hello, darkness, my old friend.
But in the memes, you only hear the first 10 seconds of the song.
You only hear,
Hello, darkness, my old friend.
And that's a very sad first 10 seconds of a song,
which is good,
because if you're making songs for sad people,
it's important to establish your sadness cred up front.
Because sad people don't like happy songs.
When you're sad,
happy songs make you feel like you're being bullshitted.
So we're 10 seconds into the song,
Hello, darkness, my old friend.
The key is D sharp minor, the saddest of all keys.
But when we get to the next line,
because of vision softly creeping,
something happens.
Let's listen.
I've come to talk with you again
Because a vision softly creeping
Ah!
What was that?
Suddenly a major chord,
an unsuspected burst of sunlight through the clouds,
and every peach fuzz hair on the back
of my biologically female neck stands on end.
Hello, light.
So the song has enticed me
with its promise of company for misery,
and then it has tricked me into feeling good.
And that's what I like about art.
It takes the standard disappointments
and humiliations of life
and cooks them into something worth
getting off the floor for.
Unfortunately, I don't really play music much anymore
because my hands are too beautiful for instruments
and my singing voice sounds like a man.
So all I really have left is what any aspiring artist
with no talent turns to, comedy.
And I especially like dark comedy.
You know, comedy about the things in life
that are the most painful.
To me, dark humor is kind of like a sad song.
It takes your worst feelings, traumas, and anxieties
and twists them into a source of pleasure.
And don't all the finest pleasures come from pain?
Ah!
A lot of the time, that means joking about topics
that in ordinary life are considered taboo.
You know, sadness, fascism, sexual deviation, cults.
Without the ability to joke and make fun
of my own experiences of self-loathing,
substance abuse, gender dysphoria,
I mean, I'd probably be the one to say,
I'd probably be on the floor right now
looking for that Xanax.
But this puts me in a difficult situation
because I want to defend my sense of humor,
which I feel is like the core of my personality
and what keeps me alive.
But at the same time, I've noticed that a lot of the people
in our culture who are really big on defending provocative,
controversial, politically incorrect comedy
are kind of dick nuggets.
Let's discuss this.
And by discuss, I mean use it quietly
and I'll tell you what to think.
Two, dick nuggets.
So the year 2016 had just begun
and already the most 2016 possible thing was happening.
Ricky Gervais, an irreverent, bad boy, atheist comedian,
was ranting on Twitter for days and days
about how stupid it is that people are offended by things.
This is pretty standard for Ricky Gervais,
a man whose personal branding screams,
I don't care about your feelings.
I know what it's like to be persecuted for my beliefs.
I am too much of a badass rebel
to care what minorities think.
But in January 2016, Ricky Gervais was having an extra badass,
irreverent, not caring about your feelings kind of month.
Why?
Because he'd just hosted the Golden Globes
and upset a bunch of people by telling jokes
about old Tran Ma Caitlyn Jenner.
But as I say, I'm gonna be nice tonight.
I've changed.
Not as much as Bruce Jenner, obviously.
That's cutting edge material there, Rick.
Very irreverent.
Very rebellious.
Very bad boy atheist.
I mean, I do wish he wouldn't deadname trans people on stage,
but honestly, the joke wasn't even as transphobic
as a lot of the stuff I've come to just expect from comics.
Still, I'm sure Twitter had a thing or two to say about it,
and Ricky spent the rest of the month tweeting
about how offending people is good, actually,
and he definitely doesn't care that people were offended.
But clearly, Twitter got to him,
because two years later, he opened his Netflix special
with a 13-minute bit, rehabbing, and saying,
and doing a series of even more, um, irreverent jokes.
Because I've always identified as a chimp, right?
Well, I am a chimp.
If I say I'm a chimp, I am a chimp.
Pre-op.
But, um, and don't ever deadname me.
Don't ever call me Ricky Gervais again.
From now on, you call me Bobo.
Does he also identify as an attack helicopter?
Does he realize he is doing a meme from 2014 on stage
in a $20 million comedy special?
My issue with this joke is that, you know, I don't know.
My issue with this joke is that, apart from being extremely passé and overdone,
it also doesn't make sense unless you ignorantly believe
that trans women are delusional men.
And even then, it's just not very funny.
But am I offended by the joke?
Well, I think it's ignorant, misinformed, unoriginal, and not very funny.
And as a great comedian named Ricky Gervais once said,
to me, an offensive joke is one that's lame, badly delivered, and not funny enough.
So by that measure, yes, I'd say this.
The fact that I identify as a chimp bit is pretty offensive.
But I'm not bringing this old controversy up because I'm offended.
I'm bringing it up because it's just an arbitrary example of a cycle
it seems like our culture repeats about once a week.
Somebody makes a joke, some people are offended by the joke,
and other people are indignant about the fact that those people are offended.
The cycle usually gets framed as a battle and a culture war
that's supposedly going on between generation snowflake,
easily triggered, humorless PC cucks,
and badass, edgy, nothing-off-limits,
free-speech truth-tellers.
Now if this really is a culture war between two sides,
then I am a double agent,
because I'm a generation snowflake PC cuck who loves dank, edgy memes,
and I've found myself on both sides of this type of conflict many, many times.
So on the one hand, when I see the internet roasting a comedian
for some shitty trans joke,
my inner snowflake wants to watch the bastard burn.
But my inner edge lady knows how it feels to be dragged across Twitter over a joke.
And as someone who basically writes jokes about controversial topics for a living,
I appreciate how difficult it is to maintain the mildly sadomasochistic character of comedy
while also keeping your moral compass from getting too jittery.
So what I want to try to do is step away from the heat of these social media battles
and try to abstract from them some more general philosophical questions.
What is the purpose of comedy?
What is it that makes comedy good or bad?
Does good comedy punch up and speak truth to power?
Does it bring light to some aspect of the human condition?
Is it, as Aristotle said,
the imitation of worse than average men?
Or is it simply anything anyone laughs at for whatever reason?
Well, I don't think there's a single objective answer.
I mean, comedy's pretty subjective.
But we can probably reach some kind of understanding by discussing this, right?
And by we,
again, I do mean me.
The rest of you can keep your goddamn mouths shut.
Straw men.
So, as a trans woman,
up here discussing why I don't think Ricky Gervais' trans jokes are funny,
a lot of haters and losers out there are probably gonna try to straw man me.
Did you just assume the straw person's gender?
Ugh!
Cis people have like two trans jokes and they're both so bad.
Here's the straw person's, assholes.
Straw person one.
You hate free speech
and are trying to silence comedians.
I'm not trying to silence anyone.
Comedians can say whatever they want on stage
and I can say whatever I want about them.
Straw person two.
You just can't take the heat when the joke's on you.
I transitioned on YouTube,
making controversial political content all the while,
and I read the comments.
My hate-taking capacity is among the highest of all time.
Of course, I do not have the internalized self-loathing
that has damaged my psyche irreparably,
but sweetie, who doesn't?
Straw person three.
You think no one should be allowed to joke about trans people.
I invented joking about trans people.
Ever heard of the mouth feel?
I'm that tran.
That's right.
If I die tomorrow,
my legacy will be that I applied wine-tasting terminology to fellatio,
and I accept my destiny.
Look, half my job is telling jokes about trans people.
I live for trans jokes.
I just don't think cis people are very good at telling them,
because they don't know enough about trans people
to know what the funny things are.
And being transgender is honestly the perfect topic for comedy.
Like, you used to live as one gender,
and then you became a different gender.
Every single thing about that is absolutely hilarious.
But humor is in the details.
And Ricky Gervais does not know the details,
because he's clearly never been close to a trans person,
and that's why he's still telling these Tinker Toy 2015 Caitlyn Jenner jokes.
And it's too bad,
because I'm actually starving over here for good trans comedy.
And I mean the real dark stuff, too.
I'm not talking about trans Rachel on the timeline
calling her hormones titty skittles.
No, I like the edgy stuff.
I like being on the edge.
Hi, my name is Natalie Nguyen,
and I enjoy edging.
Now, there is one recent work of trans comedy
that I'd like to share with you,
because when you're doing art criticism,
it helps to have positive as well as negative examples.
And the exemplary work I have in mind
is one not a lot of people are talking about yet,
but which I have no qualms placing in the same company
as the works of Dante or Swift.
I am, of course, referring to
My Sperm Bank Experience by Gigi Gorgias.
If you don't know who Gigi is,
first of all, who even are you?
Do you have no respect for legends?
She's a trans YouTuber,
like the trans YouTuber,
whose classic works such as My Hemorrhoids
and I Had Sex With a Dog
long ago cemented her status as a comedy icon.
But in this critic's opinion,
the crown jewel of Gigi's oeuvre
is without a doubt,
the singular masterpiece My Sperm Bank Experience.
Let's do a close reading.
4. Gigi's Sperm Bank Experience
A great work of literature is never just a text.
It is also what the theorist Jean-Jacques Visage du Poisson
would call a moment within an intertextual dialectic.
Love that.
Let us therefore place My Sperm Bank Experience
within its proper context.
Several months earlier, Gigi had released a video
about how she and her girlfriend
were trying to have a child,
so far without success,
and so they went to see a fertility specialist.
Apparently Gigi was not aware
that taking feminizing hormones can make you sterile,
which, girl, they tell you like seven times
before you start hormones.
Like, how?
We'll move past it.
A few months later,
the notification for My Sperm Bank Experience
shows up on my phone,
because that's right, I clicked the bell,
and immediately I knew I was about to experience
something special.
The thumbnail for this video is so much greater
than anything I've ever conceived of
that honestly it makes me feel like a failure,
both as a YouTuber and as a woman.
The sperm donation cup is labeled with Gigi's signature,
the eyes are dotted with hearts,
and her facial expression.
Ew.
Come.
The video begins with Gigi explaining
that in order to produce a sample for the clinic,
she had to stop taking hormones for three months.
So I hesitantly agreed.
I was like, fine, I will stop all of my hormones,
so, you know, my shit can get juicy again,
and I can get a good little sample up in here.
The sperm bank day arrives,
she goes to the clinic,
and approaches the receptionist.
And I said,
yes, ma'am,
I am here to give sperm
from me
to be frozen
now.
The doctor arrives and leads her to the exam room,
which she describes with the precision
of Mama Flaubert.
I walk into this room,
fluorescent lighting,
the house.
I was like, I can see every pore in my arm,
like, Jesus, what do they want me to do here?
And then the kicker,
this, like, leather couch,
the back is kind of, like, angled,
so I guess, like, you can lean
and really get into it or something.
The doctor offers her lubrication,
pornography if needed,
and a donation cup.
Gigi closes the door and gets to work.
I get in the mood,
I get in the zone,
and I'm killing it, bitch.
I am like, I'm gonna give the best sample ever.
My kid is gonna be a God-sent child.
Before I know it,
the moment has crept up on me and happened,
and it's been so long
that it hits the wall behind me.
And it's at this moment
that glam goddess Gigi Gorgeous
gets up off the leather couch
and attempts to scrape
a prodigious quantity of Gigi jism
off the wall of a fluorescent-lit exam room
in a desperate final bid to become a mother.
And I took the cup,
and I was, like, full-on, like,
scraping it off the wall,
because I was like,
I'm not gonna let any little drop go to waste.
You know, I'm here.
This is, like, my moment.
I'm trying to understand
why this video makes me laugh so much.
It's really the contrast of style and substance.
Like, it wouldn't be funny
if a masculine person told this story.
It's funny because Gigi has this
peak feminine storytelling style
in this Real Housewives diction,
but the story itself is about
blasting a giant load onto a wall
of a room full of leather and pornography.
The dissonance between form and content
is genius in that dissonance
perfectly captures the absurdity
of being transgender
with a comedic incisiveness
that Ricky Gervais could only dream of.
I also really relate to this story
because right before I started Hormones,
I decided to freeze a sample of my own
so I, too, have a sperm bank experience.
And it was exactly like Gigi describes,
down to every detail.
It is not a dignified moment, ladies.
There is just no way to feel like a woman
while you're hastily rubbing one out
in an over-lit room designed for men to ejaculate in.
I feel so fish right now.
For this five minutes in the exam room,
I was a man.
Now, I somehow managed to get most of my sample
into the cup,
but there's a different absurd detail to my story.
The receptionist at the sperm bank
saw on my paperwork that I was depositing
because I was going to start feminizing hormones.
And he asked me if there was a name I preferred he called me.
In retrospect, he was actually really sweet
and really cute.
Not that anything was going to come of that at the time,
since I was pretty everything and rough around the edges.
Be honest, I was all edges.
But he asked me for my preferred name,
and I just blurted out Natalie.
And so this was actually the first time
anyone ever called me by my biological name.
And it went like this.
The receptionist at the sperm bank
turned to me and said,
right this way, Natalie.
Here's a cup for you to bust a nut in.
And that's how it went.
And that's how my life as a woman began.
Now in the end,
Gigi's story is actually pretty tragic.
Her sample wasn't usable.
She wanted to have a child with her own DNA,
but she's been on hormones too long,
and she just can't.
And that revelation at the end of the video
kind of recontextualizes how you see the whole story.
In this ridiculous image of Gigi
scraping ejaculate off the wall,
I now see this primal maternal urge
to produce and protect children.
I see a mother bird whose chicks have fallen
prematurely from the nest.
I see the Virgin Mary cradling her child.
I really, really thought that I was going to have
a good sample and I was going to be able to participate
in having a baby with my DNA,
but it's just not on the cards for me.
And I really wanted to make this video more positive
and funny because there is nothing I can do.
And that's exactly it.
That is the darkness.
The darkness is my name for what I consider
the highest form of comedy,
where you take your own worst feelings,
traumas, and anxieties,
and twist them into a source of pleasure.
The darkness is Richard Pryor
running down the street in flames
because he set himself on fire in a coke-fueled psychosis.
The darkness is Gigi Gorgeous
scraping her own prodigious jism
off the wall of an exam room
in a desperate bid to save her chance at motherhood.
If you can make these low points funny,
then you're gonna be okay.
You're gonna survive.
You're gonna make it through life.
And I need that now more than ever
because trans experience is,
in a lot of ways, pretty dark.
But trans people make it through because
we're good-humored and strong as fuck.
Pretty soon, I'm gonna have to stop hormones
before an operation, and I'm terrified of that.
What's gonna happen to me when I stop hormones?
Am I gonna become a man again?
Because I don't know if I can handle that.
I am thinking about names, though.
Like, maybe Nathan? Or Jaden?
I can see myself as a Jaden.
See, I've gotta have my little jokey jokes,
or I don't think I can make it through this.
Like, when I have bottom surgery,
I am absolutely going to constantly refer to it as
my sex change operation.
Because it makes me laugh. It brings me joy.
Calling it gender confirmation surgery
brings me no joy.
Now, it's important to notice that just because
it doesn't make me laugh doesn't mean
it's a politically correct euphemism.
Gender confirmation is a more accurate term
than sex change, because
you're literally not changing your sex.
That's not what surgery does.
But edgy people have their own kind of political
correctness, where they mistake
edginess for honesty, accuracy,
and directness. But these are very
different things. For example,
George Carlin has a classic bit about euphemisms
that has some great moments,
but also some moments that are
way off-base. For example,
content wording ableist slur.
They say they're going to pre-board those
passengers in need of special assistance.
Cripples!
Simple, honest, direct language!
So look, I understand the aesthetic
preference for simple, honest, direct
language, and the repulsion toward
verbose, bureaucratic jargon. That's why
so much of the rest of this bit is so good.
But the word he just used is literally
a slur, so I wonder if what you're being honest
about is your feelings toward disabled
people. Because the phrase passengers
in need of special assistance is a little wordy,
sure, but in this situation
it's actually more accurate, since it also
includes the elderly, the pregnant, anyone
in need of assistance boarding.
So I call my gender confirmation surgery
getting a sex change, not because it's more
direct and honest, but specifically
because it's inaccurate and outdated.
And that makes me laugh.
Not because I'm a fearless truth teller, but
because I'm a bad person.
And I get to call it my sex change operation,
but cis people don't get to call it
that, because it's my darkness,
not yours. Get your
own darkness. When Ricky Gervais jokes about
trans people, he's being a hack,
because he knows nothing of our darkness.
And when someone tries to joke about something that they're
totally ignorant of, the result is usually
clumsy, awkward, and not very
funny. What I'd really like to see is
if Ricky Gervais took all of that irreverent
bad boy derisiveness and
turned it within. Because
within is where the darkness
lies.
Self-deprecating humor is my personal favorite
because as a lazy, selfish,
preening attention whore
who looks like a slightly more passable Ann Coulter
with the voice of a tropical bird,
there's a lot of material here to work with.
But especially when it comes to the trans jokes,
there is a faction of the
trans community that is not
amused by the buffoonery that goes on
on this channel. I think the objection
to it is best summed up by the comic
artist Diana Gadsby, who in her stand-up special
Nanette, said that when
self-deprecation comes from someone who
exists in the margins,
It's not humility.
It's humiliation.
And to be honest, I felt a little
called out by that.
I put myself down in order to speak.
In order to seek permission
to speak.
And she's not wrong, like that is how this works.
In order to gain an audience as a trans
person, you have to demonstrate
what cis people call self-awareness.
That is, you have to signal
that you see yourself the way
the audience sees you.
Which can mean looking at yourself with a pretty
merciless gaze. And of course I'm
happy to do that, cause I have no
self-respect and laughter is the only way
to numb the pain. But the terrible thing
about being a not normal with an audience
is that you don't just get to be yourself.
Because whether you like it or not,
people will see you as a
representative of the community.
Ugh.
So because of that responsibility, which I never
asked for, I have to balance out
the self-deprecation with a lot
of positive messaging about my people.
And that way, the dark jokes
function as a spoonful of
sugar to help the feminine
penis go down. But even without
the group representation issue,
it definitely is possible to take
self-deprecation too far.
As I've said, I have been diagnosed
with an incurable edginess of
temperament, and I sometimes do feel
suffocated by the safe space rules
of a lot of trans spaces, even though
those spaces are there for good reason
and a lot of people need them. But sometimes
this atmosphere of everything and everyone
is valid all the time, no
uncomfortable questions may be asked,
any self-deprecation is a sign
of traumatic internalized bigotry,
I just need to get out of there for a
while and find a place where I can relax
and be my edgy self.
I need a safe space for my edginess,
where I can just blurt out whatever
stupid question or joke comes to mind
without being afraid that I'm gonna
inflict horrible trauma on everyone around me.
So I call up another
transsexual edgelady, you know,
kiki, accuse each other of being cross-dressers,
and just laugh it all off.
And it's so so cathartic to
do that, but it does have
to be done in moderation, cause
there can come a point where you're picking at
the wound instead of numbing it.
And it mostly has to be done in private,
because in public, you have to worry
about how cis people will interpret
it, and so you have to find a way to
be self-deprecating without a
social responsibility.
Ugh, if there was ever a phrase that
instantly deadens all laughter, it's
social responsibility. But since
it's kind of the central topic of the comedy
culture war, I should probably say
something about it, even though, believe
me, I'd much rather go back to
jabbering about my sex change.
So what is a comedian's
job? What is a comedian supposed to
do? I suppose my ideal comedian
is one who is perfectly able to
balance the tension between shit
posting and snowflakery.
And this is an eternal tension,
and must never be resolved.
It is a tightrope I have devoted my
life to walking. See, if the tension
collapses into pure snowflakery,
you get a moralist who might
say that a comedian's purpose is to
promote justice by punching up,
by speaking truth to power, by
exposing the flaws of bigoted mindsets,
and so on. And these are all very admirable
goals, but they leave out what I
think is the essential purpose of comedy,
which is to be funny.
To surprise, to shock, to make
people laugh. It's kind of like how some
art and media critics only ever evaluate
a work based on whether or not it's socially
progressive, and don't seem to really
think about aesthetic pleasure very
much, which, to me, is the
reason why art exists in the first place.
But then again, I am a hedonistic
bourgeois decadent, and should probably
be sent to the guillotine at once.
Just let me do my makeup first, so that when they hold my head
up, everyone can see my beat, and their wings all
fly to the Bastille. Also, someone please post
the video to my Instagram, cause that's
gonna get a lot of engagement.
So the opposite of the pure snowflake
is the pure shit poster,
who might say that a comedian's purpose is to make
an audience laugh by any means necessary.
But that seems kinda barbaric,
since, like, if a guard at a prison
camp is torturing an inmate, and the other
guards are laughing, does that count
as comedy? Is a war crime funny?
Well, according to the Geneva Convention,
it's hilarious.
The thing is, I don't think many comedians
actually believe in a completely
nihilistic vision of comedy.
I think they sometimes pretend to,
when they're trying to evade criticism.
I mean, take even the edgiest of white guy comics,
and listen to the way they talk about their
heroes, Lenny Bruce or George Carlin.
There's always an element of admiration
for bravery, risk,
subversion, truth-telling. In other words,
there's a concern there for what is virtuous
and what is true, not just
for what makes people laugh. So maybe,
before we can even talk about what's funny,
we have to have a level of shared agreement
about what is true and what is morally right.
My objection to Ricky Gervais'
trans jokes is not just that they're not
funny. I think he's wrong about
trans people, and I think his ignorance
is infectious. I think he's
stirring up bigoted sentiments in his
audience, which has the consequence
of making the world slightly scarier
for people like me. And this is
edginess at its worst. Just a
privileged person with a platform
punching down at a politically besieged group
he understands nothing about. And that's
what happens when the snowflake shitpost tension
collapses into pure shitposting.
It's boring.
And immature. Like when someone says
he wants to watch the world burn.
You only get to watch when you have the privilege
of not being on fire.
It's edgy, but it's not the darkness.
The darkness is finding
a way to laugh about being
on fire. Edginess is always
adolescent. The darkness
is edginess aged by
time and pain. And it's only
at that full maturity that comedy
becomes art. That it becomes
comparable to music.
So, those are my thoughts.
Like, comment, and
subscribe.
The end.
Fine, I'll sing the song.
I wish my brother George was here.
Hello darkness
my old friend.
I've come to talk with you
again.
Because a vision
softly creeping
left its seeds while I was
sleeping.
And the vision
that was
planted in my
brain
still remains
within the sound
of silence.
In restless dreams
I walked alone.
Narrow streets of
cobblestone.
Neath the
halo of a
street lamp.
I turned my collar
to the cold and damp.
When my
eyes were stopped
by the flash of a
neon light.
That split the night
and touched
the sound.
Of silence.
And in the
naked light I
saw
ten thousand people
maybe more.
People talking without
speaking.
People hearing
without listening.
People
writing songs
that
voices never
share.
No one dared
disturb the sound
of
silence.
Stay
gorgeous.