Sar, I'm going to talk about Joro once again, but first, story time.
Chapter 1. Anita
The most famous spigot in American LGBT history is a woman called Anita Bryant. This is her story.
1977 was not a good time to be gay. Is it ever really a good time to be gay?
In 1969, the Stonewall Riots forced gay rights into national consciousness.
The first pride parades were held in the summer of 1970, and in 1973 the American
Psychiatric Association declassified homosexuality as a mental disorder.
But only after gay activists disrupted their conference and shouted,
Gay conversion therapy is torture! We have abnormal urges and we will not be silenced!
Because that's the only way to get anything done in this country,
you have to be super annoying about it.
They give you no choice.
On January 18th, 1977, Dade County, Florida, known for such popular cities as Miami,
approved a law that added the phrase,
Affectional or Sexual Preference to its non-discrimination ordinance,
effectively banning housing and employment discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation.
And it was just then, as things seemed to be getting better,
that Anita Bryant made her little appearance.
Anita Bryant, Miss Oklahoma!
Anita Bryant is a native Oklahoman who once had a career as a pop singer,
beauty queen, and spokeswoman for the Florida Citrus Commission.
Come to the Florida sunshine tree.
My twins love 100% orange juice from Florida any time of day.
Orange juice from Florida! It isn't just for breakfast anymore!
Orange juice with natural vitamin C from the Florida sunshine tree.
She was known for these TV commercials with the tagline,
A day without orange juice.
is like a day without sunshine.
Breakfast without orange juice is like a day without sunshine.
Cute.
When Anita heard her pastor speak about this non-discrimination ordinance,
she felt a divine disturbance in her heart.
How touching.
According to the word of God, it's an abomination to practice homosexuality.
As a mother, she would not stand for this.
So Anita wrote a letter to the county commissioner saying,
As a concerned mother of four children,
I am most definitely against this.
Ordinance Amendment.
I have never condoned nor taught my children discrimination against anyone.
But if this ordinance amendment is allowed to become law,
you will in fact be infringing upon my rights
and discriminating against me as a citizen and a mother
to teach my children God's moral code as stated in the holy scriptures.
Anita, kill your shitty child.
When the amendment passed, Anita created a campaign for its repeal.
The Save Our Children Coalition, which sponsored provocative TV ads,
implying that gay people are degenerates who ruin communities and seduce children.
The campaign has been vicious.
With television commercials, the Save Our Children group is appealing to parental anxieties,
saying gays will flaunt their homosexuality before impressionable children.
The Orange Bowl Parade, Miami's gift to the nation, wholesome entertainment.
But in San Francisco, when they take to the streets,
it's a parade of homosexuals, men hugging other men, cavorting with little boys.
Save Our Children.
Sparked the first organized backlash to gay rights in the United States,
escalating the conflict into a national controversy.
On one side were the gay rights activists,
who argued that non-discrimination was a matter of human rights.
On the opposing side, Anita Bryant argued that the non-discrimination ordinance
would give special privileges to homosexuals.
We all believe in human rights,
but we don't believe in human rights that would corrupt our children
or for individuals to have special privileges.
We all believe in human rights, but we don't believe in human rights that would corrupt our children or for individuals to have special privileges.
That would go against the constitutional rights of normal America.
As long as they don't want to flaunt their homosexuality,
they have equal rights the same as anyone else.
In other words, gay people already have equal rights,
just as long as they stay in the closet and don't do anything gay.
That's very helpful.
Thank you so much, Anita, for standing up for our right to be gay in secret.
As long as they do their job and do not want to come out of the closet and force their homosexuality
on me in the areas of business or in the schools,
they can live their life and we're not going out after their jobs
or trying to get them out of their teaching jobs or housing.
Anita also argued that allowing flaunting homosexuals to teach children
was tantamount to gay recruitment.
Just biologically that God made mothers so that we could reproduce.
Homosexuals cannot reproduce biologically,
but they have to reproduce by recruiting our children.
It's the exact same argument that's being used
today by right-wing politicians who claim that queer people are groomers.
Stop confusing our babies with your groomer gender ideologue.
This wicked book, Me and Earl and the Dying Girl,
sexually indoctrinated with wicked, vile books.
And she believes in traditional marriage between a man and a woman,
and in that book it talked about two moms.
Stay away from the children creep or you will regret it.
People should definitely arm themselves, I agree with that.
The Democrats are the party of pedophiles.
The Democrats are the party of teachers, elementary school teachers,
trying to transition their elementary school-aged children
and convince them they're a different gender.
They're just evil people and they want to groom kids.
They're recruiting.
If you don't know what furries are, it's where school children
dress up as animals, cats or dogs, during the school day.
They meow and they bark.
What a great country we live in.
I love it so much.
Gay people around the country rallied against Anita Bryant and Save Our Children.
There was a national boycott of Florida orange juice,
with many gay bars taking screwdrivers off the menu
and replacing them with an apple juice and vodka cocktail called an Anita Bryant.
Let's make one now.
Forgot my cocktail measure, so I'm just gonna have to eyeball this.
Just a dash of apple juice.
Give it a stir.
Needs a garnish.
Stir.
Stunning.
I mean, it's not as good as a screwdriver, but if I was in the 70s,
I would have thrown back so many of these goddamn things out of pure spite.
There's a story that Troy Perry, the founder of the gay-affirming metropolitan community church,
was on a transcontinental flight, and when the attendant put a glass of orange juice on his tray,
he said,
TAKE THAT AWAY.
I'M A HOMOSEXUAL.
At Gay Pride marches in 1977 and 78, anti-Anita Bryant slogans featured prominently on t-shirts,
signs, and buttons.
Anita Bryant sucks oranges.
A day without lesbians is like a day without sunshine.
True.
And meanwhile, Anita's campaign inspired more anti-gay legislation,
including bans on gay adoption and same-sex marriage, both of which passed in the Florida
Senate, as well as the failed Briggs Initiative in California, which would have forced public
schools to fire gay teachers.
So Anita Bryant was worse than a bigot.
She was an influential bigot.
But she may also have helped to unify and galvanize gay activists,
by providing them with a common enemy.
According to historian Lillian Faderman,
Anita Bryant created fervent activists out of those who'd previously been content
simply to enjoy their newfound freedoms.
Faderman cites Eric Hoffer's observation that a mass movement can get along fine without a god,
but it won't get along at all without a devil.
For gay people all over the country, Anita Bryant became that devil.
I think that she is rallying the community together like I have never seen before.
There's no way I could have done it on my own.
So even though she succeeded in her initial goal to repeal the non-discrimination ordinance,
there is no question that in the long term, Anita Bryant was the loser.
She took a lot of L's.
RIP.
That must be super hard for her.
For the short remainder of her career, gay activists protested her events,
they shut down the tour for her book about how persecuted she was by the militant homosexual,
and they succeeded in turning public opinion against Anita Bryant
to the point that she became virtually unemployable in mainstream entertainment.
It helped that she came across as kind of a judgmental prude,
that even hip straight people didn't want to be associated with.
Our top story tonight, Anita Bryant, former mediocre actress and orange juice promoter,
performed coitus in public yesterday, campaigned to promote heterosexuality.
We don't serve orange juice anymore.
Like she famously told Playboy magazine,
Why do you think the homosexuals are called fruits?
It's because they eat the forbidden fruit of the tree of life.
God referred to men as trees.
And because the homosexuals eat the forbidden fruit, which is male sperm.
Oh my God.
Like the woman is heterosexual cringe.
This is how you lose the culture war.
So let's all squeeze a fruit for Anita, pass a little juice around.
And of course, there was the famous incident where a gay activist
smashed a banana cream pie in Anita's face during a TV appearance.
And went into a place called Norfolk, Virginia, and were met with protest,
and, uh, um, all kinds of problems and, uh, uh, every security agent, security.
No, no, let him stay.
No, let him stay.
Well, at least it's a fruit pie.
Miami-Dade County finally reinstated the non-discrimination ordinance in 1998,
and they added gender identity to its protections in 2014.
In 2021, Anita took another metaphorical pie to the face.
When her granddaughter, Sarah Green, came out as gay,
she was the only one who had the courage to a woman in publicly struggling
with whether to even invite her grandmother to the ceremony.
It's very hard to argue with someone who thinks that, like,
an integral part of your identity is just, uh, an evil delusion.
That it is, Sarah. That it is.
So that's the story of Anita Bryant, as students of LGBT history know it.
But isn't it a bit one-sided?
Wasn't there a lot of toxicity on both sides?
Anita Bryant forces talk of absolute truth and morality.
Gay leaders are equally dogmatic about human rights.
A plague on both the houses.
Isn't it cruel, even, to slur Anita as a bigot and a homophobe?
In fact, isn't it possible that Anita Bryant was the real victim?
Oh no. Oh no!
I can't do this anymore.
I'm eating my pie.
I'm eating my goddamn pie.
Chapter Two.
The Witch Trials of Anita Bryant.
God help us all.
The mainstream media would have us believe that Anita Bryant is a so-called
homophobe, some kind of hateful bigot.
But isn't this just an authoritarian tactic used to silence valid concerns?
Mothers in this country are worried about their children going to school to be taught by perverts.
How can we be so sure that the militant homosexuals weren't the real bigots?
Isn't it possible, though?
Isn't it possible that Anita Bryant was the first victim of cancel culture?
Of, dare I say it, wokeism?
Well, no.
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard in my entire life.
But suppose that you're an idiot.
And suppose that that's the narrative you wanted to promote.
Well, what would be your argument?
I mean, if someone put a gun to my head and forced me to make that argument,
I'd probably say something like this.
Anita Bryant lived a difficult life.
In 1940, she was born into brutal poverty in rural Oklahoma.
Her parents divorced when she was just two years old,
the same year she made her singing debut at the Baptist Church.
Parts of my childhood, I blocked out because it hurts too much.
I guess I was happiest when I was eight years old, and my parents were remarried,
and I was baptized and came to know Christ as my personal savior.
Her father abandoned the family again when she was 12.
It was real painful, and it just about killed my mother.
She was a very submissive wife.
She was too submissive, and it angered me.
She let my dad step up.
All over her because of him.
I think I went through life for a long time hating all men.
Anita described her most intense adolescent memory as a feeling of intense ambition,
a relentless drive to succeed at doing well.
The thing I loved.
But Anita's ambition conflicted with her submissive role as a traditional Christian woman.
In 1960, Anita married Bob Greene,
Miami's top disc jockey, but only after he relentlessly badgered her into it.
This is what heterosexuals do, fellas.
Greene was allegedly a controlling and abusive husband.
Feminist Andrea Dworkin claims,
Greene manipulated Bryant with a cruelty nearly unmatched in modern love stories.
And Anita rationalized the abuse, saying,
Despite our sometimes violent scraps, I love him for it.
But while submitting to her husband
and raising four children, Anita was still able to build the career she'd always wanted.
By the 1970s, she was on the payroll of Big Orange Juice, earning half a million dollars
a year, enough to move her family into a 27-room Spanish mansion on Biscayne Bay.
So Anita Bryant struggled all her life for her success.
Did she really deserve to lose it all just because she took a stand for something she believed in?
Anita Bryant's role as a leader,
in the campaign against homosexuals may be hurting her campaign to sell orange juice are you being
blackballed well it's uh it's it looks that way it's it's worse than that we're being threatened
and uh there's all kinds of harassment even with my job with florida citrus i have been blacklisted
for exercising the right of a mother to defend her children and all children against their being
recruited by homosexuals her entire life had become a series of catastrophes she'd been dropped as
spokesperson by the orange growers she had been dropped as a commentator on the orange bowl parade
she lost a television show contract her bookings dropped drastically
no one has paid as dearly as nita bryant for taking a public stand on something she believed
in i remember lying in the bed in my my mother's house in a fetal position
and wanting to die gay activists in the 1970s didn't exactly limit their tactics to polite
debate in the free marketplace of ideas homosexuals started fighting back the gays formed new groups
and picketed the performers public appearances forcing her to cancel a few gay activists routinely
compared anita to adolf h they created pastiches of her orange juice slogan they blamed her for
hate crimes they burned her in
refugee they disrupted events she was involved in they printed toilet paper with her face on it
some sent anita death threats or they mailed her rotting oranges dead cockroaches human excrement
see this is how you cancelled people before phones instead of posting you would
simply mail actual human through the united states postal service neither snow nor rain nor
heat nor gloom of night anita's husband pleaded to supporters how would you men feel if you opened
a letter and there was a photo of her in the post office of the united states post office of the
united states you can imagine quite a lot i do think it would be fair to say that a lot of the
rhetoric did take on a misogynistic tone lillian faderman recounts that lesbians particularly
lesbian feminists abhorred the sexist terms that were being used to characterize anita bryant
and gay men called her the harassment escalated to the point where anita had to cancel her book tour
due to demonstrations and bribes against anita bryant who had been a victim of sexual abuse in the United States.
bomb threats from gay activists and of course there was the pie
so much for the tolerant matashin society it's kind of a deep cut well something to entertain
the boomer queers gay activists claimed to stand for human rights but what about anita's right to
free speech i wish i had some literal pearls to clutch civil libertarian nat hentoff wrote in his
1992 book free speech for me but not for thee that the orange shoes boycott reminded him of a little
thing called mccarthyism
have you ever considered that being pro-gay is quite similar to being anti-gay and that both
are opinions as anita tells it she and her foot soldiers of god were the victims of sinister gay
carpetbaggers the foot soldiers were housewives and mothers religious and civic leaders in
opposition to a well-organized highly financed and politically militant group of homosexual
activists we were cast as bigots haters discriminators and deniers of basic
human rights and all of this happened because we were sincerely concerned for our children and our
community so anita's version of the story is that she and a handful of well-intentioned christian
mothers were cast as bigots by a highly funded mafia of gay extremists all because they had a
few teensy tiny concerns about the militant homosexual cavorting with little boys cavorting
with little boys is it really fair to call this woman a bigot until the dade county or
the county ordinance anita was a registered democrat and considered herself a liberal
and she never said that she hated gay people or wanted them dead in fact she even said that she
loves homosexuals i love homosexuals if you can believe that i love them enough to tell them the
truth because i know that there is hope for the homosexuals that if they're willing to
turn from sin the same as any individual that that they can be ex-homosexuals the same as there can
be an extra homosexual question is she a bigot no she's not a bigot she's not a homosexual performally
an ex-murderer, an ex-thief, or ex-anybody.
She loves homosexuals because they can change,
just like murderers.
Would a bigot have said that?
Just about McFuckin' had it.
Anita was so kind-hearted,
she even said that she related to the homosexual.
I can relate to the homosexual
because I've had emotional scars in my own life.
I really felt the rejection of my father,
and that is one of the things
that maybe leads someone going into homosexuality.
Look, I don't hate homosexuals, that's the truth,
no matter what they think of my motives.
I've always said I love the sinner, but I hate the sin.
Wow, what an empath.
You know, I actually think it's really noble
how she's able to project all of her own emotional baggage
onto the marginalized group
whose rights she's trying to take away.
Okay, so we've given a fair hearing to both sides,
to many sides, we've considered all the evidence.
Now, let's suppose there's no longer a gun to my head
and ask,
did Anita Bryant really deserve that pie to the face?
Well, yes, obviously.
Look, the point I'm trying to make here
is that it's possible to take genuine virtues
like nuance, empathy, and impartiality,
and to twist them into fucked-up apologia
for horrible, oppressive behavior.
If you play this game long enough,
you can essentially explain away
the entire concept of bigotry
and conclude that, in reality, there are no bigots.
This is the true nature of all of us,
all of us who are human beings.
We're all human beings who have been
understood as people with difficult childhoods
and valid concerns cruelly demonized
by militant activists defaming and silencing them
with such reputation-ruining slurs as homophobe.
Now, because you viewers are smart, media-literate people,
you understand framing, so you already know
that I'm about to compare Anita Bryant
J.K. Rowling is a popular author who used to write whimsical stories about wizard school,
but who now writes books about transvestite serial killers masturbating into stolen panties
because she's lost her goddamn mind.
Lo ho ho, dear readers.
Christ, what a nightmare.
Chapter 3.
The Witch Trials of J.K. Rowling.
Alright kids, it's trans in time.
Last year, I agreed to be a guest on a podcast about J.K. Rowling, hosted by Megan Phelps
Roper, an escapee from the Westboro Baptist Church, the notorious hate group from Topeka,
Kansas most known for protesting the funerals of soldiers with signs that say God hates
f**ks.
God and me both, I'm tired of you people.
J.K.
Illy!
The Westboro Baptist Church is one of the most famous homophobic hate groups in the
world.
I'm like a lifelong fan of these people.
I've watched all the Louis Theroux documentaries, I went to a counter-protest in 2010, I remember
how when I was in high school, the Westboro Baptist Church was like the one thing that
conservatives and liberals could agree on because they hated the troops and the gays.
Essentially the two genders of 2006.
But let's not pretend that the Westboro Baptist Church is all bad.
Okay, when Megan was at Westboro, she used to do these amazing ladies.
She used to do these amazing Lady Gaga parodies about how the gays are going to hell, which
to this day I am a big fan of.
But what did you say you think God loves your brain?
He hates all you do cause you love fornicating.
Fornicating.
It's perfect.
I love it.
Play it at my funeral.
Stop praying, stop praying.
God will not hear you anymore.
You taught the boys and the girls to be proud.
For, for, forever burn.
Go devil's finder.
God will not hear you anymore.
You taught the boys and the girls to be proud.
For, for, forever burn.
Go devil's finder.
You just keep pushing on to the hell where you will forever burn.
Megan left the Westboro Baptist Church in 2012 after a crisis of faith precipitated
by a power struggle within the church.
She wrote about all this in her book Unfollow, which is honestly a pretty interesting account
of deconversion and the circumstances that lead someone to leaving a hate group.
Megan contacted me for her podcast because I had criticized TjK Rowling in a video a
couple years ago.
Now, you might be wondering, why would I think that a person who's been carrying a
God Hates F**ks sign most of her life would be the correct person to lead an international
conversation about the intricacies of LGBT issues?
Because I'm an idiot.
Happy?
Basically, I agreed to the podcast because it's a pretty irresistible pitch.
A former member of the Westboro Baptist Church wants to mediate a conversation between me
and the author of Harry Potter.
Would you say no to that?
Maybe.
If you're smart.
Last month, the podcast was announced in an essay by Megan titled The Witch Trials of
J.K.
Rowling.
Obviously a tendentious framing that posits Joro as the target of an irrational trans
witch hunt.
The essay included a teaser quote from Rowling complaining that she's been profoundly misunderstood,
as well as a photo of an angry trans mob holding a rotten hell roll.
I'm not sure if that's true.
The quote was a rotten hell Rowling sign, juxtaposed with an image of conservative Christians
burning Harry Potter books in the early 2000s.
This did not bode well.
So I disavowed the podcast on Twitter because I didn't want my name lending legitimacy to
some kind of unearned J.K.
Rowling redemption tour.
This caused Megan's mom, Shirley, to quote tweet me, calling me a bigot against God.
I mean, God is one of the most vulnerable minorities.
There's only one of him, and he could really use your help, Shirley.
I said in these tweets that I felt used, which that is how I felt, but ultimately I need
to take full responsibility for my involvement in this.
The thing about being a guest on a documentary like this is you honestly have no idea what
the final product is going to be like, so the decision to participate is always a leap
of faith.
And I can't really say that Megan misled me.
There are red flags from the video.
I don't know.
They were there from the beginning, and I ignored them because I was projecting my
own hopes onto the situation.
You know, it's a compelling story.
I liked the idea that this famous former bigot could talk some sense into a famous current
bigot.
We all love a good redemption arc, and I started my career de-radicalizing the alt-right.
That's something I've moved away from, but there's still part of me that wants to see
the best in people.
And to believe that people can change.
If you just talk to them, and make a good enough argument.
Maybe my wishful thinking was that because Megan left Westboro, that must mean that she
must understand the intricacies of anti-LGBT bigotry, right?
And despite no evidence for this, my hope was that Megan would act as a trans ally,
and could be really effective at confronting Joe Roe about all the trans stuff.
I don't know.
I'm Megan Phelps-Roper, and these are the Witch Trials of JK Rowling.
The Witch Trials of JK Rowling is more than seven hours of apologetics for JKR.
The podcast presents Rowling as a complex, humane, heroic figure with an inspiring feminist
backstory.
Joe Rowling's rise to success is this sort of feminist Cinderella story.
Now cruelly besieged by a vicious mob of transgender activists, all because she, as a woman, had
a few tiny concerns about the transgender rapists.
I had been becoming increasingly concerned about the way in which women were being shut
down.
And I felt had some very valid concerns.
Megan uncritically accepts Rowling's framing of the conflict as feminists versus trans
rights activists, whom Rowling describes as a powerful, insidious, misogynistic movement.
For the first five hours of this podcast, Rowling's critics are presented as an irrational
mob of enraged, shrieking, sexually violent fanatics.
And I think that's what makes this podcast so interesting.
You are murdering trans children!
Trans get up all time!
A huge amount of I want her to choke on my fat trans dick.
And you did it at my birthday dinner!
There's this one clip of some kind of antifa supersoldiers abrasive screaming that they
play like once per episode.
Fuck you, you ugly piece of shit.
You look like you got your teeth knocked out of your fuckin' flashes.
Nobody knows who you are and nobody cares and you will die alive.
I want to fight together.
I support my family.
I want to be a battle partner.
And then it usually cuts to, like, somber monks chanting some kind of medieval lament.
You will die alone and you will burn in hell!
Just in case you didn't get from the title that this is a witch hunt.
Do you guys get it?
Do you get it yet?
Yeah, your teeth knocked out, you fucking fascist!
Let's get up on time!
And then these mobs of irrational, misogynistic, trans rights fanatics are contrasted with
this poignant story of how J.K. Rowling escaped her abusive husband to publish our generation's
most beloved novels.
I was still very committed to those parts that I'd plotted in darkness, as it were,
because there was a truth to them and there was a power to them.
The
only voices of genuine trans dissent appear in episode six out of seven, more than five
hours in.
And there's only two of us.
One is me, shame, and the other is a teenager named Noah, who kind of just seems like he
wants to be liked and understood, and wishes that his favorite author would please stop
saying bigoted things about him.
I'm such a big Harry Potter fan where I was such a big Harry Potter fan.
especially because it was so hard to be in the real world.
I can't even state how important it was to me.
J.K. Rowling, I stole her biography from my third grade classroom
and I kept it for a long time because I just loved reading it
because I just admired her so much.
It's honestly pretty heartbreaking to listen to.
On my last day editing this video, I got in touch with Noah.
I asked him if he had any thoughts about the podcast he wanted me to pass along
and this is what he said.
I want to emphasize that the stakes of this issue are very different
from any sort of rhetorical debate.
Conversation, dialogue, and debate are important,
but for many of the most vulnerable people in society,
the outcome of this conversation dictates their health, well-being,
and ability to survive.
How we treat or talk to people like J.K. Rowling should come second
to fighting for maintained access to health care, support,
and general resources for children and adolescents seeking gender care.
I agree.
The most frustrating thing about this podcast
is that it refuses to be honest about what it is.
They spend seven hours implying that J.K. Rowling is the victim of a witch hunt
in the most heavy-handed way imaginable.
These are the witch trials of J.K. Rowling.
I mean, TERF is basically witch.
But if you point this out, they just deny it.
Show me the actual words, Jack.
Show me where I said I'm the victim of a witch hunt by trans people.
You're on a podcast called The Witch Trials of J.K. Rowling.
Yes, a podcast on which,
I never once say I'm a victim of a witch hunt by trans people.
What are you talking about?
I'm not scamming the government, if that's what you're saying.
Your license plate says scamming.
Uh, no.
What do you mean, no?
Yes.
Joanne.
Show me where I ever said that I'm the target of a witch hunt, you liar.
Why would you even think that?
You're crazy.
By the way, come get your This Witch Doesn't Burn t-shirt for sale now.
At Wild Womine Workshop.
And Megan is not much better.
Like, there's this whole section in episode two where Megan interviews Christians who
burned Harry Potter books in the 1990s, and this is obviously meant to be foreshadowing.
So, looking back, would you say that the Christian parents were maybe part of a moral panic?
Yeah, absolutely.
It's a scary world out there.
Megan doesn't explicitly say she thinks trans protests against Joe Rowe are equivalent to
the Christian ones in the 90s.
But she does heavily imply it.
There was an explosive reaction to Rowling's tweets, which led many, including lifelong
fans of her work, to condemn her and to call for her books to be banned, boycotted, and
in some cases, burned.
When confronted about the obvious implications of the podcast's title, Megan said,
The title is ambiguous.
Toward the end of our conversations, I spent a long time talking with Megan.
She said,
I spent a long time talking with J.K. Rowling about discernment, about how a person can
ever know if they're standing up for what's right, or joining a moral panic.
I think you'll be surprised by the thoughts she shares.
Megan, I was not surprised.
I know I won't ever regret having stood up on this issue.
Ever.
The podcast released new episodes weekly, and whenever Megan was challenged about the
blatant one-sidedness, Megan would respond,
Oh, you just think that because you haven't listened to the podcast?
Maybe you should preserve judgment.
Much more of Other Perspectives is coming, make sure to tune in next week.
Make sure to tune in next week.
More bombshell revelations to come.
Well, I've listened to the whole podcast now, and I truly do not think that anyone with
Google thi basis media comprehension skills could come away from this thinking that the
main intent was anything other than to portray J.K. Rowling as him.
And I truly do not think that anyone with basic media comprehension skills
could come away from this thinking that the main intent was anything other
than to portray J.K. Rowling as the martyr of an unjust, uh, what's the word?
Witch hunt?
This is the obvious implication of the podcast from the first words to the very last.
And of course, Rowling does literally get the last word.
The final episode concludes with this.
There are more important things in this world than being popular.
And that doesn't mean it's more important to me to be right.
It means it's more important to me to do the right thing.
Why would you end on that note?
Why would anything about this podcast be the way it is
if Megan didn't fundamentally believe that J.K. Rowling isn't the right?
I don't regret it because I did the right thing.
Like there really is no other reasonable way
to interpret this.
So I wish that she would just be honest.
If you believe that J.K. Rowling is the misunderstood victim of a witch hunt,
then just say that.
Make the argument you want to make.
Don't crouch and hide behind this disavowal,
this obfuscating veil of just asking questions.
Don't rely on innuendo and framing and
lachrymose Gregorian chanting to make your point.
Well,
don't go around coyly denying you have any kind of agenda beyond.
I just believe in conversation.
I don't know.
I just find this a slippery and dishonest way to argue.
But if you happen to be a fan of slippery and dishonest arguments,
you're in luck because there is more where that came from.
This video is sponsored by Cannabox.
Cannabox offers fresh human meat
delivered directly to your doorstep.
As an alphabet mafiosa, sometimes I just can't fit the most dangerous game into my busy lifestyle
of destroying the family and recruiting children.
Whenever a new box arrives, I get out my copy of Bless This Food, the Anita Bryant family
cookbook.
The best thing about human meat delivered to your home by mail in the dead of night?
You don't know who you're eating, so it's totally guilt-free and ethically sourced.
Maybe.
There's no ethical consumption under capitalism.
Listen, that means you're not allowed to cancel me.
Chapter four, Joe Rowe's transphobia.
That's it.
I'm going full Slytherin.
In episode five of The Witch Trials of J.K. Rowling, Joe Rowe compares trans activists
to Death Eaters, the fictionalized fascists in Harry Potter.
My position is that this activist movement, in the form that it's currently taking, echoes
the very thing that I was doing.
I was warning against in Harry Potter.
The Death Eaters claimed we have been made to live in secret, and now is our time.
I am fighting what I see as a powerful, insidious, misogynistic movement.
When an article then claimed she had equated trans people to Death Eaters, the podcast's
PR firm reached out, demanding a correction.
Because she only equated the movement to Death Eaters, not trans people in general.
Yeah, I don't hate marginalized people.
I just hate it.
I hate it when they advocate for themselves.
So I do have to be very careful with my wording here, lest a defamation letter arrive by owl.
J.K. Rowling's bigotry is exhausting to argue with, because she expresses it as an endless
series of what are called Mott and Bailey arguments.
A Mott and Bailey argument is named after a type of castle consisting of a Mott, that
is, a tower atop a mound or hill, easy to defend, and a Bailey, a fenced courtyard that's
much more vulnerable to attack, difficult to defend.
The Mott and Bailey argument is when someone makes a provocative claim that's difficult
to defend.
The Bailey.
And then, when confronted with counter-arguments, they walk it back to a much less controversial
and easy-to-defend version of the claim.
The Mott.
For example, Rowling will make an ambiguous claim like, sex is real.
What does she mean by that?
What are the implications?
Well, in the podcast, she explains that she thinks it's very sinister that in the Associated
Press style guide, it says that instead of referring to a trans woman as a man who identifies
as a woman, journalists should simply say a trans woman is a woman.
That, from the Associated Press, is hugely powerful.
They've edged from identifies as a woman, so a man identifies as a woman, which, and
I think we all understand what that means, into is a woman.
And that's precisely the creep that I'm talking about.
We are using language to...
To make accurate definition of sex difference unspeakable.
Which is of course false, because the words trans and cis exist precisely to make it easy
to talk about sex difference.
Thanks a lot, Tumblr.
God, there's this whole section of the podcast that sort of implies that transgender people
were invented on Tumblr, which I'm not even gonna get into because we don't have time.
Rowling has also tweeted that she thinks that all people who menstruate must be referred
to as women.
Or was it wombin?
I'm pretty sure it was wompmud.
So trans men and transmasculine people, they're all women and must be referred to as women.
Because J.K. Rowling demands it.
This is controversial, right?
Calling trans women men who identify as women.
Calling trans men women.
This is the Bailey in her Mott and Bailey argument.
Trans women are men.
Trans men are women.
That's the controversial interpretation of sex is real.
Now, when accused of transphobia and facing backlash...
Rowling walks the argument back and says,
I'm being persecuted just for saying that women should be allowed to discuss how being
female has shaped our lives.
Women should be allowed to discuss how being female has shaped our lives.
This is the obvious and utterly uncontroversial interpretation of sex is real.
The Mott.
And virtually every argument sophisticated transphobes make about trans people follows
this pattern.
J.K. Rowling's friend and ally, Maya Forstadter, said,
I'm being persecuted just for saying that women should be allowed to discuss how being
female has shaped our lives.
J.K. Rowling's friend and ally, Maya Forstadter, will tweet inflammatory things like,
Men cannot change into women.
But then when she's criticised, she'll say that she's being attacked for gender-critical
belief.
Gender-critical belief, which is absolutely ordinary belief about sex that your mother
and your grandmother are women.
That being female is a thing.
Your mother and grandmother are women.
Being female is a thing.
That's literally all I'm saying.
But if that's literally all she was saying...
then no one would be mad, would they?
Nine, gnar.
Men cannot change into women, is the Bailey.
Your mom is a woman, is the Mott.
Your mom's a woman.
This is why arguing with these people is infuriating.
They'll insinuate that trans women are dangerous rapists,
exhibitionists, and voyeurs.
Then when trans people understandably get mad,
they'll say, look, I'm being attacked
just for saying that being female is part of my experience.
It's dishonest.
They talk a bunch of trash about trans people,
and then when trans people talk trash back,
they pretend that they're being victimized
for making totally innocuous statements.
We could name this behavior the birthday boy argument.
I dated a 5'8 guy who'd taunt
every jacked 6'3 bro he met
until they'd pull their fist back to beat him up,
whereupon my ex would go, hey, hey, hey, come on.
I'm a little guy.
I'm just a little guy.
No, it's also my birthday.
I'm a little birthday boy.
And somehow, it always happens.
It always worked.
So a birthday boy argument
is when you make aggressive, inflammatory assertions,
followed by, teacher, teacher, look what he's doing to me,
when the target reacts
with anything less than extreme politeness.
Another common tactic you'll see
any time Rowling's transphobia is discussed
is you'll see someone jump in to say,
show me one thing she's said that's transphobic.
For example, here's someone on Twitter
called Large Gamete Producer.
It's funny, isn't it, how these people will insist
that awkward, inclusive language like people who menstruate
is horribly oppressive and degrading,
but then they'll just straight up call themselves
Large Gamete Producer,
which, by the way, is Rowling's definition of a woman.
The woman is the producer of the large gametes.
Oh, I like it.
It's very broodmother.
That Rowling's words regularly appear
in gender-critical arguments shows the massive influence
that she has in the anti-trans movement.
She's like their queen, their leader, their headmistress.
She's the best thing that ever happened to them.
Because Sheila Jeffries certainly wasn't persuading
a lot of people.
If you know, you know.
Large Gamete Producer says,
GK isn't anti-trans.
Give me just one direct quote that she has said
which is anti-trans.
Oh, what's that?
You can't find one?
Well, color me shocked.
Imagine.
Before we waste our time trying to provide examples,
let's take a look at Large Gamete Producer's profile.
Trans women are not women, they are men.
Trans men are not men, they are women.
Nothing can change that.
Sex is binary.
Like if this person doesn't think that trans women are men,
trans men are women is a transphobic statement,
then what would they consider a transphobic statement?
This is why the first question you should always ask
such people is, do you believe that transphobia
is a legitimate concept?
What are some examples of statements
that you would consider transphobic?
Because many of them don't believe that transphobia
is a valid concept.
Because they don't think that trans people
are a legitimate minority.
There's no such thing as a trans woman.
There's no such thing as a trans person.
There is no such thing.
There are people that call themselves these things
that may have other issues manifesting
that then make them think they're this, but no.
We have to stop using any words like transgender.
There may be more words that we have to say
in order to say that.
We may call it transgender ideology,
but when it comes to a person,
they may be following transgender ideology,
but they are not transgender.
There is no such thing as a man or a woman
being anything other than a man or a woman.
So when they say, show me an example
of something transphobic JK Rowling has said,
this is a trap.
They're just messing with you.
There's nothing that she could have said
that they would acknowledge as transphobic.
Now, if you're someone who believes that transphobia
is a valid concept,
and you believe that trans people are a legitimate minority,
but you just genuinely are unaware
of what JK Rowling has said on the topic,
then I will refer you to my past video on JK Rowling,
rather than recapping it all here.
Just keep in mind that she's gotten significantly worse
since I made that video.
I mean, just look at her Twitter feed.
True, she never says the phrase, I hate trans people,
because she's not a complete idiot,
but Anita Bryant never said, I hate gay people.
She said, save our children.
I love homosexuals.
For that matter, I'm pretty sure David Duke
doesn't say, I hate black people,
but he will share a lot of statistics
about anti-white crime.
So this is not really,
a very good criterion for deciding who's a bigot, is it?
What JK Rowling does do is tweet again and again
about transgender rapists,
about the danger trans women pose to cis women.
She implies that trans-inclusive language
is equivalent to the dystopia of Orwell's 1984.
She writes at length about the vague nefarious cabal
of endocrinologists and ideologue
that is supposedly persuading
confused vulnerable girls to transition.
To quote Washington Post opinion,
writer Monica Hess,
I do not know what is in Rowling's heart,
but reading her Twitter feed,
this is the overall effect.
Her Twitter feed does not ask its readers to think.
It asks them to fear.
It creates phobias of trans people.
It creates trans-phobias, if you will.
Rowling has also attacked pro-trans politician,
Nicola Sturgeon, calling her a destroyer of women's rights
via a t-shirt.
This is what she got from anti-trans hate-monger Posey Parker.
There's no such thing as a trans woman.
There's no such thing as a trans person.
There is no such thing.
If there's one thing that I want people to understand
about Rowling's transphobia,
it's that this is not a case of someone posting
a couple insensitive tweets
that got blown out of proportion.
Rowling is an extremely outspoken opponent of trans rights.
This has been her main issue for several years now.
And because she's so famous,
she's become the de facto global champion,
of trans women.
A champion of backlash to trans rights.
Truly, the Anita Bryant of transphobia.
Except worse, because she's way more famous
and way more liked than Anita Bryant ever was.
Rowling has also praised self-described theocratic fascist,
Matt Walsh, for his transphobic propaganda film.
She refers to trans women as trans-identified males,
known as Tims, among people for whom this has become
an unhealthy obsession.
She retweets images of the trans colors
being erased from the progress flag.
Also, the colors representing queer people of color.
So, you know, great.
Love that.
Often, Rowling pretends that she's being transphobic
for the principled and valiant purpose of defending lesbians.
It's something of a fixation for her.
I find this particularly gross,
because it plays into the lesbophobic trope
that gay women are especially anti-trans,
when in fact, they're the least transphobic demographic
of cis people.
According to a survey of young adults in the UK,
lesbians were most likely to know a trans person,
and also most likely, at 96%,
to say that they're supportive,
or very supportive of trans people.
So I think it's fair to say that most gay women
are probably not super thrilled
whenever Joe Rowe, the lesbian defender, logs on.
My own partner is a cis lesbian,
and I asked her if she enjoys JK Rowling
defending her from the transsexuals, and she said,
It makes me want to gouge out my eyes like Oedipus.
By the way, here is JK Rowling enjoying a bit
of banter with her friend Baroness Emma Nicholson,
the co-founder of Rowling's charity, Lumos.
Baroness Nicholson is a conservative member
of the House of Lords who voted against
same-sex marriage in 2013.
In 2020, she tweeted in defense of her vote,
claiming that gay marriage would lead to
degrading the status of women and girls.
Truly one of the great lesbian allies.
And in 2022, here is JK Rowling
joking around with Lady Nicholson.
Excellent question.
Emma.
Defining lesbians as same-sex attracted women
excludes and depresses the most marginalized of all groups,
i.e. people with penises and beards who want to shag women.
And before you say, but aren't they straight men?
They're wearing eyeliner, bigot.
Try for a moment to put aside any nostalgia you may have
for the Gryffindor common room,
and just look at this interaction for what it is.
Two straight women, one of whom is a homophobic peer
of the realm, having a nice little chuckle together
about how trans women are men wearing eyeliner.
So that's it, right?
It's over.
Case closed.
I still like hammering things.
I'm not gonna argue anymore about whether JK Rowling
is transphobic, because anyone who believes in transphobia
can see that obviously she is.
The question now is whether transphobia is the sort of
thing that progressives can denounce,
the way we at least aspire to denounce racism,
misogyny, and homophobia.
That's usually what we're talking about
when we talk about JK Rowling, right?
Whether it's fair to cancel her.
That's what the witch trials of JK Rowling is about.
The Rowling debate is a proxy for a larger question.
Is transphobia a legitimate viewpoint
worthy of polite consideration and respect
in liberal, humane society?
Or, is it just an option?
Or is it just an ugly prejudice
that we can justifiably react to
with scorn and condemnation?
And there's an even broader question here
about whether we can justifiably react to anything
with scorn and condemnation.
Is canceling ever warranted?
Is it right to condemn racism, homophobia, and misogyny?
Or should we allow spokespeople for these prejudices
a respected position in the free marketplace of ideas
where we can all sit around debating the legitimacy
of gay marriage or the possible merits of a white ethnostate?
Is the final solution a myth promulgated
by the international Jew?
Are yoga pants to blame for sexual violence?
Wouldn't the taxpayers save a lot of money
if there weren't so many disabled people?
Who knows?
These are open questions.
Let's sit down with people on both sides, on many sides,
and have calm, civil conversations about it
for the rest of our goddamn lives.
Five, debate.
Sar, I know I did this look before
and it's like not related to the video topic at all,
but it just makes me feel slithing.
The boy who slithed.
So Megan Phelps-Roberts' viewpoint seems to be
that scorn and condemnation are never appropriate,
that we should approach every conflict
with empathy and compassion,
even when dealing with the worst,
most destructive people in the world.
Hi, my name is Megan,
and my heretical friend, Megan Phelps, is a gay man.
My heretical belief is that even the people
who seem to be the worst,
most destructive people in the world
are human beings who deserve compassion and empathy
if we want to find a way to change their minds.
In her book, in her TED Talk,
in her public appearances,
Megan expresses the idea
that society has recently become polarized
in some unprecedented way,
that we've all become extremists,
that in some sense, we've all become
the Westboro Baptist Church.
I can't help but see in our public discourse
so many of the same destructive impulses
that ruled my former church.
She identifies things like certainty,
vilification of compromise,
us versus them thinking,
suppression of empathy,
and celebration of death and misfortune
as Westboro-like elements in public discourse.
And this really bothers Megan,
because she claims that a decade ago,
when she went on Twitter to tweet about
how marriage is abominable to God,
it was people who engaged her in a civil,
rational way that eventually led her
to renouncing Westboro's ideology.
And like, I don't entirely disagree with Megan about this.
She's totally right that if you want
to change people's minds,
then approaching them with compassion and empathy
is usually the best way to do that.
But Megan reaches another conclusion
that I don't agree with,
which is that because compassion and civil conversation
are most likely to persuade people,
we should never cancel anyone,
even the most horrible bigots.
And canceling is a pretty meaningless term at this point.
But what Megan means is we shouldn't say mean things
to bigots.
We shouldn't boycott or counter-protest
or raise our voices.
We shouldn't shun or exclude anyone,
because that's just not how you change minds.
And I get why Megan thinks this, right?
De-radicalization was a really important part
of her life experience.
She's also clearly holding out
hope that other members of her family
will leave Westboro and have a life on the outside.
She has a quote from her mom in her Twitter bio.
The last lines of her book address her family.
"'I want to tell them that I love them.
I'll just have to find another way.'"
This is touching and human
and also kind of a conflict of interest.
The problem is Megan's views about this only makes sense
if you assume that Megan is the main character of reality.
If you assume that the moral improvement of bigots
is more important than protecting the people they target.
Or if you assume that changing bigots' minds
is the only way to make social progress, which it isn't.
As far as I know, Anita Bryant is 83 years old
and she's still homophobic.
But even without Anita's blessing,
gay rights have still somehow managed to progress
since the 1970s.
Because gay activists didn't need to persuade Anita Bryant.
They needed to defeat her.
And that's what they did.
We have to accept that realistically,
persuading all the bigots is just not an option.
Yes, we should convince as many people as possible,
but there will always be bigots.
And mocking them, shaming them, or boycotting them
is, I think, a perfectly valid strategy.
Does that mean that when we cancel bigots,
we're acting kind of like the Westboro Baptist Church?
Gnar.
You would only think that if you're a total moral relativist.
I guess controversial opinions are the only way to do that.
It's not a controversial opinion, but bigotry is shameful.
And it should be shamed.
I'll say it.
You know, if you're testing out some racist ideas in your head,
you might feel afraid to express them publicly
for fear of being shamed or judged.
Is that because we live in an Orwellian dystopia
that punishes people for wrong-think?
No, it's because racism is dangerous and shameful
and you should be ashamed of it
and the people judging you are right to do so.
And sure, there are some very, very, very, very,
very patient people who devote their lives
to de-radicalizing bigots,
which I think is a perfectly noble thing to do.
There's a guy named Daryl Davis
who's befriended members of the Ku Klux Klan
for over 30 years,
and he claims he's convinced more than 200 of them to leave.
And good for him.
De-radicalization is a valid strategy,
but it cannot be the only strategy
and it must not be the primary strategy.
Because we're not going to defeat racism
by telling black people to be a little nicer to racists.
Feminists would be wasting their time
trying to convince Andrew Tate to respect women.
In general, I think that the massive effort
that it takes to maybe persuade bigots
is better spent persuading other people
not to listen to them.
And it's also worth cautioning that de-radicalization
is often a messy and incomplete process.
20-year-old white nationalist Peter Sejtanovic
became the face of the fascist Unite the Right,
the right rally in 2017
when a photo of him mid-scream, tiki torch in hand,
was published in news outlets all over the country.
Peter was unrepentant in interviews
he gave immediately after the rally,
but he began to question his beliefs
after befriending a Muslim woman who,
according to Charlotte MacDonald Gibson,
challenged his views without insulting him,
allowing him to understand the hurt he had caused.
Peter is no longer a white nationalist,
but that doesn't mean he's fleshed out
every trace of bigotry.
In a 2019 interview with the London School of Economics
student paper, Peter said,
I don't like the whole transgender thing.
You're born either a man or a woman.
So he maybe still has a little bit of work to do.
When I did de-radicalization work on YouTube,
I used to get some criticism from people of color
who were not thrilled that I was bringing
a bunch of semi-reformed racists over to the left,
a frustration that I don't like, but I do like.
I don't like that. I don't like that. I don't like that. I don't like that. I don't like that.
I don't like that. I don't like that. I don't like that. I don't like that.
To paraphrase YouTuber Ian Danskin,
diverse leftist communities are maybe not the best holding space
for someone who's
a bit of a Nazi but working on it.
In the case of Megan Phelps Roper,
I don't know if she has lingering bigoted sentiments,
but what she does have is a kind of hypervigilant skepticism
about anything she perceives as ideology.
This is pretty common with people
who used to be religious fundamentalists.
They were so certain they were right,
only to realize that everything they believed
about the world is wrong.
So they become distrustful of any strong moral convictions
because it reminds them of their former fanaticism.
Coming from Westboro,
where I believed so strongly that I was doing the right thing
and then to leave and come to believe
that it was so destructive and harmful,
I had this moment in time and it lasted for many months
where I was like,
how can I ever trust my own mind again?
This kind of skepticism is in some ways a good impulse,
but valuing dispassionate intellectualism above all else
can cause problems,
especially where topics of social justice are concerned.
Because it can lead you to this kind of toxic centrism
that asks,
why are marginalized people so unwilling to have calm,
philosophical debates about whether they should have rights?
Are they afraid of dangerous ideas?
Atheist philosopher Sam Harris,
in his podcast about Megan's podcast,
can we talk about how there are too many podcasts?
I'm calling for a complete and total shutdown of podcasts
until we can figure out what's going on.
Sam Harris, in his podcast about Megan's podcast,
complained that trans activism and activism in general
is plagued by mental illness and hysteria.
I frankly think there's a fair degree of mental instability.
and even frank mental illness in the activist community.
I mean, in really in all activist communities.
The level of viciousness and hysteria is,
you know, it's hard to know what to compare it to.
Diversity when...
Man accuses trans women of being hysterical.
Is it really hysteria to react with strong emotions
when your basic inclusion in society is up for debate?
Aren't there certain situations
where strong emotions are warranted?
It reminds me of this awful episode
of Joe Rogan feat Ben Shapiro,
where little Benny argues that gay marriage is immoral
with his usual whining sophistry.
And Joe gently raises objections
for Ben to talk circles around.
The human sex drive was made to procreate
within a stable relationship
in order to progenerate
and have future generations of people.
Misuse of that sex drive in any way,
whether you're talking about from masturbation
to homosexual activity,
is therefore a diminishment of the use of that drive.
That's the natural law case against homosexual activity.
All of the top comments on this video are like this.
Imagine talking about different beliefs
while still having a productive conversation.
Things progress when you don't demonize people.
The discussion here was excellent.
Two guys with opposing opinions,
speaking calmly and intellectually without cursing,
shouting and making disparaging comments about each other.
This is how it should be done.
Kudos to both of them.
Joe is a great interviewer.
He can totally disagree with someone
and still have a calm, collective conversation.
This is how it should be.
Just two people sharing ideas,
learning different point of views from each other.
This is why Joe is the number one podcast.
Joe Rogan beautifully asked the tough questions.
And Ben answers honestly.
He is strong in his faith.
I love this debate because it's two so contrasting views
and they have a civil conversation.
Great learning.
And like, yeah, it's easy for two straight men
to have a dispassionate theoretical conversation
about the ethics of homosexuality.
Because it's not their lives
and their relationships that are up for debate.
These people don't understand the emotional burden
placed on marginalized people
who are asked to defend their rights.
Like, if you're straight,
do you want to publicly debate
whether your marriage is valid?
Andrew Dworkin claimed that
penetrative heterosexual intercourse
is inherently an act of violence.
I've noticed that most straight men
don't want to have a calm, civil conversation about that.
So if you're straight,
imagine how they'd react
if there was a powerful political movement
to criminalize penetration
or revoke their right to marry.
Add in a lifetime of ostracism,
family rejection,
bullying, and discrimination,
and maybe then you'll begin to understand
the hysteria of a lot of queer people.
It is my right to raise my child
with the moral precept
that I find to be beneficial for my child.
Beto O'Rourke does not get to raise my child.
And if he tries,
I will meet him at the door with a gun.
That is insane.
Wow, Ben Shapiro threatening violence
because he can't handle the debate.
Sounds like a classic case of hysteria to me.
Why can't Ben Shapiro just have a polite conversation
about Beto O'Rourke transing his children?
I now have two choices.
One is to leave the country utterly.
Two is to pick up a gun.
Those are the only choices that you have left me.
Dave Rubin is a gay conservative
whose career requires that he convince
his right-wing audience that he's one of the good ones.
This means that he's not the only one
who's willing to sit across
from his so-called friend,
homophobe Ben Shapiro,
and listen to Ben say
he would never attend his anniversary party
because it would be tantamount to endorsing sin.
There's a difference between me
just being friends with Dave
and me actively participating in an event
that I feel is religiously sinful.
The two of them then congratulate themselves
about how they can still be great friends.
Why is it that we're able to do this?
And most people can't do this.
That's what I'm curious about.
We go home at night and we can have our own lives.
And here's Dave having a civil conversation
with conservative Glenn Beck,
who compares homosexuality to alcoholism
and then congratulates himself
on having the conversation.
I'm a deeply religious man
and my religion says
man and a woman,
that is the basic building block of family.
And that's what I believe,
but I also am,
and I also know God created you
just like he created me,
flaws and all.
You know, I believe I have a gene,
they've never found it,
that makes me very susceptible to alcoholism
because it runs in my family.
So does craziness,
but it runs in my family.
Well, Dave smiles and nods,
probably because he's thinking about
how much he enjoys the taste of boots.
Usually I just take out a picture
of me and DeSantis and then we're good
because they get it, they get it,
that's my governor, yeah.
I think a lot of straight people look at Dave Rubin
and they see, finally,
a reasonable gay person
who doesn't scream,
beg it, at everyone who disagrees
and can actually have a civil conversation.
But that's not what I see.
I look at Dave Rubin
and I see a sabineless,
boot-licking doormat
who won't even defend his own family.
from the most fundamental disrespect.
I also can't help but notice
that none of these civil conversations
seem to change anyone's mind.
Persuasion is more complicated
and less rational than people think.
Megan often says that she was de-radicalized on Twitter,
but if you read her book carefully,
you'll notice that that's not exactly true.
The major precipitating event
for Megan's crisis of faith
was her mother's mistreatment
at the hands of an increasingly misogynistic
church leadership
that made Megan feel like she was the victim
of the church for once.
She says of the church discipline,
For the first time in my life,
the accused were people I lived with
and knew most intimately,
and I knew that the judgments
leveled by the elders were wrong.
I could no longer blindly trust
the judgment of these men.
So she finally experienced firsthand
what it's like to be the victim of her family.
She stopped voting for the leopards-eating,
people's faces party
only when the leopards ate her face.
It also seems relevant to notice
that the people who had calm, civil conversations
with Megan on Twitter were generally not gay people,
the people most affected by her family's violent rhetoric.
They were mostly straight men,
like director Kevin Smith,
who started hashtag SaveMegan
because, quote, she's hot.
There's often an erotic component to persuasion,
and that certainly seems to be the case with Megan
because one of the people who helped de-radicalize her
is now her husband.
And I feel like that's a relevant detail
if we're trying to understand the role of reason and emotion
in de-radicalization experiences.
I think this experience is usually more
akin to religious conversion
than it is to logical reasoning.
There's also a world of difference
between the mostly private conversations
that actually lead people to reflect on their beliefs,
and the spectacle of public debate.
Ben Shapiro is never going to become less homophobic
because he livestreamed a civil conversation with Dave Rubin.
So who is this conversation even for?
Well, obviously, it's for the audience.
I think these civil conversations basically function
to reassure a homophobic audience
that just because they disagree with the lifestyle
doesn't mean that they hate gay people.
Look at Ben Shapiro.
He is friends with a gay.
Public debate is one way that we define the limits
of the Overton window,
the range of beliefs that are socially acceptable to hold.
So often people who want to promote bigotry
will use debate as a foot in the door.
It's a way of establishing that their prejudices
are within the realm of reasonable
and socially accepted opinion.
Here's obsessive anti-trans bigot Graham Linehan
in a fury that a drag queen,
that a drag queen is on Doctor Who
without the British public having a proper debate
about these issues.
Now, why do we need to have a proper debate
about whether drag queens should be allowed on television
when drag performance has been a staple
of British entertainment
since at least the time of Shakespeare?
Life is a joke, that's just begun.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, high five.
Three little maids from school.
Fishy, fishy, fishy, fish.
As I am man,
my state is desperate for my master's love.
As I am woman, now alas the day.
Bigots like Graham want a perpetual debate
on their own terms
because this is how they dignify their pearl clutching.
It's how they convince the public
that their moral panic about drag queens on TV
is actually a valid concern.
Rather than the tedious,
small-minded whining about nothing that it really is.
Having the debate on a bigot's terms
is not a good way to win people over
unless you're really skilled
in the art of humiliating people,
which most of the time is what public debate
is actually about.
This is something that J.K. Rowling
doesn't seem to understand.
In the witch trials of J.K. Rowling,
Joro takes a contradictory stance on deplatforming.
She brings up right-wing provocateur,
Milo Yiannopoulos,
saying that activists are making a strategic error
and giving Milo power by protesting his events,
making him look dangerous and sexy.
But when trans people try to deplatform TERFs,
Rowling characterizes this as silencing.
So is deplatforming a strategic error
that gives power to your opponent,
or is it a powerful tactic of silencing?
I find Rowling's conviction
that we ought to debate Milo Yiannopoulos
really out of touch.
Milo Yiannopoulos doesn't have reasons
for the things he does.
He has strategies for humiliating people.
I've taken some time out of my busy schedule,
being fabulous and doing my hair,
to prepare a speech for you.
Well, a few remarks, really.
Feminism is cancer.
Thank you very much.
To again quote Ian Danskin,
you can't really reason with someone
who thinks that feminism is cancer,
because you don't reason with cancer.
You eradicate it.
Rowling objects to the slogan,
no debate, in the strongest possible terms.
And then we come to the famous two-word slogan,
the stock phrase, no debate, no debate, no debate.
We hear it all the time.
That alarms me, really alarms me.
I can't think of a purer instance of authoritarianism
than no debate.
It's kind of amazing to me
that someone could think angry trans people on Twitter
are the purest example of authoritarianism.
I truly hope that one day,
I am privileged enough to be capable of such a perspective.
Before I move on, I do want to clarify
that I do think there are trans issues
that are legitimately debatable by people who are not bigots.
In my opinion, trans women and women's sports
is one of those issues.
But it's a complicated issue.
Like, first of all, which sport are we talking about?
Are we talking about figure skating?
Middle school field hockey?
I see no reason why trans women and women's sports,
I see no reason why trans girls should be excluded from that.
But if we're talking about professional weightlifting,
well, then it seems plausible that trans women
who have been through male puberty
may still retain some kind of group advantage.
But not all trans women have experienced male puberty.
People are transitioning younger now,
and that's another thing you have to consider.
So I'm not against debating this issue.
I just want people to approach it with nuance and good faith.
And currently, I'm not against it.
A lot of the people who are vocally against
trans women and women's sports sound like this.
And we will keep men out of women's sports.
Right?
How ridiculous.
That will take place on day one.
And I don't want to debate those people.
I want to serve them a banana creme pie.
Chapter 6. Illiberal Methods.
One of J.K. Rowling's core complaints about men being too aggressive is that,
the trans rights movement is she sees it as illiberal in its methods so when i first became
interested and then deeply troubled by what i saw as a cultural movement that was illiberal
in its methods so what are these illiberal methods if you are saying this person is
cancelled that is the language of a dictator it's true cancel culture is exactly how the third reich
started first they cancelled the socialists and i did not speak out because the hashtag was trending
but maybe we should see what an actual dictator thinks
you know i can't help but wonder what counts as acceptable activist methods
to an author from
whom hermione protesting slavery was taking things too far i am fighting what i see as a powerful
insidious misogynistic movement i do not see this particular movement as either benign or powerless
rowling seems to think that the trans rights movement is dangerous and authoritarian
in some unprecedented way that makes it different from all past liberation movements
but how what are these illiberal methods that distinguish trans
rights activism from similar past movements canceling anita bryant was way more cancelled
than jk rowling ever will be boycotts boycotts have been a staple of every progressive movement
in modern history disrupting feminist meetings disrupting feminist meetings is a feminist
tradition haven't you heard of the lavender menace in 1969 betty friedan author of the feminine mystique
and founder of the national organization for women and second wave feminism in general coined the
phrase lavender menace
to describe the threat she believed that lesbians posed
to the women's movement.
Friedan was worried that being associated with lesbians
would make it easy to dismiss the movement
as a bunch of mannish man-haters.
This understandably pissed off a bunch of lesbians
who attended the second Congress to Unite Women in 1970
to stage what used to be known as a ZAP,
a disruptive public protest designed to draw attention
to gay rights issues.
Think glitter bombing, think pies.
Half aggression, half whimsy.
Like that time the Lesbian Avengers zapped
Rowling's friend Baroness Nicholson's house,
demanding that she resign.
This podcast has pushed me over the edge.
Centrism has gone too far, and I am now pro-cancel culture.
So just as the meeting was beginning,
a group of 17 lesbians wearing Lavender Menace t-shirts
switched off the lights, pulled the plug on the mic,
and charged down the aisles, laughing and screaming.
Their leader, Rita Mae Brown, took the mic and yelled,
"'This conference won't proceed
"'until we talk about it.'
"'Let's talk about lesbians and the women's movement.'"
One of the NOW organizers yelled back,
"'I object to your coming in and taking over this meeting.
"'You're acting like men.'"
Betty Friedan would later speculate
that the lesbians were a CIA PSYOP
designed to make the women's movement look bad.
So the Lavender Menace disrupted the feminist meeting
using illiberal tactics,
not because they were against feminism,
but because they wanted lesbian exclusionary feminists
to include them.
It's the same thing that's happening today
when trans people disrupt feminist meetings.
As J.K. Rowling puts it,
interestingly neglecting to mention
which feminist meetings these are.
I was starting to see activists behaving
in a very aggressive way outside feminist meetings.
There was a feminist meeting in which they were banging
and kicking on windows, very threatening.
There's a historical obliviousness to Rowling's idea
that trans activists are somehow more aggressive
than similar past movements.
Like she retweeted a transphobic gay man
called Dennis Noel Kavanaugh, who says,
all those gay rights movements,
gay rights and AIDS protests,
I don't remember a single one
where we intimidated or silenced a woman.
Not a single one.
Dennis has also tweeted that he preferred AIDS
to the trans movement.
And also, quote,
I will fucking nail you to a wall
what you have done to these innocent women.
Your mutilation of these little humand
because they were gay will be nothing
compared to what I will do to you legally.
You think you are ghouls,
wait till I deal with you bastard and I mean to.
Dennis, it's time to log off, gorge.
I do wonder, does Dennis threatening to nail people
to a wall count as illiberal methods?
I guess JK Rowling doesn't think so
because she's never condemned it.
In fact, when Dennis's Twitter suspension ended,
she was right there to welcome him back.
And she continues to retweet him.
I've always been happy to acknowledge
that angry trans people on Twitter
sometimes take things too far.
Things like death threats or misogynistic insults,
I don't support that and I've called it out in the past.
Like when the leftist streamer Vosh,
drama alert, who is not trans,
tweeted at JK Rowling,
women be quieter and start apologizing challenge.
I called him out, tweeting,
doing edgy, ironic misogyny while defending trans people
magnifies the grain of truth in what TERFs say
about there being misogyny in trans activism.
I tweeted that because I recognize
that if people who are claiming to speak for you
are doing so in a misogynistic way,
and if you let that slide,
you're going to wake up one day to find
that you're in a misogynistic movement.
Of course, Vosh took the criticism really well,
explaining that actually,
I just didn't understand the complex tactical arguments
for the moral necessity of being trans.
Being misogynistic to JK Rowling.
And then he accused me of cancel culturing him
while at the same time,
literally telling his followers to publicly shame me.
The more of you were in the replies being like,
that's not what's happening right here.
Like this is necessary, okay?
Publicly shame her into changing her mind on this.
Then bringing up my past struggle with addiction.
Move you off this site and into,
I don't want to bring up the substance abuse.
So that pretty much confirmed to me that Vosh doesn't
actually care about advocating for trans people
and just uses trans rights as a pretext
to act like a fucking dingus.
I won't tell you to publicly shame him though,
because unlike Vosh, I would never sink to that.
The point I'm trying to make is I have no qualms
about calling out people on my side
whenever they go too far or cross a line
or do stupid tweets and then mansplain to me
about how I don't understand tactical misogyny.
Idiot.
But the same cannot be said of JK Rowling.
I have never once seen her call out any of the bigotry and
abusiveness that is absolutely rampant
in the gender-critical movement.
There's a great video called JK Rowling's New Friends
by YouTuber Sean that exposes the dishonesty
of framing this conflict as meek, concerned feminists
versus the abusive trans mob.
A framing that the witch trials of JK Rowling accepts
uncritically, citing numerous examples of death threats
and abusiveness from trans advocates.
Things like, kill TERFs 2014.
How about slowly
and horrendously murder TERFs
in saw-like torture machines and contraptions?
Now, I don't think anyone should joke
about putting people in saw traps,
but also, how serious is this threat
that was posted to Tumblr in 2014?
Let's use our critical thinking skills here.
Do you think that Jigsaw, the villain from the Saw movies,
has a Tumblr account and is threatening TERFs?
Or do you think this was posted by a 14-year-old?
The podcast cites zero examples of death threats and abusiveness
from anti-trans bigots.
And it's not exactly like you have to dig deep to find any.
I can fill the screen up with examples just from people
who JK Rowling has explicitly supported or interacted with.
I will drive you out into the desert and bury you 9 feet down,
one tweet says, from a fan of JK Rowling.
First I'll set you on fire and piss on your half-alive corpse.
Fuck trans activism, fuck gender ideology, and fuck you.
Another threat from the same user is so graphically violent and sexual,
another threat from the same user is so graphically violent and sexual,
I don't know if I can even read it aloud without violating the YouTube terms of service.
But threats like this from the gender critical side are simply not mentioned
in the witch trials of JK Rowling.
Both Rowling and Megan seem happy to cherry-pick threatening tweets
and soundbites of shouting protesters
Fuck you, you ugly piece of shit!
You look like you got your teeth knocked out of your fucking flashes!
as evidence that the trans movement is dangerous and insidious to the core.
But this exact technique has been used against literally
every liberation movement in world history.
For example, let's consider Reclaim the Night,
the protest movement against sexual violence in Britain,
which first got JK Rowling interested in feminism in the 1970s.
Here's how The Guardian, Britain's spineless centrist paper of note,
covered a Reclaim the Night protest in 1979.
Chanting slogans against rape seems reasonable to promote awareness,
but what about the hissing and swearing at any innocent male,
and cries of castrate men?
We were all sympathetic to the principles of the women's liberation movement,
but we left the crowd of shouting, torch-bearing women when it became clear
that my friend's brother was running the risk of personal mutilation if he remained with us.
The protesters were allegedly singing,
Here I stand, my knife in hand, free castration on demand.
So this is how the British press covered the women's movement.
Angry, torch-bearing women screaming,
Castrate men!
Now, is that a fair representation?
Of the women's movement?
Should we judge every movement by its most militant extremists?
Is it fair, say, to pretend that Valerie Solanus,
who shot Andy Warhol,
who advocated for male extermination in her Society for Cutting Up Men manifesto,
is representative of feminism as a whole?
Many anti-feminists over the years have done exactly that.
But it's not fair, is it?
So why does JK Rowling think it's fair to judge the trans movement
by the worst things trans people have ever tweeted?
I want her to choke on my fat trans dick.
And I made excuses for you then.
In the fourth episode of The Witch Trials of JK Rowling,
Megan interviews New York Times columnist Michelle Goldberg,
who has written sympathetically about transphobic feminism.
There's a moment in this interview where Michelle kind of stumbles
into an honest observation that I find fascinating.
Right, I mean, I think you'll often hear people say,
you know, I'm not going to debate my basic humanity.
And part of the difficulty is that there are indeed certain issues
which we have sort of decided somewhat collectively
with some sort of consensus are beyond the realm of debate.
And I think that part of what is so difficult about this issue
is that there are certain people who think that this kind of consensus
can be imposed, maybe, as opposed to evolve organically.
And so they're sort of desperately trying to shore it up
in the hopes, I think, that if they can,
they will enjoy the same sort of assumed
protection as other groups whose rights we've decided
are not up for public conversation.
I think the problem is that we don't actually have a consensus.
So Michelle correctly observes that the reason trans people
are often reluctant to debate our rights is that we want
the same assumed protections as other groups whose rights
liberals have decided are not up for debate.
But then Michelle suggests that trans people have to debate our rights
because there isn't a mainstream consensus that we deserve rights.
I am really curious to know how Michelle Goldberg thinks that past
liberation movements have succeeded.
Like, does she think that women's suffrage just evolved organically?
Did suffragettes just have calm, civil conversations about whether
women are intellectually capable of voting until all the misogynists
were rationally persuaded?
No, they stood up and demanded their right to vote,
sometimes violently, especially in the UK.
Like, people forget this, maybe because they were called suffragettes,
which is kind of a cute thing.
But the suffragettes, they murdered people.
They were suffragette terrorists.
They broke windows.
They bombed churches.
They set fire to a theater.
In 1909, a suffragette attacked Winston Churchill with a horse whip.
Queen shit, honestly.
The English suffragette Mary Lee threw a fucking hatchet
at the Prime Minister's head.
And my point is not to advocate terrorism or to excuse the terrorism
of past movements.
I think these kinds of tactics have tended to turn people against
the movement.
I don't think it's effective.
But let's not pretend that past movements have never made demands
before everyone was ready.
Because there never has been and there never will be a time
when everyone is ready.
I mean, Mary Wollstonecraft published The Vindication of the Rights
of Women in 1792.
And misogyny, in case you hadn't noticed, remains rampant.
So there never has been a consensus about women's rights,
and there probably never will be.
In fact, marginalized groups wouldn't need rights if there was a consensus
that we deserve rights.
The whole reason to have rights is to protect you from the kind of people
who think you shouldn't have them.
I mean, it's a nice thought that we can just politely persuade everyone
to give us rights, but the reality is that's not how this works,
and it never has been.
Like, how do these debate me centrists think that slavery ended
in the United States?
Well, between 1861 and 1865, there was a little event called
the American Civil Debate.
See what I'm holding in my hand?
This is a high-caliber idea that I picked off
the polite discussion field of Manassas.
Do you people think that American schools were integrated
because all the white people in the South were persuaded
that segregation is bad?
No dum-dums.
Eisenhower had to send in the 101st Airborne to enforce that shit
at gunpoint.
And my point is not to equate LGBT rights movements
with black civil rights.
I am aware that being a white queer person is not in any way equivalent
to living in the aftermath of slavery.
I'm just saying that there's this tendency to
sanitize history, and to imagine that progress was smooth
and bloodless, that consensus evolved organically,
when it just didn't.
And then people get the impression that current movements
are somehow more militant than successful past movements
when they just aren't.
I am fighting what I see as a powerful, insidious,
misogynistic movement, a cultural movement that was
illiberal in its methods.
And I believe absolutely that there is something
dangerous about this movement, and it must be challenged.
Why is J.K. Rowling like this?
J.K. Rowling loves to quote radical feminist Andrea Dworkin,
whomst I've already mentioned a couple times in this video.
I myself favor violence.
Deeply, I favor it.
Dworkin is known for her extreme sex-negative views,
which I don't agree with.
But she was an interesting writer, one of those half-crazed,
savantes who gets in your head, who you can't stop thinking about.
In my opinion, Dworkin's best book is Right Wing Women,
published in 1983, the era of Phyllis Schlafly and Anita Bryant.
Right Wing Women is an analysis of why so many women
are drawn to conservative politics, seemingly against their own interests.
Anyone who's interested in understanding the gender-critical movement,
a crypto-reactionary backlash disguising itself as feminism,
should read this book.
In Dworkin's analysis,
And conservative politics promises women meaning.
The gender-critical movement offers women a brutally simple understanding of sex and gender.
A woman is an adult human female.
Right-wing anti-trans activist Posey Parker has made this phrase
into the motto of the gender-critical movement.
Adult human female.
It's on billboards, it's on t-shirts, it's on banners, signs, and tweets.
Presented with the authority of a dictionary definition,
it's rigid, it's orderly, it's immutable.
There are no exceptions, there are no blurred lines,
there can be no change.
This mantra is a defense against the conceptual instability and chaos
that gender-criticals fear.
The same fear that once drove homophobic women like Anita Bryant.
Just biologically that God made mothers so that we could reproduce.
Homosexuals cannot reproduce biologically.
Erasing the concept of sex removes the ability
of many to meaningfully discuss their lives.
Dworkin says,
Within the frame of male domination,
there is a good reason for women to hate homosexuality,
both male and female.
Women are interchangeable as sex objects.
Women are slightly less disposable as mothers.
The only dignity and value women get is as mothers.
Having children is the one social contribution credited to women.
It is the bedrock of women's social worth.
Without childbearing, women know they have nothing.
Homosexuality for women means
having nothing. It means extinction.
Substitute transgenderism for homosexuality
and you'll understand the gender-critical movement.
J.K. Rowling's definition of woman is this.
The woman is the producer of the large gametes.
The producer of the large gametes.
Rowling says her primary concern about young trans men
is the loss of fertility.
Homosexuality, its rise in public visibility,
attempts to socially legitimize or protect it,
makes women expendable.
The one thing women can do and be valued for
will no longer be valued.
Male homosexuality is especially terrifying
because it suggests a world without women altogether.
A world in which women are extinct.
This exact fear appears frequently in gender-critical rhetoric.
Trans activists are erasing women.
They're erasing biological sex.
They're going to call us pregnant.
Pregnant people.
Confused girls are being robbed of their precious fertility.
Trans women are going to replace biological women.
As a woman, I feel threatened because biological men
are aggressively replacing women.
You will not replace us!
Sometimes this paranoia ramps up to the point of obsession
and the results can be...dazzling.
In September 2022, Maya Forstadter,
who you'll remember as the anti-trans activist
whom J.K. Rowling came out as a TERF to defend,
went on a full-blown Twitter rampage
because the Hertfordshire County Libraries announced
they were changing their children's storytime mascot
from the Bookstart Bear
If you don't know where this is going, strap in!
to a bright, vibrant, gender-neutral creature
called Tala.
Are you enraged?
If not, you haven't been spending enough time on Mumsnet.
Maya tweeted the words of an indignant mother
who referred to Talia
Wait, wasn't it Tala?
referring to Talia as a trans bear with they-them pronouns,
describing the mascot as
ideological, creepy, and gaslighting.
I cannot express how upset I feel.
The library jumped in to clarify that Tala,
not Talia,
isn't trans.
They are an alien.
Maya then demanded to know how this alien was birthed.
Did it hatch from an egg?
Or was it born from a mama?
Some people tried to reason with Maya.
There's an advantage in having a character
that isn't identifiably male or female,
as it can be equally relatable to either sex
and avoid promoting gender stereotypes.
But Maya was not convinced.
It seems highly unlikely that an alien
that had evolved with such recognizable vertebrate body plan
is not sexually reproducing.
It's a relatable anthropomorphic character,
not a slime mold.
I need to know
how the alien fucks
right now.
I said,
I need to know
how the alien fucks
before I can show it
to my child.
When Twitter understandably laughed it up at Maya's expense,
she just kept posting.
And she posted hard.
Honestly, I don't know if I've ever seen anyone post so hard.
In a lengthy diatribe,
Maya wrote about the miseries of new motherhood.
You are in charge of a baby.
You have never done this before.
You haven't had a good night's sleep for months
and won't for years.
Everyone has an opinion
on what you are doing right and wrong,
and you've become invisible.
You had politics.
You had a career.
You had interests.
You had a sex life.
Now you have the daily needs
of a completely dependent person,
and your world has shrunk.
The fact that these men
and the young women that cheer them on
think this is so laughable
reflects society's disdain.
Disdain for mothers.
This is what it means to say
a woman is not a feeling or a costume.
This is why the hub of the resistance
is on Mumsnet.
So, I am fascinated by this thread.
I think it's one of the most revealing texts
in gender-critical history.
Because you know what?
Maya Forsyter actually does
have valid concerns.
But the concerns she has that are valid
have nothing to do with trans people.
And they definitely have nothing to do
with an adorable,
adorable cartoon alien.
Honestly, reading this,
I have some concerns.
Concerns like,
where is Maya's husband?
I know she has one.
Isn't raising children supposed to be
a mutual project?
No one should have to feel this alone,
raising children.
That is a valid concern.
Oh my god, we actually found one.
It's like finding El Dorado.
A valid concern.
Isn't what's going on here that Maya
is taking legitimate feelings of being
overburdened and underappreciated
and displacing those feelings onto
transgender people?
This is exactly how the gender-critical
movement recruits.
By providing a scapegoat
to frustrated women.
It's not your husband's neglect.
It's not the increasing atomization of society.
It's not the indignities of aging.
It's Tala,
the non-binary alien,
with its dungarees and
smug aura of gender neutrality.
Mumsnet is the hub!
The hub of the resistance
to non-binary cartoons.
It's too much.
These people are too much.
Okay, we have to be serious now.
The political right also promises women
safety and security.
For women, the world is a very dangerous place.
The right acknowledges the reality of danger,
the validity of fear.
The right then manipulates the fear.
Women fear and resent male violence,
which they're most likely to experience
from the men closest to them.
Boyfriends, husbands, and fathers.
They're most likely to be killed by sexual partners.
But the need to survive in a male-dominated society
means that women's legitimate fears and resentments
often cannot be directed at the men with power.
Inevitably, this causes women to take the rage
and contempt they feel
for the men who actually abuse them,
those close to them,
and project it onto others.
Those far away, foreign, or different.
And this displacement of rage
is just transparently what's going on
with J.K. Rowling.
In her essay about sex and gender issues,
Rowling speculates that trans men are transitioning
to be the son her father wanted.
I really felt the rejection of my father,
and that is one of the things that maybe leads
someone going into homosexuality.
And she describes the lingering trauma
from her first violent marriage.
The marriage at this point has turned very violent
and very controlling.
And that, she says, is why she decided to speak out
against the transgender movement.
If you try to understand this rationally,
it looks like a total non sequitur.
But if you look at it emotionally,
there's a kind of logic to it.
The existence of the dangerous outsider
always functions for women simultaneously
as deception, diversion, painkiller, and threat.
Women cling to irrational hatreds
focused particularly on the unfamiliar,
so that they will not murder their fathers,
husbands, sons, brothers, lovers,
the men with whom they are intimate,
those who do hurt them.
In the 1970s, many conservative women
displaced this rage onto lesbians,
the threatening outsider of the day.
Dworkin attended the National Women's Conference in 1977,
where she spoke to a lot of women
about their fear of lesbians.
Right-wing women consistently spoke to me
about lesbians as if lesbians were rapists,
certified committers of sexual assault
against women and girls.
To them, the lesbian was inherently monstrous,
experienced almost as a demonic sexual force
hovering closer and closer.
She was the dangerous intruder,
encroaching, threatening by her very presence
a sexual order that cannot bear scrutiny
or withstand challenge.
It's almost surreal to read this
because of how precisely it describes
how gender criticals talk about trans women.
Pronouns are like Rohypnol.
They dull your defenses.
They change your inhibitions.
They're meant to.
Now, it's true that trans-exclusionary radical feminism
began as an offshoot of far-left lesbian separatism,
with academic feminist Janice Raymond writing in 1979
that transsexualism should be morally mandated
out of existence.
But the gender critical movement was always destined
to become a right-wing movement
because it has the structure of a right-wing movement.
Taking women's fear and rage toward familiar men
and displacing it onto an unfamiliar outsider.
The momentum behind this is just too ripe an opportunity
for conservatives to pass up.
As Dworkin says,
Because women so displace their rage,
they are easily controlled and manipulated haters.
Women require symbols of danger that justify their fear.
The right provides these symbols of danger
by designating clearly defined groups of outsiders
as sources of danger.
In the 2020s, anti-trans bigotry has become a trend.
A keystone of Conservative Party platforms,
both in the UK,
where Lee Anderson,
Deputy Chair of the Conservative Party,
predicts that the next election will be won on
Probably a mix of culture wars and trans debate.
and in the US,
where the ACLU is currently tracking more than
450 anti-LGBT bills,
including more than 130 gender-affirming care bans,
51 trans sports bans,
40 drag bans,
29 trans bathroom bans,
and 24
and 21 bans defining trans people out of the law.
Republicans have escalated anti-trans rhetoric
to eliminationist extremes
that have most trans people in this country
living in a constant state of fear for our future.
Transgenderism must be eradicated
from public life entirely.
The left is attacking our children,
pushing sex talk,
transgender extremism,
and noxious politics in our schools.
We should reject this demonic assault
on the innocence of our children
and stand fast against leftist efforts
to mutilate their bodies and minds.
Stop confusing our babies
with your groomer gender ideologue.
I will revoke every Biden policy
promoting the chemical castration
and sexual mutilization
of our youth,
and ask Congress to send me a bill
prohibiting child sexual mutilation
in all 50 states.
On day one, I will revoke
Joe Biden's cruel policies
on so-called gender-affirming care.
Ridiculous.
I will sign a new executive order
instructing every federal agency
to cease all programs
that promote the concept of sex
and gender transition at any age.
A few gender criticals
still want to insist
they have nothing to do
with right-wing anti-trans bigots.
Like Helen Lewis.
I mean, TERF is basically witch.
Who attempts in her interview
in the witch trials of J.K. Rowling
to distinguish between the transphobia
of the far right
and that of feminists.
I think the hardest thing
for outsiders to understand
is that there are two different arguments going on.
One is the traditional conservative right argument
which is anti-LGBT.
The other one is a criticism from the left
in which it says
sometimes male people and female people
have different interests.
No matter how the male people identify.
But as a trans person,
I don't care
whether you justify your transphobia
in the name of protecting women
or protecting children.
Whether it's radical feminist Janice Raymond
calling for transsexualism
to be morally mandated out of existence
or conservative Catholic Michael Knowles
calling for transgenderism
to be eradicated from public life
is the same repulsive bigotry to me.
And in any case,
the gender critical movement
has recently reached
an implicit consensus
that they're mostly done
pretending to be feminist.
The rising star of the movement
Posey Parker
aka Kelly J. Keene-Minchel
rejects feminism entirely.
Do you call yourself a feminist now?
No.
Did you ever call yourself a feminist?
I probably did for a short time.
But so you wouldn't be
like a Julie Bindel type feminist?
No, well some feminists,
I mean Julie Bindel
has been critical of mothers in the past
and I think that's a theme
flowing through feminism.
I'm not a feminist!
This is not Andrea Dworkin.
This is Phyllis Schlafly.
Parker's campaign is currently funded
by the right wing CPAC.
CPAC came along
and said that they would sponsor our events
and cover all of our insurance
throughout our whole trip
which is really kind of them.
But what we would need to do
is we would need to show
that we were working for them,
working with them.
She has no qualms about collaborating
with far right white nationalists.
I want to talk about Marjorie Taylor Greene.
Let me tell you what she's been saying.
She's a Republican,
but she, I agree with her wholeheartedly.
She's opposed abortion
and contraception for teenagers.
Why are we enabling children
to take sometimes contraceptives
that are quite harmful
or access to abortion?
I think that we really need
to rethink all of this.
I think parents need to take back
control of their children.
She's called trans people
fools and perverts.
Transgenderism is nuts.
It's for fools and perverts.
She's denied that transgender
is a legitimate concept.
It's not a real thing.
There's no such thing
as being born in the wrong body.
There's no such thing as a trans woman.
There's no such thing as a trans person.
There is no such thing.
There are people that call themselves
these things that may have other issues
manifesting that then make them think
they're this, but no.
We have to stop using any words
like transgender.
There may be more words
that we have to say in order to say that.
We may call it transgender ideology,
but when it comes to a person,
they may be following transgender ideology,
but they are not transgender.
There is no such thing as a man
or a woman being anything other
than a man or a woman.
She's called trans women pedophiles.
We know that if a man has a paraphilia
of dressing as a woman,
the most likely cross paraphilia is pedophilia.
We know that these men have multiple paraphilias.
They don't ever stop at one.
She's said that each and every woman
who stands in her way will be annihilated.
Each and every one of you women
who stand in my way,
each and every one of you,
let me just tell you,
you will be annihilated.
She's called on armed men
to enter women's restrooms
to attack anyone they perceive
as not a real woman.
And men, for once,
I'm talking to you.
I'm talking about you dads
who maybe carry,
I think that's what you say.
I'm so done with the American lingo.
Maybe you carry, maybe you don't.
Maybe you consider yourself
a protector of women.
Maybe you're that sort of man.
Maybe you have a daughter
or a mother or a wife.
Maybe you have a sister.
Maybe you just have some friends.
Maybe you just think women are human
and you don't need
any absolute connection with them
to feel compelled to protect us.
Um, I think you should start
using women's toilets, men.
And she's said that women
who call themselves men
should be sterilized,
which seems to be a little bit in tension
with JK Rowling's concern
about the fertility of confused girls.
You know, you might look
at these differences of opinion
between Rowling and Parker,
little things like pro-feminist
versus anti-feminist,
left versus right,
pro-abortion versus anti-abortion,
concern about trans men's fertility
versus advocating forced sterilization
of trans men,
against annihilating women
who stand in your way
versus pro-annihilating
each and every woman
who stands in your way.
You might look at these differences
and expect that these two women
would be at odds.
But they aren't.
Because promoting anti-trans bigotry
is a common cause
that for both of them,
trumps all else.
In 2020, Posey Parker paid for a poster
reading,
I heart JK Rowling
to be displayed at a railway station
in Edinburgh.
And Rowling has tweeted
in defense of Parker numerous times
and has modeled her t-shirts.
So, the gender-critical movement
started by lesbian separatists
in the 1970s
has finally passed into the hands
of pound shop Ava Browns,
as gender-critical lesbian Julie Bindle
memorably described them.
It's a movement that has no beliefs
apart from a shared determination
to reduce the number of trans people.
In the numbers we're currently seeing,
particularly of young people coming forward,
I find cause for doubt.
In the meantime,
while we're trying to get through
to the decision makers,
we have to try to limit the harm.
And that means reducing
or keeping down the number of people
who transition.
And that's for two reasons.
One of them is that every one of those people
is a person who's been damaged.
But the second one is every one of those people
is basically,
you know, a huge problem to a sane world.
Like, if you've got people,
whether they're transitioned,
whether they're happily transitioned,
whether they're unhappily transitioned,
whether they're detransitioned,
if you've got people who've dissociated
from their sex in some way,
every one of those people
is someone who needs special accommodation.
In a sane world where we
re-acknowledge the truth of sex.
So to wrap this up,
is the backlash against JK Rowling
a witch hunt?
Unequivocally, no.
It's very thoroughly deserved.
But I will say this.
A movement can't get along without a devil.
And across the whole political spectrum,
there's a misogynistic tendency
to choose a female devil.
Whether it's Anita Bryant,
Hillary Clinton,
Marie Antoinette,
Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez,
or JK Rowling.
And there's always going to be people
who seize on any opportunity
to be misogynistic.
So, I would advise trans people
and our allies to keep in mind
that JK Rowling is not the final boss
of transphobia.
She's not our devil.
The devil is the Republican Party,
the conservative party.
The devil is patriarchy.
It's the right-wing men
who will be the ones
to put gender-critical theory
into brutal practice.
Anita Bryant,
Posey Parker,
and JK Rowling are,
to borrow a term from TERFs,
handmaidens.
TERFs are the real handmaidens.
They're useful idiots
who put a concerned female face
on the patriarchal violence
against trans people
that will ultimately be enacted
by right-wing men.
I call on men
to consider themselves
decent human beings.
To call out the deviance among them
and eradicate these monsters
from society.
And Megan Phillips Roper
and centrists like her
are wrong that civil conversation
can resolve this.
To call out the deviance among them
and eradicate these monsters
from society.
People like Michael Knowles
and Ron DeSantis
and Donald Trump
cannot be persuaded.
They have to be defeated.
As for what to do about JK Rowling,
honestly,
let's all just block her.
Open up Twitter right now,
go to her profile
and just block her.
Problem solved.
Like, don't harass her,
that doesn't help.
But also,
I wouldn't wait for her to change.
She's gone down what I call
the bigotry whirlpool.
The deeper you go in,
the harder it is to leave.
For the same reasons
that it's hard to quit a cult or scam.
To quote video essayist Dan Olson,
One of the most insidious elements
of a confidence scam
is that the victims
who invested the most
are often the most passionate defenders.
Because shame
is a powerful force
in the human psyche
and they can't bear the shame
of admitting they were tricked.
Reformed bigots have to face
not only the shame
of being dupes,
but also the guilt
of having devoted years of life
to harming vulnerable people.
This is something Megan,
to her credit,
faced head on.
If we were wrong,
then I had spent
every day of my life
industriously sowing doom,
discord,
and rage
to so many
not at the behest of God,
but of others.
Not at the behest
of my grandfather.
I had wasted my life
only to fill others
with pain and misery.
Most bigots cannot stand
to face this moral sunk cost.
It's why an obsessive bigot
like Graham Linehan,
whose all-consuming hatred
of trans people
has ruined his life,
cost him his marriage,
and left him alone
to tweet about destroying
gender ideology
minutes before midnight
on New Year's Eve,
feels psychologically compelled
to insist with ever more certainty
that trans people
are not just delusional
or dangerous,
but are all
demonic perverts,
an enemy so hyperbolically evil
that they justify
his self-immolating crusade.
They took everything from me,
you know.
They took my family,
And I just said,
no, hang on a sec.
Stop calling these women TERFs.
Stop sending them abuse.
Let them speak.
And for that,
they just destroyed me.
Do you honestly feel destroyed?
No, because,
because the one thing about this,
the one thing about this
that keeps me going
is that I know I'm right,
you know.
I know I'm right.
As long as he stays here,
in the bottom of the whirlpool,
he never has to face
that he's ruined his relationships
and wasted years of life
because he just couldn't let it go.
And if JK Rowling
doesn't log off soon,
this will likely be her fate as well.
I guess what I'm really trying to say is,
Harry Potter's dead to me.
I'm switching to Twilight.
And there's authors
that are bound to say
that wizardry is a good thing
but neither is warned.
And they say,
well,
you and I
can
think about
some other story
you can put a bit
more perspective.
Anything will
please let these characters
have their own story.
Because it all depends
on Jesus.
Especially what one
of the characters
would ever say when
they first come here.
said that she was
on the line
and byr.
His daughter.
spelled out
it's one of the reasons
Jim Crow doesn't roll over,
Thank you.
At least it's a fruit pie.