Comfort ye, comfort ye, my subscribers, so saith your goddess, for it is I, the digital messiah, the online oracle, the social media savior, yea, verily I say unto you, there are influencers abiding in the feed, keeping watch over their followers by night.
And lo, I came upon them, and the glory of my posts shone about me, and I delivered unto them a vision.
Freedom, freedom, fucking freedom.
Which matters more, the freedom to live an authentic life, or the freedom to crush degenerates under the heel of a jackboot?
As a centrist, I am unbiased.
Undecided, but the important thing is we are talking about it.
Hi, I'm Jackie Jackson, host of the Freedom Report, the political talk show where we discuss important issues like Mexicans.
How dangerous are they?
Muslims, can we stop them?
Tonight we return, once again, to the dangerous transgender trend that is turning your children into all manner of half-and-halfs and in-betweens.
I mean, look at this, they're transing 13-year-olds now, what's next, babies with breast implants?
It makes me want to throw up.
I live in constant fear, and fear is what freedom is all about.
Cut the music!
Tonight, my first guest is Tiffany Tumbles, transgender makeup vlogger and conservative opinion-haver.
And my second guest...
Well, what the hell are you? You're transgender, you're a man, you're a woman, you're an attack helicopter, what's your deal?
Well, Jackie Jackson, my, as you say, deal, is I don't like society.
Forcing me into tiny little boxes.
Okay, but are you a man or a woman? Just tell me.
Well, why does it matter? Why do you have to know?
Maybe you should examine why it is you feel the need to fit everyone you meet into these little categories, Jackie Jackson.
Well, can I at least ask your name, or is that now considered cisgender imperialism?
My name is Baltimore.
Baltimore what?
Baltimore, Maryland.
I'm sorry, your name is Baltimore, Maryland?
It is among my names.
Tiffany, what do you make of this?
Look, Jackie, I'm going to be completely real with you.
I am a transsexual.
That means I have a very specific mental disorder called gender dysphoria.
I was born a boy, but I have a female brain because of a hormone imbalance in the womb.
This is a real psychiatric disorder that is verified by science and requires hormones and surgery for treatment or else I literally cannot function.
It is not a fashion statement.
It is not a trend.
It is not an easy way to feel special and oppressed.
It is a very difficult condition to live with.
I'm dying inside.
Okay, so you're both transsexuals then.
No, I am a transsexual.
That is not a transsexual.
That is a trans-trender.
Trans-trender? What is that? Is that a gender?
No, it's not a gender.
A trans-trender is a person like Baltimore over here,
who puts on a dress and puts glitter on his beard and goes around telling people he's transgender and complaining about misgendering for oppression points.
Actually, it's they.
What?
I use they-them pronouns.
They go around collecting oppression points, as you can see.
Why do you say that, Tiffany Tumbles?
Have I complained about oppression so far?
It seems to me that it is you who has been complaining about your dysphoria.
Isn't it you?
Is it you who is collecting oppression points, Tiffany Tumbles?
No, I'm not saying I'm oppressed.
I'm saying I have dysphoria, which is not society's fault.
It's in my brain.
I was diagnosed.
It's a fact.
It's real.
My pain is real.
And my pain isn't real?
It's interesting that you think that.
Well, what pain are you talking about?
People making fun of you because you dress like a circus act?
Interesting that you mentioned the circus.
Tiffany Tumbles, don't you think we should examine why society confines gender-variant people to the circus?
You're not confined anywhere.
You choose to dress like that.
And why do you choose to dress the way you dress?
Because I'm a woman, so I'm dressed like a woman.
Hello.
And I'm non-binary, so I dress non-conforming.
Why should I conceal who I am just to appease small-minded people?
Well, it's a free country.
If you want to be a glitterbeard genderfuck, then go ahead.
But don't go around telling people that you're transgender because it makes us all look like a bunch of trendy freaks.
But aren't we all freaks in the eyes of society?
Do you think you can purchase acceptance through conformity?
Because that is not freedom, Tiffany Tumbles.
That is simply adding another cell to the prison.
It's not about conforming.
It's about me having an actual medical condition.
You do not have a female brain.
You have a fashion disaster.
Oh, do they?
Well, tell me, Tiffany Tumbles.
When the doctor prescribed your hormones, did he take a look at your brain then?
What?
Of course not.
But you have seen a scan of your brain, yes?
Well, no.
Where are you going with this?
I mean, if you've never seen your brain,
and the doctor who diagnosed your gender dysphoria didn't look at it,
then tell me, Tiffany Tumbles,
how do you know that you have a female brain?
Bullshit.
That's a good point.
No, it isn't.
Look, there's scientific studies that—
Can you explain to me the difference between a male brain and a female brain?
Are they different colors?
I'm not an expert.
But there's science showing that men and women have brain differences.
I see.
But your doctor never looked at your brain.
So how did he know that you have gender dysphoria?
Well, he asked me questions and I told him about it.
And you told him what exactly?
That I experience gender dysphoria.
So would you agree then that your gender dysphoria,
and therefore your identity,
is valid not because of any observed factors,
not because of any observed facts about your brain,
but because of your feelings?
Well, congratulations, Attorney Frankenfurter.
You backed me into a corner.
Sure, it's because of my feelings.
My feelings of gender dysphoria.
So tell me, Tiffany Tumbles,
why is it that your feelings about your gender are valid,
but mine, according to you, are not?
This burgeoning brick.
You guys, let's think about this.
If I have never seen my brain,
how do I know I even have a brain?
Well, you probably don't, girl.
Look, Baltimore, I'm sure you have lots of feelings about your gender.
And if you feel cloud gender or demi-nebula or astroglide
or whatever Tumblr bullshit passes through your mind,
then you do you, girl.
Or, not girl, whatever the fuck you are.
But I want to make one thing very clear.
I am nothing like you, okay?
My gender is not unicorns and glitter.
My gender is a serious psychiatric diagnosis
that I wouldn't wish on my worst enemy.
No, not even you.
My, I'm really getting under your skin, aren't I?
No.
Well, actually, yes, to be honest, you are.
You're getting under my skin because it really rattles my dysphoria
that you're sitting here claiming to represent the transgender community,
when in fact, you're just making a mockery of my pain.
Your pain?
You're in a lot of pain, aren't you, Tiffany Tumbles?
Well, I can sense the vibrations of your pain across the room.
And I pity you, Tiffany Tumbles.
I pity you because you don't think you're real
until a man in a lab coat signs a prescription pad.
And I can't imagine what it must be like
to have so little confidence
in your own reality.
Okay, well, don't patronize me.
I'm just trying to understand, Tiffany Tumbles,
why you think being transgender is all about hating yourself
and hating your body.
Why can't trans identity be joyful and celebratory?
No, you don't have to hate yourself or hate your body,
but you do have to have dysphoria.
And if you tell people otherwise, you're just misleading them.
I want to heal the rift inside your heart, Tiffany Tumbles.
Would you please join me
in saying a prayer for your wellness?
Actually, I would strongly prefer
if you would stay away from any of my rifts.
Oh, goddess of light,
please shield and protect Tiffany
against the ravages of inner strife.
Enclose her in your loving arms
and cleanse her of all condemnation
and internalized transphobia.
I entreat you, oh great mother,
bathe Tiffany in inner peace, acceptance, and self-care,
and rid her of her toxic,
disnormative, true scum ways.
Amen.
Are we done here?
I don't think I can make it through any more readings
from the SJW prayer book.
Tiffany, why are you rejecting the love
I am trying to deliver unto you?
Because I'm grossed out by you.
That's why.
Okay, then.
Well, namaste, bitch.
Look, why don't we all take a step back
and take a moment just to honor our heroes in uniform
and let them know how much we appreciate their service.
God, I love the troops.
Thinking about the troops makes me wet.
It makes me cum.
Semper fi, boys.
What?
I think I'm starting to wrap my head around this.
Tiffany, your transsexualism,
I have to say I don't love it,
but you do seem to at least be aware
that you have some kind of mental disorder,
so I'll give you that.
Whereas, Baltimore, you're what?
Making some kind of statement?
If my existence is a statement,
I think that says more about society
than it says about me.
Jackie, what you have to understand
is there have been transsexuals around for a long time.
I have talked to 80-year-old transsexuals,
and they agree with me
that all this genderqueer bullshit,
it's just a trend.
It's a fad.
But is it?
For thousands of years,
there have been third-gender groups
across human cultures.
There's the Hydra of India,
the two-spirit people among Native Americans.
Whereas, binary transsexualism
is a medical construct of the 20th century.
Gender dysphoria wasn't even a recognized medical condition
until 2013,
meaning that Tumblr is twice as old
as the first gender dysphoria diagnosis.
So perhaps it is you, Tiffany Tumbles,
and not I who is following a trend.
Wow, that just blew my mind.
The tables are turned, bitch.
Tiffany, could you explain to me
why you decided to become a trans-trender?
He's not Native American, though.
They.
You know, it's kinda hard not to call you he
when you have a fucking beard.
If you were actually trans
and you actually had dysphoria,
then you wouldn't be comfortable with that.
Your Honor, in my defense,
it is a glitter beard.
Okay.
Well, that's very 2019,
very gender, very they,
but what it isn't is two-spirit.
Look, the SJWs don't even agree with this.
They think it's racist.
White people have two genders.
Pick one and sit down, dude.
Yeah, that's a good point.
Two genders.
Attack helicopter.
It's ma'am.
Okay.
Attack helicopter.
Two genders.
Only two genders.
How many genders?
Two.
Attack helicopter.
It's ma'am.
Two genders.
You're just saying that you're me
and talking in a whiny voice.
That is not an argument.
The toxic truce gumbolias are gatekeeping my gender.
I don't have dysphoria,
but for some reason,
I still have access to doctors
like a transition
from a man to a man.
The one thing you'll always have to deal with in life
is assholes.
Oh, but how dare you misgender me?
It's hard to be yourself,
but it's worth it.
How dare you not know that I use they,
then I don't,
even though no one ever sees that.
Let's be ourselves.
Let's totally be ourselves.
All right.
That's enough of this.
You know,
as a biological female,
I honestly don't understand any of this
shitty shit.
Okay.
That was a hard T.
Now, does my husband sometimes wear panties around the house
and ask me to call him mommy's little slut?
Well, sure,
but that is a matter between her and the Lord.
Let's best not think about it too much.
Anyway, Tiffany,
my brain has an easier time processing you
than whatever is going on over here,
so congratulations.
You're the winner.
That was some excellent free speech.
Okay.
Great.
So, in conclusion,
trans-trenders are real
and probably dangerous.
Make sure to protect your children.
Bye.
As for how many genders there are,
you know,
I'm going to take the centrist route
and say two and a half.
All right.
That's our show.
This has been the Freedom Report
where the debate never stops.
Except when the show is over.
Get out.
The girl can't help it.
She's a Libra.
Behold,
the non-binary lamb
who is despised and rejected.
They gave their cheek
to them that mocked their beard
and hid not their face from shame.
But lo,
Tiffany,
the person who tricks
trendier than thou,
a shady queen,
came next upon her friend Justine
and sought her counsel thus.
God damn it, Justine.
I just can't
with these trenders anymore.
I simply cannot.
You know,
you can just text me here
and I'll come open the door.
Okay.
Seems a little formal.
Ugh.
You look great, hon.
Cute.
Justine,
you look like absolute shit.
What happened?
Did the cat girl
finally beat you up?
No.
I...
Justine, look,
I slept in my makeup, okay?
Leave me alone.
I've been having a difficult time.
Were we serving
a little depression moment?
Jesus.
Well,
don't leave me out.
I saw you
on the Freedom Report today.
Okay, girl,
can we talk about
Ladybeard, Baltimore, Maryland?
Ugh.
Add that one
to the crazy
tranny hall of fame.
Really?
You're happy
with the way that went?
You feel good about that?
You feel good
about yourself right now?
Well,
why wouldn't I?
Tiffany,
there is nothing
more sad
and pathetic
and desperate
and low in this world
than a tran
who thinks
she's better
than other trans.
It's like a drunk
feeling superior
to a junkie.
You seem to think
that you're queen
of the world
because you're hanging on
to societal acceptance
by two fingers
instead of one.
Well,
you're not, bitch.
You're just an insecure,
frightened little queer
who's determined
to use the one ounce
of power you have
to tread
other people down.
And if I'm being honest,
I don't find
that very admirable.
Your eyelash
is coming unglued.
Ugh.
My life is coming unglued.
Look,
it's not like I'm coming
after trannies
who just can't afford
to transition
or don't have
the social support.
It's not like Baltimore
is doing everything
he can to pass
and people just treat him
like a freak
for no reason.
They.
It's they.
Are we really saying
they now?
In private?
Yes,
we are.
So get used to it.
My name is Justine.
I think misgendering
is toxic
because I care
about people's feelings.
Ugh.
I always forget
that you're like
actually an SJW.
I always forget
that you're actually
an asshole.
Why do I even hang out
with you?
Oh,
because you hate yourself
and you have to believe
there's hope for me
because if there's hope
for me,
there might be hope
for you.
Wow,
you're developing
self-consciousness.
Where'd you learn
that trick?
Gigi?
Tiffany,
have you ever
been bullied?
Oh,
let's see.
You don't see me
going on talk shows
to play the victim.
No,
I see you going
on talk shows
to play the bully.
I think you grew up
getting bullied
for being a sissy
till you started passing
as a woman
and then you got
a little taste of normal
and now you want
to be the one
who bashes the queers.
Bash them?
If anything,
I'm the one
defending trans people
from appropriation
and misrepresentation
by these trenders.
You said on air
that Baltimore
grosses you out.
Do you really
expect me to believe
that you have
anything to do
with your own
self-loathing?
How could it be
self-loathing
when Baltimore
is nothing
like me?
Okay,
then it's just bigotry.
That's even worse.
Oh,
it's not bigotry.
Look,
I shouldn't have said
grossed out,
I'll give you that,
but he does,
they do
make me uncomfortable.
And why do you
think that is?
Ugh,
I got secondhand dysphoria
looking at someone
so burgeoning.
Ugh,
it makes me want
to down a bottle
of whiskey
and you just
clock everything
and you feel like
sympathetic
vibrations
of dysphoria.
Yeah,
I do know
what you're talking about
and I'll tell you
why it happens.
When you're early
in your transition
and you're doing
everything you can
to pass,
you develop
a really sophisticated eye
for every little thing
that makes you clockable.
Then,
you turn that
sophisticated eye
onto other
trans people
and you project
your dysphoria
onto them.
I buy that.
This is
other trans people's
presentation.
Secondhand dysphoria
is not valid.
The fact that
you project
your dysphoria
onto other people
is your problem
and your problem alone.
And you need to deal
with that issue
in private,
girl,
not on a fucking
talk show.
Yeah,
you're probably
right about that.
But it still
doesn't make
Baltimore,
Maryland
any more valid.
Tiffany,
let's be pragmatic
about this.
Suppose everything
you do
is for the
sake
of
transsexuals.
Every time
you say the word
transsexual,
I feel like
it's 1978.
Are you 80 years old?
I guess you could say
I'm not the trendiest person.
Haha.
Look,
suppose you're right
and everyone
who doesn't meet
your definition
of a transsexual
is some kind of
confused trend follower.
Even if that were true,
and to be clear,
it isn't,
what you're doing
harms
even the trans people
you think are valid
about their gender
and of having
non-conforming expression
and you're going around
enforcing a stigma
against that.
Didn't you ever
have doubts
about your gender?
Weren't you ever
androgynous?
Oh yeah,
I mean,
I was never
that burgeoning,
but I had my little
cringe here
being a non-binary
SJW.
Uh huh.
And one of the great
things about
non-binary identities
is they give
trans people
the conceptual
space to exist
even when
neither gender
confuses them.
Has it occurred to you
that being shamed
and berated
for being a trender
during your
exploration year
might not have been
the most helpful thing?
Not really.
I have dysphoria
so if anyone
called me a trender
I'd eventually
prove them wrong.
That's all I'm saying.
If you're not a trender,
then transition.
Prove me wrong.
The stigma
you perpetuate
against gender confusion
and experimentation
keeps trans people
in the closet
and delays transition.
It alienates
baby trans
from the community
instead of publicly
humiliating them.
And when you
appoint yourself
the public decider
of whomst is
really trans,
the Torquemada
of the trender
inquisition,
you're terrorizing
a lot of people
who are genuinely
trying to figure
themselves out.
Okay.
But then
how do we decide
which trendies
are valid?
We don't.
Then this is
where I'm losing you.
Because trans trenders
are absolutely a thing.
Like, undeniably.
I've talked to people
who've literally told me
they used to be
trans trenders.
Some people
question their gender
but end up deciding
they're not really trans.
There is nothing
wrong with that.
And those people
still aren't being helped
by public shaming.
Well, maybe they wouldn't
be confused in the first place
if SJWs weren't
going around
telling people
they don't need dysphoria
to be trans.
You know,
it's one thing
if teenage girls
want to dye their hair pink
and call themselves
Demi Boys
for most of sophomore year.
But some of these kids
are actually gonna
medically transition.
And soon,
we're gonna have
an epidemic
of detransitioners
who told you so
op-eds
in every major newspaper.
Now, maybe you think
that's worth it
just to make sure
no one ever feels
invalidated
for any reason.
But I think
that's highly irresponsible.
Look,
if you're so worried
about people
feeling pressured
to medically transition,
then what you should be doing
is working to make
the trans community
as inclusive
and welcoming
as possible
to gender non-conforming people
and non-binary people
and people
who are questioning
and trans people
who don't medically transition.
But instead,
you're doing
the exact opposite.
You're telling everyone
that medical transition
is the only way
to be valid.
And if anything
is pressuring people
to medically transition,
it's that.
Justine,
I think
you're a good person.
Maybe too good.
And that's why
you're trying
to have compassion
for everyone.
But at some point,
you have to protect yourself.
We live in a world
of Jackie Jacksons
who don't understand
trans people
and don't think
we're real.
So we need to have
an explanation
of what it is
to be trans
and not feelings.
And the most factual
explanation
is transmedicalism,
which is the idea
that transsexualism
is a diagnosable
mental disorder
called gender dysphoria.
There's science
to back this up.
It's accepted
by medical professionals
and it clearly explains
why we are valid
unlike Rachel Dolezal
and snowflake
gender teenagers
and people
who identify
as cats.
Okay,
I see the appeal
but I don't think
transmedicalism
is as validating
as you think it is.
Why not?
Apparently.
Why does having
gender dysphoria
make you a woman?
Because gender dysphoria
means I have
a female brain.
No it doesn't.
I'm sorry to tell you
but the science
does not say
what you think it says.
There may be neurological
causes of gender dysphoria
but at the end
of the day
all dysphoria is
is discomfort
in a male body
or a male social role
or however you want
to put it.
And wanting
to be a woman
is not the same thing
as being a woman.
Not by any means.
Girl, where are you
going with this?
What is this?
Are you becoming
a TERF?
No, I just don't think
your theory actually validates
our womanhood.
Well if you're right
that's a real problem
because we need
to have reason
and science
and logic
and facts
on our side
so that we can explain
to society
that we are valid
and that we are real
otherwise
bad things.
Well maybe there's
a better theory.
Well okay Socrates
let's hear it then.
The way I see it
gender is either
psychological
or biological
or social.
Now my friend Tabby
the cat girl
she thinks it's
all psychological
that it's just
identity
that whatever you think
about your own gender
is true.
And that makes me
really uncomfortable
because then
what's the difference
between identifying
as a woman
and identifying
as a Norwegian forest cat?
It's a difference
that Tabby herself
seems not to have
much of a grip on.
Girl that's literally
what I've been trying
to tell you about
trans-trenders
this entire time.
Just let me finish.
If gender is strictly
biological
it doesn't influence people
unless you make
some kind of
wrong brain
and the wrong body argument
but I told you
I'm not buying that.
So that leaves
gender as a social construct.
Are you going to try
to make me read
Judith Butler again?
I'll summarize it.
Gender is a series
of gestures.
It's called performativity.
It's the way you dress.
It's the way you speak.
It's the way you act.
It's the way you relate
to other people.
Through transitioning
we habituate
to the gestures
of womanhood
and socially
that makes us women
regardless of
biology or psychology
checkmate
or transphobe.
Okay.
The problem with that
is that it's both
too exclusionary
and too inclusive.
It excludes
a lot of trans people
who can't transition
for circumstantial reasons
but whose dysphoria
is very real.
And it includes
every trans-trender
drag queen
fetishist
and two-bit
cross-dressing comedian
in a dine-out wig.
Well,
do you really believe
that a man who plays
a woman on stage
becomes just as much
of a woman
as you and me?
Uh,
yes?
Bitch,
no you don't.
Yeah,
you're right.
I'm full of shit.
I know you are
because you're an SJW
and SJWs hate
performativity theory
almost as much
as they hate me.
Well,
they only hate it
because they don't understand it.
They think it invalidates
non-binary identities
but in fact
it's the most rational way
to explain
non-binary identities.
How can you perform
a non-binary identity?
Simple.
You learn the rules
so you can break them.
Wearing a beard
and a dress
and the gesture
of declaring
I am neither a man
or a woman
is a speech act
that removes the speaker
from the semantics
Girl,
shut up.
This is too much philosophizing.
I can't stand it anymore.
Why don't you tell me
what's really going on with you?
Why do you look like
you've been in a k-hole
for a week?
Why are you suddenly
so obsessed
with white knighting
for non-binary people?
Because I am non-binary.
No you're not.
What are you talking about?
I just
feel like
since I started transitioning
I've been trying
so hard
to fit in
and to perform
my gender
and to pass
and to just be normal.
But I can't do it anymore.
I just cannot
make it work.
I feel like an actor.
I feel like a zombie.
Like I'm
going through
the motions
of this new gender role
that's supposed
to liberate me
but that's somehow
just as empty
as the old one.
Because I'm just
not normal, Tiffany.
I am a freak.
And I'm always
gonna be a freak.
Justine,
you're not non-binary.
You're gay.
And everyone
can see this
Oh come on.
I'm not
gay.
Justine
was extremely
gay.
In protest
to the Lady May
there simply
is no stopping
gayness.
I love
cat girls.
I hate
cat girls
but I also
love them.
Oh
abominable
fate.
Okay.
So I'm a little bit
gay.
Right.
And you don't know
how to reconcile
your gender.
That's why you feel
this dissonance.
Yeah.
I guess that's
basically it.
Well it really shouldn't
be that hard, girl.
You already came out
as a woman.
Just blurt it out.
Say,
Hello world.
My name is Justine
and I fuck
pussy.
That's a very
cis-normative way to
Say it.
Hello world.
My name is Justine
and I fuck
pussy.
Ugh.
I feel like a man
when I say it.
Yeah.
Well you should
probably buy a pickup
then.
Get some of those
mud flaps on the back
with the little sexy
ladies on them
and you may as well
change your name
back to Justine.
Okay.
Well that's just
uncalled for.
Girl, I don't know
what to say except
I told you so.
Sexuality is just
like gender identity.
It is not a performance.
It's not a trend.
It's not a choice.
It's just part of
who you are
and there's nothing
you can do to change it.
I guess you're right.
I guess my theory
sucks.
It sucks so fucking
hard.
But the good news
is you can unclench
your asshole now
and do whatever you
want because you're
still a woman
whether you're
performing a stereotype
or not.
So run free,
Justine.
Go top a cis woman.
Bang a gay guy.
Wear some oversized
flannel.
Do whatever you
want.
Wow.
Yeah.
I guess that is
pretty liberating.
Yeah.
Thank God for
transmedicalism,
right?
Oh, except not
because you just
destroyed transmedicalism
with facts and logic
so we have no theory.
What do we do now?
How do we prove
we're valid?
Well, just do what
every trans woman
has done since
the beginning of time.
Go out and fuck
the most brutally
heterosexual man
you can find
and be validated
and come.
Oh, honey,
I have and I will
but that's not going
to convince anyone
but me.
It's not a proof.
It's not a theory.
Well, maybe
we don't need a theory.
Maybe we don't need
to prove anything.
Bad things,
Justine.
Bad things.
Do we have a theory
about why people
are trans?
No.
They just are.
The only reason
we even feel like
we need a theory
about trans people
is that society
is so unaccepting
of us
that it's constantly
demanding we justify
our own reality.
Okay.
So what am I supposed
to tell Jackie Jackson
then?
What am I supposed
to tell the TERFs?
That I'm a woman
because reasons?
No.
Not even because reasons.
Just because you are.
So it's what?
A leap of faith?
Oh, great.
I'm sure that's
going to convince
us to believe
that we are
trans.
It makes us sound
completely delusional.
Well, Tiffany,
delusion
is what separates
us from the animals.
Who do you think
built the pyramids
and the cathedrals?
Clearly not people
with a perfectly
rational worldview.
But what do you care anyway?
Aren't you the one
who thinks being trans
is a mental disorder?
Well, I wouldn't
describe it as
the height of sanity,
but I would prefer
to think that my whole
life and identity
is based on something
I can rationally explain.
Well, what are we, Tiffany?
Men?
Can we wrap up
the entire world
in a little
rational box?
Maybe the most
important things
in life can't
be logically proved.
Can you logically prove
that you love
your own children?
No.
And the attempt
to prove it
is as degrading
as it is futile.
Maybe gender identity
is one of those things.
Okay, but then
how do I prove
I'm more valid
than Baltimore,
Maryland,
and the star genders,
and the cat people?
Well, maybe
we should stop
getting so caught up
in proving
our validity
to ourselves
that we end up
being horribly cruel
to other people.
What if we just
accept all the freaks
of the world?
At the end of the day,
maybe it's just not
as important
to have logical proofs
as it is to be
empathetic
and open-minded
and compassionate.
Kumbaya, my lord,
kumbaya.
Tiffany.
Kumbaya, my lord,
kumbaya.
I have something
to tell you.
Here it comes.
I love you.
Okay.
Well, I'm going
to get going now.
I have an important
date tonight,
drinking vodka
cranberries
and reading
YouTube comments
by myself.
So I'd really better
go do that,
but good luck
with your new life
as a male lesbian
who fucks cats.
Ugh.
I love you.
Oh, are you upset?
She has to go.
I'm sorry.
I hate this bitch.
But God,
she's a yum yum.
Hearken, children.
In this vision
ye have witnessed
world fools
upon the screen.
Fools
who do not love
themselves,
but otherwise
I, your goddess, mother, queen, messiah, I am nothing like them.
For I am truth, I am light, I am in capitalism, and everything I tweet is woke.
But most importantly, I love myself.
I love myself so much it makes me wet, it makes me cum.
Praise be up to me, hallelujah, like, comment, and subscribe, amen.
Thank you for watching.